<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
 <responseDate>2014-12-14T16:32:39Z</responseDate>
 <request verb= "ListRecords">http://digitaldu.coalliance.org/oai2</request>
 <ListRecords>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63574</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:51:36Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Integrating Service-Learning into Undergraduate Students&apos; Curricula: Recommendations for Best Practices</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Shalabi, Neivin Mahmoud Marzouk</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Higher Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Several recent studies have revealed that there is increasing individualism and declining interest in politics and civic engagement among college students. Accordingly, many scholars called for reinvigorating the civic mission of higher education. This thesis study examines academic service-learning as an effective pedagogy for promoting students’ civic engagement. The purpose of this thesis is to investigate the best ways of integrating service-learning into the curricula of undergraduate students. Using McCarthy’s (2003) conceptual framework, the “Concept of Triangles,” this study provides a comprehensive review of literature on the theoretical underpinnings, partners, and relationships of academic service-learning. The results of the study suggest that establishing clear connections between course content and the kind of service students do, and making meaningful placements of students to service sites are necessary for establishing effective
service-learning courses. Additionally, the findings of the study reveal that promoting critical reflection, encouraging active participation from all partners, and meeting real community needs are essential to the success of service-learning programs. Finally, the findings of this study indicate that effective campus/community partnerships are characterized by reciprocal, collaborative, democratic, caring, trusting, and respectful relationships.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Higher--Campus/community partnerships--Civic Engagement--Concepts--Critical Pedagogy--Partners--Service-Learning</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>94</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63574</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63574</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Tuitt, Franklin A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Grealy, Deborah S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cox, Enid O.</dc:contributor>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63571</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:51:50Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Liberalization of the Capital Market in Russia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Smole, Nejc</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Economics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This paper analyzes the empirical events of capital market liberalization in Russia and refers to the procedure of capital market liberalization described in theory as a benchmark to assess the magnitude of events shaping the capital market liberalization in Russia.The reformers of Russian regime change did not take a gradual approach of adjustments toward a successful socioeconomic transition. The state failed to create market-supporting institutions and instead rather proceeded with an ambitious program of synchronized application of policy changes and the economic liberalization. Lack of market-supporting institutions and an underdeveloped legal system in Russia have been the key tools through which politically well-connected managers and politicians themselves seized the opportunity and established ownership of former state-owned enterprises. Russian privatization did not provide efficiency incentives to produce new wealth, rather is has redistributed the already existing wealth through dubious methods.Clearly, the ultimate goal of capital liberalization in Russia was not to disperse ownership of former state-owned enterprises among the people of Russia, but to create a powerful support group that would ensure the second mandate of President Yeltsin&apos;s administration. The class of newborn `oligarchs&apos; in Russia became the ruling minority that was not interested in creating value; rather, they were interested in stealing the value that has already existed. Weak and vaguely defined laws as opposed to explicit legal foundations and the ability to enforce contracts at proper institutions make an enormous difference in development of capital markets.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Economics, Finance--Economics, History</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>75</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63571</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63571</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Mott, Tracy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pap, Jennifer</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Yasar, Yavuz</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Urquhart, Robert</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63570</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:52:05Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Hemingway and Bullshit</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eiers, Nathan</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>English</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Author: Nathan R. L. EilersTitle: HEMINGWAY AND BULLSHITAdvisor: Clark DavisDegree Date: November 2008ABSTRACTThis paper uses Harry Frankfurt&apos;s definition of bullshit as a lens to re-examine Ernest Hemingway&apos;s aesthetic of factual details and omission. Frankfurt argues that bullshit consists of speech made with indifference to its veracity, and one who makes a habit of bullshitting may lose touch with reality. By studying three works across the author&apos;s career, &quot;Big Two-Hearted River,&quot; &quot;The Short Happy Life of Francis Macomber,&quot; and The Old Man and the Sea, one sees that Hemingway&apos;s prose style evolves and eventually contradicts his artistic statements. Given the fact that he promotes his aesthetic while discarding it, his theory becomes bullshit. Because normative critical interpretation of the author rests largely on his aesthetic theory, it too is inaccurate. Though Hemingway misrepresents how he writes, the success of his work regardless of aesthetics demonstrates that his writing is more complex than many think and deserves a more thorough re-evaluation.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Literature, Modern--Literature, American--Literature, English--Aesthetics--Big Two-Hearted River--Bullshit--Ernest Hemingway--The Old Man and the Sea--The Short Happy Life of Francis Macomber</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>71</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63570</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63570</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Davis, Clark</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Goodfriend, Joyce</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kiteley, Brian</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63569</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:52:09Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>THE DEVELOPMENT DRIVE OF NORTH-SOUTH VERSUS SOUTH-SOUTH PTAs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ramirez, Jose Luis</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Economics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The importance of PTAs in today&apos;s global economic order is unmistakable, especially during the last fifteen years when their proliferation has dramatically accelerated and their scope and structure have radically changed.  However, the available theoretical framework (international trade theories) from which their developmental impact is assessed seems to be largely lagging behind.  Hence, there is a crucial need for more realistic assessments of their embedded developmental features because an increasing number of developing countries are perceiving these agreements as one of the key instruments to propel their long delayed economic development.  In this thesis, I strive to construct an alternative theoretical framework that can better adapt to current PTAs&apos; structures, allowing a more realistic assessment of their economic impact on developing countries.  By following this alternative approach, I comparatively assess the development drive of two of today&apos;s most important PTAs, namely NAFTA and ASEAN.  The main conclusion echoes an increasing literature that warns developing countries from engaging in &quot;reciprocal&quot; North-South PTAs, but at the same time, encourages them to pursue South-South integration, which can prove to be beneficial for their development.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Economics, General--Economics, Commerce-Business--Political Science, International Law and Relations--ASEAN--Foreign Investment--Market Access--NAFTA--PTAs and Development--Regional Economic Integration</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>131</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63569</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63569</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Sai-wing Ho, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Goetz, Andrew</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Mott, Tracy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>von Arnim, Rudiger</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63566</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:52:24Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organizational Conflict within the Department of Homeland Security</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Manderson, M. Katherine</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Conflict Resolution Institute</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This thesis seeks to explain why the Department of Homeland Security had difficulty fulfilling its roles when it was formed, specifically its role as grant administrator.  Role theory surmises that conflict arises from unclear expectations, conflicting expectations, and too many roles.  This study utilized various public testimonies, legislation, and other government documents to examine how the missions of the twenty-two agencies that were merged together to make up DHS changed.  Even though DHS has changed continually over the five years since its existence most employees seem to be clear on the mission of the organization in which they work.  However, there is still a considerable amount of conflict resulting from the agencies being forced together in such a frankensteinian way.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Business Administration, Management</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>154</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63566</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63566</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Laird, Frank</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Feste, Karen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Allen, Doug</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63564</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:52:30Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>CONTINUING THE GREAT DEBATE:  THE INTRINSIC VALUE OF THE LEADING INDEX</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Morgan, Seth</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Economics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The following work is a look into the history and value of the composite index of leading indicators. Current and past business cycle theory is explored to demonstrate the relevance of a tool like the composite index of leading indicators. An argument that business cycle theory has not proven sufficient in explaining changes in the direction of the economy is made. The notion that the composite leading index has a proven track record of successfully predicting movements in the economy is reviewed. The conclusion becomes the idea that since theory and its forecasting counterparts have not proven a reliable method to predict movements in the economy, a tool like the composite leading index is valuable.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Economics, Theory--Economics, General--Economics, Commerce-Business--Conference Board--Economic Indicators--Leading Index--Leading Indicators--Philip Klein--Victor Zarnowtiz</dc:subject>
  <dc:format></dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63564</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63564</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Mott, Tracy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Schulten, Susan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Urquhart, Robert</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Freeman, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63563</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:52:45Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An Inquiry into the Metaphysical Foundations of Mathematics in Economics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Luna, Edgar</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Economics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Economics is supposed to fall somewhere between a hard science and a social science.  During the last half century, economics has become highly mathematical trying to mimic physics.  The purpose of this study is to look at the metaphysical statements linked to mathematical models, specifically, Game Theory.  In doing so, it will be demonstrated that Game Theory, as part of neoclassical economics, engages in analysis which can be categorized as metaphysical, with real metaphysical implications.  In categorizing the metaphysical assumptions of neoclassical economists/game theorists we will see how much of their analysis is consists in a reductive, implausible metaphysical view.  Problems that arise from this view are hardly taken into consideration most economists.  This lack of consideration has non-trivial consequences for economics as a discipline and for its methodology.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Economics, Theory--Philosophy--Economics, History--Economic Methodology--History of Economic Thought--Philosophy of Mathematics--Philosophy of Science</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>122</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63563</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63563</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Urquhart, Robert</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Mott, Tracy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Upton, Candace</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63558</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:53:00Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ISLAMIC RELIGIOUS CURRICULA AND TERRORISM : A CASE STUDY OF THE AZHERITE SCHOOLS IN EGYPT</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>BABIKIR, BABIKIR FAISAL</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Conflict Resolution Institute</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This thesis examines the connection between Islamic religious educationand terrorism. It looks at the curricula of the Azherite religious schools in Egypt.It examines how the curricula view the three themes of Jihad which are offensiveJihad, defensive Jihad, and Jihad for the purification of the soul in addition to therelations of Muslims with non-Muslims. Books which are used by violent jihadistgroups for membership acquisition and cadre training are also studied for Jihadthemes and relations with non-Muslims.The analysis shows that the curricula are, generally speaking, a peaceful onein its principal direction, since it obviously calls for defensive Jihad and notoffensive Jihad. Often, it deals with important concepts of Jihad within theconfines of such subjects as the Jihad for the purification of the soul [the GreaterJihad]. Some textbooks included lessons on &quot;Peace in Islam&quot; and advocated thefact that peace is the origin in Islamic Shari&apos;a and war is the exception and it isfought only for defensive reasons. This orientation in the curricula very muchcoincides with the themes of conflict resolution The comparison between theAzherite schools&apos; textbooks and the books used by violent jihadist groups formembership acquisition and cadre training shows that they are in total contrast inrelation to how they view the topic of Jihad and relationship with non-Muslims.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Political Science, General</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>135</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63558</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63558</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Feste, Karen A</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63557</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:53:05Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Protecting Investment, Profit, and Personnel: Corporations as Social Change Agents</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fotino, Carole Claire</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Conflict Resolution Institute</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This paper describes a three-level toolkit - The Investment Sustainability Toolkit.  The Toolkit assists firms in improving the efficacy of one segment of Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) initiative by creating at the first level, a strategy of conflict prevention.  This strategy is followed by Common Elements of Conflict that Resolves/Becomes Violent, and Key Areas for Stabilization as Level II.  The third and final level of the toolkit describes specific initiatives for increasing success, through The Screening Checklist.The paper assesses through case study, the efforts of Firestone, Inc. in Liberia regarding regional development, stabilization, and economic development.  This is done through the lens of the 3-levels of The Toolkit and for the purposes of illustrating lost opportunities that a Toolkit framework would have identified by linking the success of all stakeholders.  Losses That Look Like Wins are a key focus area within the case study as are times of stability that offer the opportunity to create institutions - civil, political, economic - to perpetuate that stability.This paper makes the case for corporations as social change agents, for preceding violence, and for including a strategy, and a framework, as well as targeted initiatives to increase the success and efficacy of this segment of CSR.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Business Administration, Management--Economics, Commerce-Business--Conflict prevention--Investment--Preconciliation--Stabilization perpetuation--Strategic corporate social responsibility--Transnational corporations</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>207</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63557</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63557</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Allen, Douglas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wittmer, Dennis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Winn, Joan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63556</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:53:19Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Study of Colorado&apos;s TABOR Law and Its Influence on Public Finance During the 2001 Recession</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brewer, Zak</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Economics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Colorado&apos;s constitutional Taxpayer Bill of Rights (TABOR) is a product of the citizen initiative process, a mechanism of direct democracy that allows citizens to circumvent legislatures and enact laws themselves.  A prominent argument against this process is that such a mode of lawmaking can generate conflicts within state constitutions and bring about unintended consequences.  This paper considers the Colorado state budget difficulties that arose during the 2001 recession, the relationship of TABOR and those difficulties, and finds that TABOR resulted in unintended consequences that were unforeseen by voters who approved the measure.  Examples of these unanticipated, unintended consequences include: significant budget cuts for higher education, reductions in state mental health services, and insufficiencies within the TABOR law regarding how TABOR refunds were to be made.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Economics, Finance</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>76</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63556</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63556</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Wilson, Matthew</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Freeman, Katherine</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Mott, Tracy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sterett, Susan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63555</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:53:34Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>MEMS TRANSDUCER FOR HEARING AID DEVICE</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tang, Houwen</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>A study of implantable middle ear MEMS piezoelectric transducer for hearing aids was developed. The physical vibration deflection at the tip of the transducer is simulated using finite element method. Further, a study of thermoelastic damping effect of four designed MEMS mirrors used as resonators is presented. An optical measurement system based on Mach-Zehnder interferometer is</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical--Hearing aids--MEMS Transducer</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>72</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63555</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63555</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Yi, Yunbo</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Whitman, Bob</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
 </ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
