<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
 <responseDate>2014-12-14T16:32:57Z</responseDate>
 <request verb= "ListRecords">http://digitaldu.coalliance.org/oai2</request>
 <ListRecords>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_67613</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:36:39Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>(1 year embargo) Capacity-building through English language training to improve long-term resettlement success: A case study of the refugees along the Thailand-Burma border</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Yuen, Lorelle</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Van Arsdale, Peter W</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kreps, Christina</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sisk, Timothy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Department of Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:date></dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>Denver (Colo.)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:type>thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:format></dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Achieving long-term resettlement success is a challenge for many refugees seeking to restart their lives after displacement and being uprooted from their lives. Refugees must deal with finding employment, integrating into a society immensely different from what they have known their whole lives, and starting over from scratch. Learning a new language enables refugees to progress towards integration and long-term resettlement success, however, resettled refugees face a multitude of barriers in the U.S. to accessing language classes and attaining English proficiency. This study seeks to bridge this problem by exploring the possibilities of implementing a standardized language training program in the refugee camps to better prepare refugees for resettlement. A case study of the refugees along the Thai-Burma border demonstrated the significance of learning English in the camps on eventual English proficiency as well as the need for increased partnerships to overcome the barriers of lack of motivation and lack of funding. The author explores the possibilities of implementing a language training program in the camps by determining need, interest, barriers, and perceptions through the use of interviews, surveys, and focus groups of camp refugees, resettled refugees, and key organizational representatives. The significance of these results offers the possibility of leveraging and unlocking resettlement as a durable solution for more of the world&apos;s refugees in protracted situations.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This item is under a one-year embargo. Permission must be granted by the author for access.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>International relations;</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Resettlement</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Refugee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>English language training</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Capacity-building</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage>Burma</dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage>Thailand</dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dissertations, Academic</dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier></dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author. User is responsible for all copyright clearance.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>Embargo period: 1 year embargo.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:67613</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_67607</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:36:44Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>(2 year embargo) Performance Study of OFDM Over Fading Channels for Wireless Communications</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alshammari, Ahmed</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Matin, Mohammad</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Thurimella, Ramakrishna</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gao, David</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:date></dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>Denver (Colo.)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:type>thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:format></dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiplexing (OFDM) is a very efficient multicarrier technique. OFDM is used more and more in recent wideband digital communications. It has numerous advantages such as the ability to handle severe channel conditions, efficient spectral usage, reduced inter symbol interference (ISI), and high data rate. Therefore, it has been utilized in many wired and wireless communication systems like DSL, wireless networks and 4G mobile communications.  Studying the performance of OFDM over different channels is the main focus of this research. Channels&apos; environments simulated in Matlab are additive white Gaussian noise (AWGN) and fading channels. Each channel affects the process of transmission in a certain way. Simulation results will make us understand some of these effects.  Fading channels include two types of flat fading and two types of frequency selective fading. At certain signal-to-noise ratios (SNRs), channels are compared together in order to rank them according to the delivered signal. Quality of the signals, bit-error-rates (BERs), and peak signal-to-noise ratios (PSNRs) of the received signals are the aspects in which system performance is evaluated.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This item is under a two-year embargo. Permission must be granted by the author for access.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Engineering</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dissertations, Academic</dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier></dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author. User is responsible for all copyright clearance. </dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>Embargo period: 2 year embargo.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:67607</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_67606</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:36:49Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>(2 year embargo) The Bit Error Rate (BER) Performance in Multi-Carrier (OFDM) and Single-Carrier</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Albdran, Saleh M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Narapareddy, Vi</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Matin, Mohammed</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gao, David</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Department of Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:date></dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>Denver (Colo.)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:type>thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:format></dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>The spectacular growth of wireless communication tools has escalated the number of mobile subscribers from almost 700 million in 2000 to more than 4 billion in 2009. The huge number of subscribers has led to several issues with how service is provided. The high user demand has forced developers to overcome the problems of the old analog systems and to introduce OFDM as a promising technique that can fulfill users&apos; high demands. This technique matches well with high data rate connection and provides a higher capacity for the subscribers&apos; usage.  The OFDM, as a multi-carrier, is more complex than the single-carrier transmission scheme. However, the OFDM technique maintains better performance for high data rate in terms of bit error rate (BER). In this thesis a comparison has been presented between the multi-carrier OFDM and the single-carrier to prove, in a simulation form, the theoretical point of view. Despite the advantages of using the OFDM scheme, there are several drawbacks. One of these negatives is the high peak to average power ratio (PAPR).  To overcome this problem, there are power reduction techniques that can be applied to the signal to reduce the high power. One of these techniques is the clipping and filtering technique. A maximum level is sited for the transmitted signal to reduce the power and afterward, the signal goes through a filter to remove the influence of the in-band distortion and out-of-band radiation.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This item is under a two-year embargo. Permission must be granted by the author for access</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Electrical engineering</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Wireless</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Single-Carrier</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>QAM</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>PSK</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>OFDM</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Multi-Carrier</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dissertations, Academic</dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier></dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author. User is responsible for all copyright clearance.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>Embargo period: 2 year embargo.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:67606</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66607</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:43:44Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The effect of a medical collar on the initial stability of cementless primary femoral hip prosthesis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Huff, Daniel N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Rullkoetter, Paul J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hughen, Chris</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Laz, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Engineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:date>Nov. 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:type>thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:format>vii, 130 p. : col. ill.</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>The initial stability of a primary femoral hip prosthesis is important to the long-term survivorship and efficacy of the prosthesis. In the absence of adequate initial stability, micromotion between the prosthesis and the proximal endosteal femoral bone will result in partial fibrous encapsulation of the prosthesis, rather than direct bony apposition. Long-term survivorship of the prosthesis may suffer as a result of the lack of long-term osteointegration due to early prosthesis instability. The present study demonstrates the effect of a medial collar on the initial stability of a triple-tapered, broach-only, proximally porous-coated primary cementless hip prosthesis using a computational analysis. In a computer model, collared and collarless prostheses are placed into six femora from six different patients and subjected to two separate loading conditions encountered daily. The presence of a medial collar was found to produce a significant reduction in the total micromotion and subsidence of the femoral hip prosthesis.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Artificial hip joints</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biomedical engineering</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dissertations, Academic</dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66607</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66607</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66606</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:43:49Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>El Gran Manipulador : political survival, dual power, and the emergence and maintenance of social movements in Hugo Chávez&apos;s Venezuela</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hart, Kelly C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Viotti, Paul R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Taylor, Matthew</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gochman, Ben</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:type>thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:format>v, 148 p. : col. ill., col. maps</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Social movements facilitate democratic transitions. However, the understanding of the modern democracy as a firmly institutionalized system has little room for the emergence and maintenance of influential social movements. This trend is changing as leaders of democratic states in Latin America begin to identify the disfranchised as a power base. This effort to include previously marginalized groups has allowed social movements to participate more intensively in the political process, as allies of the state. The result of this alliance is a shift from a representative democracy to a participatory democracy. The purpose of this thesis to determine why, when, and how significant social movements emerge as enduring allies of political leaders in solidified democratic states. This thesis will link political decision making at the presidential level with the maintenance of significant social movements as winning coalition members. It argues that social movements are essential to the political survival of particular presidential administrations. This thesis will examine the alliance between President Hugo Chávez and Venezuela’s social movements as its case study.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Political science</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social movements</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Venezuela Politics and government, 1999</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject>Chávez Frías, Hugo</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dissertations, Academic</dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66606</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66606</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66600</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:43:54Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Income Inequality In U.S. Metropolitan Areas: Which Areas Have The Greatest Inequality And Why?</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Compton, Carl Peterson</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Schneider, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Mott, Tracy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Urquhart, Robert</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Boschmann, Eric</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>In recent years, much focus has been placed on the high and growing level of income inequality in the United States.  This composition begins to fill a void in the existing literature by examining specific urban areas that have particularly high levels of inequality and the characteristics that factor into inequality.  In this paper, I construct a qualitative model for a particularly unequal metropolitan area.  I then apply the model to a set of U.S. metros that are among the most unequal in the country and share a particular set of characteristics consistent with the model.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66600</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66600</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Compton, Carl Peterson</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Economics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Social Sciences</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>iii, 71 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Agglomeration</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Income</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Inequality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Metropolitan</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66599</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:43:59Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicle in Smart Grid</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Yao, Yin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gao, Wenzhong</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Yi, Yunbo</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Matin, Mohammad</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Zhang, Jun</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>In this thesis, in order to investigate the impact of charging load from plug-in hybrid electric vehicles (PHEVs), a stochastic model is developed in Matlab. In this model, two main types of PHEVs are defined: public transportation vehicles and private vehicles. Different charging time schedule, charging speed and battery capacity are considered for each type of vehicles. The simulation results reveal that there will be two load peaks (at noon and in evening) when the penetration level of PHEVs increases continuously to 30% in 2030. Therefore, optimization tool is utilized to shift load peaks. This optimization process is based on real time pricing and wind power output data. With the help of smart grid, power allocated to each vehicle could be controlled. As a result, this optimization could fulfill the goal of shifting load peaks to valley areas where real time price is low or wind output is high.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66599</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66599</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Yao, Yin</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Engineering and Computer Science</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>vii, 101 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Electrical engineering</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Demand side response</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Plug-in hybrid electric vehicle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Renewable energy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66598</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:44:04Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Episodic Recruitment and Climate Analysis of Ponderosa Pine on the Palmer Divide, Eastern Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Brenton Jr, William Henry</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sullivan, Donald</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Quigley, Martin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Daniels, J Michael</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hamann, Hillary</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Previous recruitment studies on populations of ponderosa pine (&lt;italic&gt;Pinus ponderosa&lt;/italic&gt; P. &amp; C. Lawson) in Colorado have been limited to the western mountains and the Front Range.  In this research I used tree-ring data to reconstruct recruitment for ponderosa pine near the eastern limits of its distribution at two sites on the Palmer Divide, Eastern Colorado, to determine the relative climate sensitivity of the two sites, and the extent to which climate or other factors may have influenced recruitment at the sites.  The results of the tree-ring analysis suggest that ponderosa pines in more the easterly site lower elevation population are more sensitive to climatic factors than are in the more westerly site.  Both higher elevation populations showed a history of episodic recruitment that only partially reflects local climatic conditions.  Climate is probably the most important factor in recruitment pulses, but only if there is opportunity within the stand for recruitment.  Although favorable climate patterns were present at both sites at the same time, the opportunity for recruitment within each stand was different at separate times.  While climate conditions must be favorable for seedling establishment and growth, conditions of stability and competition within the stand dictate the ultimate recruitment success.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66598</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66598</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Brenton, William Henry, Jr.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Natural Sciences and Mathematics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>v, 58 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Climate</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dendroecology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Episodic Recruitment</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66597</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:44:19Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Restorative Justice and Recidivism: A Meta-Analysis</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Bain, Kristin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Feste, Karen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>d&apos;Estree, Tamara</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Karson, Michael</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Restorative Justice is an approach to resolving conflict that has become increasingly relevant as both financial and social costs associated with crime have continued to rise.  As alternative methods of managing crime are being considered and implemented there is a call from policy makers for evidence that those programs are indeed the best practice.  Although there is a significant amount of research on restorative justice, synthesis of that information is lacking which impedes full understanding of the potential of the impact and role of this approach.  A central argument is that restorative based programs produce benefits because they reduce recidivism rates.  Is that true?  I conducted a meta-analysis on 24 published studies to evaluate the claims for effectiveness and to discover what aspects of restorative justice programs are most effective in reducing recidivism, as well as what offender characteristics make for the best restorative justice candidates.  Analysis indicated that recidivism may be decreased more for adults than juveniles, when there is contact with the direct victim of the offense, and after the offender goes through the treatment.  Surprisingly, community involvement, the ability to develop consensus, and victim satisfaction indicated an increase in recidivism.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>Bain_denver_0061M_10690.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66597</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Bain, Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Conflict Resolution Institute</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>iv, 135 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Criminology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Balanced Approach</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Criminal Justice</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Meta-Analysis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66596</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:44:30Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Capacity-building through English language training to improve long-term resettlement success: A case study of the refugees along the Thailand-Burma border</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Yuen, Lorelle</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Van Arsdale, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sisk, Timothy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kreps, Christina</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Achieving long-term resettlement success is a challenge for many refugees seeking to restart their lives after displacement and being uprooted from their lives. Refugees must deal with finding employment, integrating into a society immensely different from what they have known their whole lives, and starting over from scratch. Learning a new language enables refugees to progress towards integration and long-term resettlement success, however, resettled refugees face a multitude of barriers in the U.S. to accessing language classes and attaining English proficiency. This study seeks to bridge this problem by exploring the possibilities of implementing a standardized language training program in the refugee camps to better prepare refugees for resettlement. A case study of the refugees along the Thai-Burma border demonstrated the significance of learning English in the camps on eventual English proficiency as well as the need for increased partnerships to overcome the barriers of lack of motivation and lack of funding.The author explores the possibilities of implementing a language training program in the camps by determining need, interest, barriers, and perceptions through the use of interviews, surveys, and focus groups of camp refugees, resettled refugees, and key organizational representatives. The significance of these results offers the possibility of leveraging and unlocking resettlement as a durable solution for more of the world&apos;s refugees in protracted situations.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66596</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66596</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Yuen, Lorelle W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>viii, 153 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>International relations</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Burma</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Capacity-building</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>English language training</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Refugee</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Resettlement</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66595</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:44:45Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Solar Photovoltaic System Modeling and Control</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Xia, Qing</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gao, David Wenzhong</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Yi, Yunbo</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Zhang, Jun</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gao, David Wenzhong</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>To realize the benefits of grid-connected photovoltaic system, it is extremely important to reduce energy losses and improve reliability of grid-connected PV systems with high PV penetration. In this thesis, three different Maximum Power Point Tracking (MPPT) strategies named as Perturbation &amp; Observation MPPT, Incremental Conductance MPPT and Fuzzy Logic Control MPPT have been analyzed, simulated and compared with each other to improve the efficiency of power conversion. A general discussion to counteract partial shading effect in several aspects is also provided in this thesis. In order to improve reliability of the system, an optimum current control loop with suitable control parameters are achieved by comparing three different PI controller parameter design methods, including self-tuning method, trial and error method and mathematical analysis method. Considering the complexity brought by modulation and demodulation process between abc stationary frame and dq0 synchronous frame of PI control loop, P+ Resonant controller, with simple control loop structure and zero steady-state error is also designed in this thesis. At last, LCL filter is analyzed and modeled under both steady state and disturbing condition. The effects of LCL filter for improving disturbance rejection capability and dynamic performance of the system is verified.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66595</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66595</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Xia, Qing</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Engineering and Computer Science</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>x, 174 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Electrical engineering</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Grid-connected VSI</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>LCL Filter</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>MPPT strategies</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>PV array modeling</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66594</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:44:59Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>U.S. Military Engagement with Authoritarian East/Central African States</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Russell, Shawn P.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>VanArsdale, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Allen, Doug</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sisk, Timothy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>This paper examines the question, &quot;How can the US best engage authoritarian governments in Africa militarily, in order to facilitate more positive outcomes for that country&apos;s citizens?&quot; In order to answer this, it is necessary to examine the presumption that authoritarian governments do not promote positive outcomes for their constituents. If this is not the case, then it may be possible to use different, non-traditional means in order to identify positive performance indicators. This can lead to a more holistic assessment, and allow the US to leverage the resources of the military to further promote these outcomes.In this thesis, I argue that if it is possible for an authoritarian government to facilitate positive outcomes for its people, it may be possible to craft a military engagement plan so that the US military can help continue this cycle. The benefits of a well-crafted engagement plan can improve the lives of that country&apos;s citizens, and improve governance by its leaders. For the everyday people in these countries, the consequences of a poorly-crafted plan could hardly be worse.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66594</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66594</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Russell, Shawn P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>iv, 171 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>International relations</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Autocracies</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Benevolent Dictatorships</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dictatorships</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Military engagement</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66590</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:45:10Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Hyperspatial Self: Henry James and Posthuman Modalities</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Patsiokas, Christina</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McNees, Eleanor</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Howard, Scott</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Waldman, Diane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>In the era of computing and ubiquitous media, scholars across disciplines have been developing new models for how humans operate in complex environments. This line of inquiry can be bracketed under the larger term of posthuman thought. This thesis attempts to engage the critical and fictional work of Henry James with several posthumanist texts to challenge the temporal limitations of both. Against the backdrop of posthuman discourse, James emerges not as the cherished father of modernism but rather as a pioneer of distant territories far beyond the ways in which the modernist novel conceptualized the self and its consciousness. James provides useful models for defining modalities of the posthuman before the advance of technology materially manifested the cyborg reality in which we presently live. Juxtaposing James&apos;s proto-modern thought with the postmodern sensibilities of the posthumanists results in significant reconfigurations of both. Jamesian narrative and theory find ways to reconcile the absorption of the self into informational pattern with long-cherished notions of individuality and autonomy; because this self exists both in physical space and outside of it, it is essentially hyperspatial--that which can move through space but also transcends the limitations imposed by space through mediation and virtuality. Ultimately, James performs the posthuman in a holistic way that more productively reveals insights about technology and identity than the attendant theory or criticism.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66590</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66590</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Patsiokas, Christina</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>English</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Arts and Humanities</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>iii, 79 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Literature</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consciousness</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>In the Cage</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>James, Henry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Narrative theory</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Post-human</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66591</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:45:26Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Towards a Fluid Solid Interaction Model of a Dynamic Lung</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Jacobs, Justin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lengsfeld, Corinne</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Fukami, Cynthia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rullkoetter, Paul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gordon, Matthew</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Because the pulmonary system is a site for both environmental particulate contamination, as well as drug delivery into the body, numerous research groups have focused on precisely understanding its inner-workings. Past research has demonstrated the need to realistically model the lung walls in order to accurately capture the complex airflow profile throughout all of the branches. Since this is paramount to properly replicating particulate transport in the lung, computational fluid dynamics simulations on their own are inadequate, as they cannot account for lung wall dilation. Only by coupling the fluid and solid domains can natural lung behavior can be effectively modeled. The goal of this work was to develop and validate the methods required to create a reliable computational fluid-solid interaction pulmonary simulation. To validate the proposed technique, a balloon was both experimentally and computationally modeled. A small pulmonary system was then presented to demonstrate the simulation capabilities.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66591</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66591</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Jacobs, Justin</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Engineering and Computer Science</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>viii, 79 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Mechanical engineering</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fluids</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>FSI</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Interaction</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Lung</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Modeling</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66592</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:45:32Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analysis of Interphase Chromatin Motion in HeLa Cells</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Westacott, Matthew Joel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Loerke, Dinah</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Loerke, Dinah</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Siemens, Mark</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ghosh, Kingshuk</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Motion of particles under influencing forces may be observed under light microscopy techniques. Variations in mobility of particles may give relevant biophysical information. Automated high resolution single particle tracking techniques were used to characterize interphase chromatin mobility in the cell nucleus. Interphase chromatin undergo replication prior to cell division with the assistance of replication proteins (machinery) which modify chromatin mobility. Using dual color imaging of flourescently tagged chromatin and proliferating cell nuclear antigen (PCNA) were followed through interphase. Chromatin motion was modelled as a two dimensional random walk.  Reduction in chromatin mobility was observed during S phase was dependent on proximity to the replication machinery. Mobility during G1 and G2 phase is independent of proximity to GFP-PCNA maxima and is higher than during S phase.  These results suggest that replication selectively inhibits chromatin mobility. Local proximity to replication machinery however, cannot account for the entire mobility difference. By modelling the mean square displacement as a power law, sub-diffusive behavior was observed in S phase chromatin whereas non S phase exhibited normal diffusional characteristics.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Biophysics--</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66592</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66592</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Westacott, Matthew J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Physics and Astronomy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Natural Sciences and Mathematics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>iii, 42 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66593</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:45:37Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Feminine Realism in Cornhill Magazine: Anne Thackeray Ritchie and Frances Parthenope Verney</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Scamahorn, Alexandra Virginia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McNees, Eleanor</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Dobyns, Ann</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Warlick, M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>This thesis explores the literature published by two lesser known women writers in &lt;italic&gt;Cornhill Magazine&lt;/italic&gt; during the 1860s: Anne Thackeray Ritchie and Frances Parthenope Verney. By using the magazine as a context for their fiction, I examine the ways in which these writers both reflect &lt;italic&gt;Cornhill&lt;/italic&gt;&apos;s brand of realism, which privileged masculine ideology, and diverge from it, inserting a feminine perspective. Because the magazine&apos;s representation of the multiple facets of its society is varied and complex, my thesis examines a particular aspect of societal representation: one that depicts mid-nineteenth-century society in transition from traditional to progressive values. Caught between these phases, Thackeray Ritchie and Verney recognize and reflect the implications such a transition had on women and their place in society. Both embrace traditional values and comply with gender norms, creating distinctly feminine texts, but, in so doing, they argue for more opportunities for women, including education, vocation, and independence. In the process of portraying women, they create a feminine realism that complies with but expands &lt;italic&gt;Cornhill&lt;/italic&gt;&apos;s masculine ideology and realist constructions.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66593</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66593</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Scamahorn, Alexandra Virginia</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>English</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Arts and Humanities</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>iii, 140 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>British and Irish literature</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Anne Thackeray Ritchie</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cornhill Magazine</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feminine realism</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Frances Parthenope Verney</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Periodical studies</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_65307</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:45:56Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>New Open Source Software for Building Molecular Dynamics Systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Allen, Bruce Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Materials Science</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The context of this work is the development of open source software to support researchers to quickly build systems of molecules for molecular dynamics (MD) simulations. The goal is achieved through the integration of three open source programs by judicious modifications and creation of new source code, which allows the creation of molecular models, MD cells and the LAMMPS geometry input files. The software changeswork together supporting an easy and intuitive process for simulation system creation. Creation of multiple MD cells for research simulations becomes quicker and provides needed standardization to the simulation process. The researcher can select from atomistic force fields or modify the software to use other force fields. The software has been validated by generating the glass transition temperature (Tg) and the bulk modulusfor a cross-linked epoxy system composed of Diglycidyl Ether of Bisphenol-A and Isophorone diamine (DGEBA/IPD). The Large-scale Atomic/Molecular Massively Parallel Simulator (LAMMPS) software is used to conduct the molecule dynamics simulations.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Materials Science--Nanoscience--Computer science--LAMMPS--Molecular Dynamics--NanoEngineer-1--PACKMOL--Software Development</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>119</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:65307</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:65307</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Predecki, Paul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kumosa, Maciej</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Yi, Yun-Bo</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Eaton, Gareth</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Predecki, Paul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kumosa, Maciej</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_65301</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:46:01Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Influence of Soil Microorganisms on Plant Growth and Fitness</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jayne, Benjamin</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Biological Sciences</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Most terrestrial plants benefit from symbiosis with soil microorganisms.  Symbiotic bacteria and fungi have wide-ranging effects on host plants, including improved nutrition, disease resistance, and drought tolerance.  Association with Arbuscular Mycorrhizal Fungi (AMF) can enhance growth and protect plants from environmental stressors while they share products of photosynthesis with the resident fungi.  Scores of studies indicate that mycorrhizal plants are more resistant to drought stress than their non-mycorrhizal counterparts.  Use of microbes as a plant and soil supplement in home gardens represents a sustainable alternative to resource-intensive inputs and may allow for reduced water use.  I investigated the effects of commercially-available microbial products and a peat soil amendment on strawberry plants under water stress.  In a greenhouse experiment, strawberry plants were grown across factorial treatments of two AMF mixtures, two types of soil, and two water treatments.  Inoculated strawberry plants had greater total dry weight biomass and leaf surface area than un-inoculated plants but showed no increases in reproductive tissues.  Plants grown in peat-amended soil had improved growth in all measures except number of fruits and flowers.  This data shows that modification of urban and suburban soil with peat and soil microorganisms can improve plant biomass.Despite a large body of literature that describes the effects of mycorrhizal colonization on plant resistance to water deficit, reviews of these works are only in narrative form and it is therefore difficult to quantify the magnitude of the effect.  In a meta-analysis, we examined the effect of mycorrhizal colonization on growth and yield of plants exposed to water-deficit stress.  We found that, in terms of biomass measurements, mycorrhizal plants are more resistant to water stress compared to non-mycorrhizal plants.  When variables such as habit, lifecycle, or water stress level are considered, differences in mycorrhizal effect on growth between variables are observed.  For example, while growth of both annual and perennial plants is improved by symbiosis, perennials respond more favorably to colonization than annuals.  Overall, meta-analysis reveals a quantifiable corroboration of the commonly held view that mycorrhizal symbiosis improves plant&apos;s resistance to water-deficit conditions.Efforts to restore native vegetation may benefit from treatment of native seeds and plants with AMF.  Invasive plants can alter ecosystems by out-competing native species or changing the physicochemical properties of the local environment.  Tamarisk (Tamarix spp.), a shrubby tree native to the Europe, Asia, and Africa, has now invaded 1.6 million acres of land in the western United States.  Tamarisk exudes salt from its leaves that accumulates in surrounding soils and can affect the growth of native plant species.  Here we examined the effect of AMF on the growth of an array of restoration species native to riparian areas of the southwest US under varied water and salinity regimes.  AMF affected only one plant species with regard to root biomass and root:shoot ratio.  Infection rates of inoculated plants varied from 0-61% and were limited by high salinity.  We also found that salinity and water have strong effects on several native species, and that biomass decreases with increasing salinity or decreasing water.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Ecology--AMF--Drought-tolerance--Meta-analysis--Mycorrhiza--Plant growth--Sustainability</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>108</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:65301</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:65301</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Quigley, Martin F.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Daniels, J. Michael</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sher, Anna</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_65273</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:46:06Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Through the Eyes of Visitors: Understanding the Contexts of the Visitor Photo Study at the Denver Museum of Nature &amp; Science</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schroeder, Kathryn Irene</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Quantitative Research Methods</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This case study describes the analysis of the Visitor Photo Study, a study in which visitors to the Denver Museum of Nature &amp; Science documented their visit through pictures. The origins, implementation, and findings of the Visitor Photo Study are considered within the contexts of the fields of Community-Based Research (Strand, Marullo, Cutforth, Stoecker, &amp; Donohue, 2003b), Visual Studies (Marshall &amp; Rossman, 2011; Pink, 2007), and Visitor Studies (Visitor Studies Association, 2012). This study considers the extent to which the principles and elements of each of these fields were present in the Visitor Photo Study, which elements were not fully realized or were missing from the study, and ways in which the Visitor Photo Study extends each of these fields. The value of this type of analysis and implications for museums, faculty, and students are also discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Educational evaluation--Community-based research--Informal learning environments--Visitor studies--Visual studies</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>174</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:65273</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:65273</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Cutforth, Nicholas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Olmos-Gallo, Pablo Antonio</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Benson, Janette</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_65261</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:46:11Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>AFFECTIVE-DOMAIN OCCURRENCES REPORTED BY UNDERGRADUATE NON-MUSIC-MAJOR STUDENTS IN A KEYBOARD-CENTERED COURSE INCORPORATING THE NINE NATIONAL STANDARDS FOR MUSIC EDUCATION AND A METHODOLOGY BASED ON CONSTRUCTIVIST PRINCIPLES:  PATTERNS THAT MIGHT SUGGEST HYPOTHESES ABOUT CAUSE-AND-EFFECT RELATIONSHIPS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Argirova, Gergana</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Music</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>In this study, data about occurrences in the affective domain of non-music-major subjects taking a keyboard-centered course that incorporates the nine National Standards for music education along with a methodology based on constructivist principles were collected.  The problem of this study was to identify any patterns in those data that might suggest hypotheses about cause-and-effect relationships that might be tested later in quantitative studies with experimental design.The instruction consisted of a keyboard-centered music education curriculum that encompassed the U.S. nine National Standards for music education along with a teaching methodology based on constructivist principles.  This study was conducted in order to examine the relationship between five beginner piano subjects and the piano, revealed through observations (from their own perspective and the teacher&apos;s) on their feelings, thoughts, and emotions during the time of the research study.  Data for this research study were collected from a variety of sources:  pre- and post-instructional questionnaires, personal journal entries required from the participants, and researcher notes.This was a qualitative study in which questionnaires were administered and in which the subjects and the instructor kept journals that were collected and examined.  The lesson plans incorporated objectives representing the U.S. nine National Standards for music education, which are listed at the Web site of the National Association for Music Education (http://musiced.nafme.org/resources/national-standards-for-music-education/):1.  Singing, alone and with others, a varied repertoire of music.2.  Performing on instruments, alone and with others, a varied repertoire of music.3.  Improvising melodies, variations, and accompaniments.4.  Composing and arranging music within specified guidelines.5.  Reading and notating music.6.  Listening to, analyzing, and describing music.7.  Evaluating music and music performances.8.  Understanding relationships between music, the other arts, and disciplines outside the arts.9.  Understanding music in relation to history and culture.The teaching methodology was based on constructivist principles that describe learning as a process in which learners construct their musical knowledge and upgrade their schemata based on their musical experience, while the role of the teacher is to facilitate and guide this process.  The implementation of the study and the actual data gathering took place at a medium-sized, private research university in the Rocky Mountain west of the United States during its 2012 spring quarter with subjects who were undergraduate non-music-major students.  This thesis is a report and analysis of the data collected.KeywordsU.S. Nine National Standards, music education, constructivism, non-music majors, keyboard-centered curriculum</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.M.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Music education--Constructivism--Keyboard-centered curriculum--Music education--Nine National Standards--Non-music majors</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>353</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:65261</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:65261</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Montano, David R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sheinbaum, Jack</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Mayer, Steven</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gould, Eric</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63845</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:46:45Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>THE IMPACT OF SMI, SFI AND ACCOMMODATION ON SATISFACTION IN PARENT-YOUNG ADULT RELATIONSHIPS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hancock, Ryan</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Human Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This study investigates the potential influence of shared musical identities of young adult children and their parents in relation to communicative and relational aspects of family, in order to determine whether musical tastes of individuals impact family relationships. In this research study, 196 college students reported on their perceptions of shared musical identity with their parents, shared family identity, parental accommodative communication behaviors, and family satisfaction. Results indicated that shared musical identity positively predicted perceptions of shared family identity, parental accommodative behaviors, including general accommodation, overaccommodation, topic management, and family satisfaction. Furthermore, shared musical identity and shared family identity positively predicted perceptions of parental accommodative behaviors and family satisfaction. Finally, perceptions of parental accommodative communication behaviors mediated the relationship between shared musical identity and family satisfaction. These findings indicate that music may have a noteworthy influence on family relationships, including impacting perceptions of communication and satisfaction between parents and their children, as well as perceptions of family identity. These findings also suggest that social identity theory, communication accommodation theory, and shared family identity can be applied to, and illuminate aspects of, nuclear family communication and relationships, which are areas not often explored with these theories.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Communication--Psychology--Music--Communication Accommodation Theory--Family--Musical Identity--Shared Family Identity--Social Identity Theory--Young Adults</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>93</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63845</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63845</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Walker, Erin K.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sheinbaum, John K.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Morr-Serewicz, Mary Claire</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Erin K.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63846</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:46:50Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Tackling Tax Evasion: Transfer Price Manipulation, Extractive Natural Resources and a Strategy for the Southern African Customs Union</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>McLennan, Patrick Grant</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>An increase in the number of multinational enterprises (MNEs) has increased the attention on cross-border challenges, such as transfer price manipulation (TPM). TPM is a development issue - it undermines institutions as well as siphons money from government revenues that could be directed towards programs for human development. Pervasive corruption in the natural resource sector supports an environment where TPM can flourish. This paper develops a strategy for combating TPM within the countries of the Southern African Customs Union. It does this by 1) defining the terrain of illicit flows, both generally and specifically to the abuse of transfer pricing through TPM, as well as the nature of corruption in the natural resources sector; 2) exploring the role of private actors by examining global trends in transfer pricing, as well generalizing trends by public actors from recent actions taken by governments of developing countries; 3) exploring the extent of MNE involvement in the natural resources sector within the SACU region, as well as the specific legislation surrounding the sector; and lastly, 4) developing a strategy based on international norms and standards. A fully accurate assessment of TPM is unavailable because of a limited amount of data. Through proxy analysis, this paper finds that the transfer pricing and mineral legislation of the SACU region fails to regulate TPM adequately. Developing a coordinated strategy based off international standards, with the SACU institution and its members as the primary drivers, is the best step towards limiting the abuse.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>International relations--Economics--African studies--Africa--Illicit--Illicit financial flows--Natural resources--Trade--Transfer pricing</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>109</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63846</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63846</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Hughes, Barry B.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Allen, Douglas B.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Grabel, Ilene</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63836</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:46:57Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Dopamine-beta-hydroxylase and Norepinephrine Transporter Immunoreactivity in Rat Taste Buds</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Walton, Jenna Ashley</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Biological Sciences</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Of the handful of neurotransmitters modulating taste response, norepinephrine (NE) may be the least understood. Although the physiological role of NE has been tested, it is still unclear whether the rat taste bud may serve as an endogenous source of neurotransmitter or if it must be taken up from outside the taste bud. Immunocytochemical analysis of DBH has shown that DBH–LIR is present in taste cells of the rat circumvallate papillae. Specifically, DBH–LIR is present in a subset of Type II taste cells. Nearly all (98%) DBH–LIR cells express PLCβ2–LIR, and about half (41%) of PLCβ2–LIR cells express DBH–LIR. DBH–LIR does not co–localize with NCAM, and thus, is not present in Type III cells.NET–LIR is present in the taste cells of the rat circumvallate papillae. Double labeling of NET–LIR and IP &lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;R3–LIR indicates that NET is present in Type II taste cells. A large proportion (77%) of NET–LIR cells express IP&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;R3–LIR and all (100%) IP&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;R3–LIR cells express NET–LIR. A small proportion (7.8%) of NET–LIR cells also express syntaxin–1–LIR in Type III cells. About a third (32.8%) of syntaxin–1–LIR cells express NET–LIR.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Biology--Neurosciences--Chemoreception--Immunohistochemistry--Norepinephrine--Taste</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>88</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63836</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63836</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Kinnamon, John C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lorenzon, Nancy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Smith, Dwight</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Barbee, Scott</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63829</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:47:04Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Hijas Rebeldes: Chicana Spirituality and the Re (claiming) of the Indigenous</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vargas, Daisy</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Religious Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Though the Chicano nationalist movement of the 1960s and 1970s helped Chicanas/os embrace an indigenous identity traced back to the Aztecs of Mexico, it nevertheless proved alienating to Chicanas. In response to patriarchal structures of control within the Chicano movement and Western culture, Chicanas developed a mestiza consciousness. The grounding of this new epistemic tradition in ancient indigenous practices creates a Chicana spirituality and amethod for identifying with the cosmology and goddess mythology of the Aztecs. Though critics of Chicana spirituality question the authenticity of Chicana claims to indigenous traditions, Chicanas employ their spirituality as tool to transform them into agents of their own identity.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Religion--Ethnic studies--Women&apos;s studies--Aztec--Chicana--Goddess--Indigenism--Spirituality</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>55</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63829</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63829</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Leon, Luis D.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Raschke, Carl</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Calafell, Bernadette</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63828</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:47:11Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Feasting On Four Wheels</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rodriguez-McGill, Mariel Patricia</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Mass Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The documentary film Feasting On Four Wheels explores the new wave of &quot;gourmet&quot; food trucks on the streets of Denver, Colorado. What started as a bigger movement across the country made its way to the Mile High city in 2010 and snowballed to the food-loving community portrayed during the summer of 2011. Interviews with food truck owners, a food truck fabricator and a blogger for DenverStreetFood.com, explore the nature of the movement and how its existence creates a feel of community and culture within the city. The evolution of street food history and the influence of new technology are also discussed in relation to the current day movement.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Film studies--Mass communication--Denver--CO--Documentary--Film--Food Trucks</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>91</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63828</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63828</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Schroeder, Sheila E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ortega, Deb</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Waldman, Diane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Schofield Clark, Lynn</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63821</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:47:29Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Redefining, Crafting, and Re/Presenting Contemporary Ethnicities: Honduran National Identity, 1994-2006</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Frewen, Cordelia A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Anthropology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Since the last quarter of the twentieth century, Fourth World populations, including those in Honduras, have been steadily gaining partial recognition of cultural rights; yet often official discourses of national identity continue to subsume cultural traditions of indigenous and Afro-descendant communities.  Honduras&apos;s heterogeneous ethnic pluralism has historically been combined to promote a more cohesive national identity of a homogenized, mayanized, indo-Hispanic mestizaje. Exclusion and mis- or under-representation of indigenous groups is reinforced by popular imagination, particularly in the cultural heritage and tourism sectors.  Firmly situated within regional Latin American and global trends, over the past two decades, official discourse on Honduran national identity has ostensibly shifted from hegemonic notions of mestizaje to one of ethnic diversity and multiculturalism.This thesis is a multi-sited ethnography that examines the cultural politics of four institutions of power in Honduras. I explore how one state-sponsored project and three private museums contributed to the redefinition of ethnicity in Honduran national identity.  I suggest that although these institutions seemingly project the new official discourse of multiculturalism, in fact they uphold antiquated notions of national identity and continue to depict reductionist, universalized, and exclusionary visions of ethnicity in Honduran national identity.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Cultural anthropology--Museum studies--Artisanry--Ethnicity--Honduras--Museums--National identity</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>254</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63821</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63821</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Kreps, Christina F.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>St. Jacques, Ermitte</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Euraque, Dario A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63838</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:47:43Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Foreign Savings, Financialization and Minsky:  How External Capital Flows Pave the Way for Financial Instability in the Face of Increasing Risk</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fresques, Marcus</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Economics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Minsky&apos;s Financial Instability Hypothesis has not come without its fair share of criticism.  Much ado about Minsky&apos;s endogenous business cycle theory stems from a model where boom-time profit opportunities indelibly encourage firms to finance investment by leveraging their fixed capital assets against their internal liquidity.  Opposition to Minsky often points to two distinct circumstances that might discourage the external finance of investment: a rise in effective demand and increasing risk.  A rise in effective demand can increase the retained earnings of a firm providing more capital to internally finance investment and investment financed from retained earning is less risky than investment financed with debt.  This has fueled criticism of Minsky&apos;s framework as having controversial assumptions that discourage rather than encourage financial instability.This paper examines Minsky&apos;s Financial Instability Hypothesis from a savings and debt point of view in order to determine whether or not Minsky&apos;s financial crisis theory holds up to its critics.  It looks at the peculiar role of foreign savings in creating an incentive for financialization and how that engenders financial instability.  Moreover, I hope to display a theoretical argument that unifies much of the criticism of Minsky with the valuable contributions he has made to economic theory.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Economic theory</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>71</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63838</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63838</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Mott, Tracy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Piovani, Chiara</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Grabel, Ilene</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ho, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63826</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:47:48Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>DESIGN AND SYNTHESIS OF NOVEL FLUORESCENT NUCLEOSIDE ANALOGUES</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Elsharif, Nada Abdulnasir</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Chemistry and Biochemistry</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This project aimed to obtain a set of fluorescent nucleoside analogues that closely resemble cytosine with extending the aromatic surface (extended conjugation) for enhance the photophysical properties.We have synthesized 2-amino [4,5-b]quinoline-one ring tCC  under super dry reaction conditions in &lt;10% yield.In addition, we have successfully reported new tC nucleoside derivatives with electrons donor substituent OCH3 group at carbon 7, tC7OMe, and the other at carbon 8, tC8OMe. These different substitution positions offer important distinctions between the design of the tC, tC8OMe, and tC7OMe. The unsubstituted tC nucleoside was easy to synthesize. In contrast, the synthetic strategy of the tC7OMe nucleoside that has electron donor substituent group OCH3 located at carbon 7 and para to amino group is synthetically less challenging and higher yielding than synthesis of tC8OMe which has OCH3 group substituent meta to amine group.Moreover, the fluorescence studies of modified tC nucleosides demonstrated distinguish fluorescence emission and absorption wavelengths for tC7OMe, and tC8OMe, which displayed higher quantum yields and brightness compared to unmodified tC, dependent on mismatch position of the electron donor group (7 or 8) on the tC.  This can be explained by the fact that the donor group OCH3 which allow for extended conjugation of unshared pairs of electrons lead to increases the freedom of the ᴨ-electrons and likely to raise the fluorescence.   Also, our fluorescence study established that there are effects of the different positions of substituent donor group. The fluorescence emission wavelength of tC8OMe, where the OCH3 is meta to amino group, is red sifted longer than the fluorescence emission wavelength of tC7OMe, where the OCH3 is para to amino group; however, tC7OMe exhibited higher quantum yield and brightness than tC8OMe.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Organic chemistry--Chemistry--Fluorescent nucleoside--Photophysical properties--TC8OMe--TC7OMe--TC nucleoside analogues</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>135</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63826</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63826</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Purse, Byron W.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Purse, Byron</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Blankenship, Todd</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kutateladze, Andrei</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Knowles, Michelle</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Eaton, Sandra</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63841</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:48:02Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>CONNEXIN-32 AND CONNEXIN-43 IMMUNOREACTIVITY IN  RODENT TASTE BUDS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bond, Amanda Elizabeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Biological Sciences</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Studies indicate that ATP is one of the primary neurotransmitters in taste transduction. ATP release occurs from taste cells via specific hemichannels such as pannexin/connexin hemichannels (Huang et al., 2007; Romanov et al., 2007). We hypothesize that Type II (receptor) and possibly Type III (presynaptic) cells release ATP at sites containing pannexin/connexin hemichannels. In this study, we examine the presence of connexin–32–LIR (Like Immunoreactivity) and connexin–43–LIR in rodent taste buds through immunocytochemical analysis and DAB (Di–amino–benzidine) immunoelectron microscopy. We observed that connexin–32–LIR co–localizes with P2X2–LIR in nerve fibers and in a small subset of NCAM–LIR cells. Connexin–32–LIR does not co–localize with α–gustducin–LIR or PLCβ2–LIR. We observed that connexin–43–LIR is present in a subset of PLCβ2–LIR cells and in a subset of α–gustducin–LIR cells. Connexin–43–LIR does not co–localize with NCAM–LIR cells or P2X2–LIR nerve fibers. These results are consistent with our results observed using DAB immunoelectron microscopy. Thus, our results indicate that both connexin–32 is expressed in Type III cells and nerve fibers and connexin–43 is expressed in Type II cells in rodent circumvallate taste buds.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Neurosciences--Biology--Connexin-32--Connexin-43--Electron Microscopy--Gap Junction--Immunocytochemistry--Taste</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>136</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63841</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63841</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Kinnamon, John C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Smith, Dwight</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Angleson, Joseph</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lorenzon, Nancy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Snyder, Judith</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63844</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:48:17Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>THE THEORETICAL SYMBOLISM OF ERUVIN: A Model of Dual-Identity and Sacred Space</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hanson, Liza Stoltz</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Religious Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Eruvin are an innovative solution to the logistical &quot;problem&quot; of carrying on the weekly Sabbath. Boundaries that symbolically extend the walls of private homes into the public sphere, eruvin allow Orthodox Jews to carry objects outside of their homes on the Sabbath, a seemingly simple act that would otherwise be prohibited. Constructed according to intricate Rabbinic specifications, eruvin use existing architectural elements such as walls, train tracks, roadways and telephone wires, as well as natural features like rivers to create a continuous boundary. This paper will examine the theoretical significance of creating such a space. My argument maintains that beyond the functional application for observant Jews, eruvin strengthen the bonds of Jewish communities while subsequently allowing for the full integration of the same Jewish community into the majority &quot;mainstream&quot; culture. Further, they represent a challenge to western notions of space, most emphatically the concept that physical space can hold more than a singular meaning; the result is that the eruv becomes a model for &quot;territoriality without sovereignty ,&quot; or a microcosm of symbolic Jewish geography while simultaneously being a part of the American cultural landscape.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Religion--Judaic studies</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>46</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63844</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63844</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Robbins, Gregory A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pessin, Sarah</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Schofield, Alison</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63848</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:48:22Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Rethinking Rosato: Understanding the Genesis of European Integration</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brienzo, Andrew J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>A balance-of-power argument that completely discounts the role played by the United States has been employed in a recent attempt to explain both the origins of European integration and the Continent&apos;s recent difficulties. This thesis sets out to rebut these notions through an examination of the historical record. Such an examination makes it clear that France and West Germany&apos;s reasons for pursuing the integration of Western Europe were grounded in these states&apos; relationships with one another within the postwar context, not in their fear of Soviet aggression. France, after all, was seeking to rebuild itself and hold down the Germans after the war, while West Germany was seeking to regain its sovereignty. Further, it is clear from the historical record that the role played by the United States in the earliest iterations of postwar European integration was critical and should not be discounted.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Political Science--Adenauer--Eisenhower--European Coal and Steel Community--European Union--Monnet--Truman</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>118</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63848</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63848</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Griffith, Lewis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Epstein, Rachel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Conant, Lisa</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Griffith, Lewis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63834</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:48:30Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>If There&apos;s No &quot;Fat Lady,&quot; When is the Opera Over?:  An Exploration of Changing Physical Image Standards in Present-Day Opera</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stephenson, Emily L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Music</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Though present-day American society generally assumes opera is one of the few remaining entertainment fields where talent matters more than physical appearance, as the 2004 firing of Deborah Voigt demonstrates, present-day opera singers are increasingly being held to stricter image standards.  In 2004, Covent Garden dismissed Voigt from their production of Ariadne auf Naxos, in which Voigt was supposed to reprise her critically acclaimed interpretation of the title role.  According to Voigt, Covent Garden&apos;s casting director Peter Katona felt that she was too large to fit into the black dress the new production required of the character.  Voigt&apos;s removal from the production and consequent media attention made opera&apos;s new image standards public.  My ethnographic and archival research concludes that present-day opera singers are expected to fit much more stringent physical standards.  Though popular publications like Classical Singer, Time, and Newsweek have published articles exploring the new standards, little published academic work has explored this topic.  As both a singer and an ethnomusicologist, I have spent several years observing and interviewing singers at various stages.  This thesis explores evidence supporting the focus on image within opera and examines how this emphasis impacts various facets of the opera community.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Music--Ethnography--Image--Music--Opera</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>117</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63834</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63834</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Morelli, Sarah</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Buxton, Rod</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sheinbaum, John</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Banducci, Antonia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63817</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:48:44Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Preventing the Clash: Reexamining U.S. Public Diplomacy in the Middle East</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Martin, Clifton</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This paper analyzes U.S. public diplomacy in the Middle East. In explaining the concept of public diplomacy itself and its evolution in the United States, four factors are identified as most crucial to the capabilities and limitations of U.S. public diplomacy in the region: U.S. foreign policy options, institutions, strategies, and tools. These factors are shown to affect the outcome of U.S. public diplomacy programming in the Middle East and are the foundation for a new U.S. public diplomacy model.The paper continues by examining the development of contemporary U.S. foreign policy in the Middle East, providing a traceable landscape upon which U.S. public diplomacy sits and responds to increasingly negative public opinion of the United States. Generally, U.S. foreign policy has shifted toward more aggressive containment policies while promoting support of democratization despite partnership with repressive regimes. While the United States is able to pursue a containment strategy, such contradictory elements exacerbate the structural and institutional limitations of its public diplomacy outcomes in the region.Finally, this paper considers whether or not U.S. public diplomacy has been an underdeveloped foreign policy tool. The conclusion is that the capabilities of the current U.S. public diplomacy experiment are substantially limited due to a lack of institutional participation in the outset of policy formulation. As such, brief recommendations are put forth to correct these contradictory elements of U.S. foreign policy.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>International relations--Middle Eastern studies--History--Middle East--Public Diplomacy</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>112</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63817</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63817</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Hashemi, Nader</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Griffith, Lewis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Stanton, Andrea</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Viotti, Paul R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63824</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:48:59Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Estradiol Modulation of Calcium Dynamics in Pituitary MMQ Lactotroph Cells</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pauckova, Monika</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Biological Sciences</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Pituitary lactotrophs are excitable cells that exhibit spontaneous, calcium influx triggering prolactin (PRL) secretion to stimulate lactation. Lactotrophs express estrogen receptors (ER) and are a well established estrogen-responsive cell system. 17B-estradiol (E2) is known to directly affect lactotrophs by increasing PRL transcription and biosynthesis, intracellular Ca2+ concentration ([Ca2+]i) and PRL secretion. This study demonstrates that the MMQ clonal cell line, isolated from the 7315a rat pituitary tumor, is a model lactotroph cell line that is E2-responsive. Spontaneous and evoked Ca2+ transients were especially sensitive to L-type channel block, but not affected by block of omega-conotoxin-GVIA-sensitive CaV channels or TTX-sensitive voltage-gated Na+ (Nav) channels. A population of 17B-Estradiol-treated cells exhibited enhanced spontaneous Ca2+ oscillation amplitude and frequency and depolarization-evoked Ca2+ transients. E2 treatment significantly enhanced the Ca2+ response through dihydropyridine-sensitive voltage-gated Ca2+ (Cav) channels, suggesting that 17B-Estradiol increased L-type Ca2+ channel genomic expression.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Biology--Calcium--Estradiol--Lactotropes--Lactotrophs--MMQ</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>57</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63824</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63824</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Lorenzon, Nancy M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Smith, Dwight</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Angleson, Joe</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Dores, Robert</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63832</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:49:03Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Kicking the Can</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ellis, Peter Maring</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Mass Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Kicking the Can is a video documentary that explores the financial crisis of 2008 and the socio-political factors that led to the collapse. The documentary was produced over the course of a year and a half, and contains interviews with economists, politicians, academics, and U.S. citizens. Kicking the Can ultimately reveals that the financial crisis is a complex issue that can be analyzed and interpreted from a variety of political and social perspectives. This paper documents the making of the film, the production involved, and the process of working with collaborators and other crewmates.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Film studies--Economic history--Economics--2008--Crisis--Depression--Documentary--Financial--Recession</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>76</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63832</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63832</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Keables, Michael</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Buxton, Rodney</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Botta, Renee</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Waldman, Diane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63865</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:49:10Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Abbot Suger&apos;s Silent Soliloquy of Public Aesthetics in the Medieval Saint Denis Abbey</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ceas, Sandra Jean</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Religious Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Abbot Suger transformed the twelfth-century medieval Saint Denis abbey from a didactic Romanesque prayer hall to a spiritually illuminating pre-Gothic worship center. The extant culture, although primarily illiterate, was poised on the threshold of Scholasticism, the rational pursuit of &quot;reason,&quot; which challenged the Christian doctrine of  &quot;faith.&quot; Abbot Suger, fully aware of the secular threat, was suitably positioned to be a significant instrument for saving souls from the diversion of their trust in God toward a reliance on logical thinking. Suger undertook a major art restoration campaign for the Saint Denis abbey to create an environment of public aesthetics that engendered a new, heightened experience of worship and devotion that illuminated God&apos;s Sovereignty. Suger synthesized centuries of philosophy and theology to manifest a silent soliloquy of what was ineffable at the time.Michel Foucault&apos;s method of intellectual archeological inquiry is used to gather relevant information, which contributed to Suger&apos;s vision and his artistic practice. Suger&apos;s art restoration in the Saint Denis abbey manifested the aesthetics of anagogical agency to lift the heads of worshipers toward a theophany of Divine Wisdom.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Aesthetics--Medieval history--Spirituality--Abbot Suger--Art and the ineffable--Divine Inspiration--Public Aesthetics--Saint Denis Abbey--Silent Soliloquy</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>125</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63865</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63865</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Raschke, Carl</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Robbins, Gregory A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kreps, Christian</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63837</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:49:15Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Democratic Transitions in Divided States: The Case of Iraq</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kingma, Kara Leigh</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Many theorists have posited that democratic transitions in states divided along ethnic, racial, or religious lines are accompanied by violent conflict and thus unlikely to succeed. The end of authoritarian rule in Iraq and the introduction of democracy by the United States has been followed by many such challenges, and it has been argued that the artificial Iraqi state and its Kurdish, Sunni, and Shia communities does not possess the unity as required by democratic government. However, an informed analysis of Iraqi democracy requires attention to the role of its authoritarian leaders and war and economic hardships in making Iraq&apos;s ethnosectarian communities largely competitive and conflictual. Furthermore, it is possible that continued participation in democratic institutions and processes, though imperfect, may build support for the system and legitimize it as the means to make political decisions. As a consequence, Iraqis may increasingly identify with the state and its democratic system rather than their more rigid, and at times conflicting, ethnosectarian identities.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Middle Eastern studies</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>142</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63837</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63837</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Hashemi, Nader</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63849</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:49:19Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Alchemical Transformation and the Grief-Threshold in H.D.&apos;s Helen in Egypt</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bennett, Eliza Claire</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>English</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>In H.D&apos;s lyric epic, &lt;italic&gt;Helen in Egypt&lt;/italic&gt;, Helen of Troy experiences a phenomenological transformation in the brazier of the heart, which burns both on the beach of her new home in Egypt and in the depths of her psychic life.  I have envisioned a process by which Helen psychologically enters into the brazier&apos;s flames to begin an alchemical process, so that she might see the beauty of the earth emerge and understand the rhythmic significance of the heart&apos;s perception.  I call the brazier&apos;s (or the heart&apos;s) place of alchemical transformation the &lt;italic&gt;grief-threshold&lt;/italic&gt;, which balances Helen on the edge of the underworld, but also reveals that beauty is the aquifer of life&apos;s longing, both for her, and for mythical figures of her imaginal experience.  The visitations of figures like Achilles, Theseus, and Paris, bring Helen closer to understanding coniunctio, the alchemical marriage of masculine and feminine that takes place in the brazier of the heart.  Her identification with mysterious feminine figures like Aphrodite, Persephone, Thetis, and the Egyptian goddess Isis provides a mythic landscape through which to welcome &lt;italic&gt;anima mundi&lt;/italic&gt;--the soul of the world--inherent in the earth&apos;s beauty.  She finally learns that the alchemically transforming heart perceives with a greater trajectory, expanding the body and the psyche into intimate relationship with an Aphroditic consciousness that reveals the conversational wisdom of the earth and the heavens.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Literature--Psychology--Philosophy--Alchemy--Bachelard--H.D.--Jungian--Mythology--Phenomenology</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>69</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63849</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63849</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Howard, W. Scott</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Seeburger, Frank</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ramke, Bin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63858</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:49:24Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>FEATURE-BASED NEURO-SYMBOLIC NETWORKS FOR GLOBAL DIAGNOSTICS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schantz, Tracy Lynn</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Engineered system diagnostics have been researched over the years with many successful results. From transportation systems to office technologies, many have been equipped with self-diagnostic capabilities and are called Smart Machines. In spite of these advances, current diagnostic systems are driven by direct sensory information without much concern for patterns of the system behavior or features associated with them. For large-scale systems with complex dynamics, global as well as local diagnostics become of great importance, where sensory information is used as input for the local diagnostics, and patterns of behavior or features are utilized for global diagnostics.The main objective of this research is to develop a bio-inspired data/information architecture for feature-based global diagnostics of a large-scale system. In order to accomplish this goal, information from local diagnostic systems is integrated with physical and engineering principles (e.g. conservation of momentum) to create a feature-based neuro-symbolic network. This network is very similar to a neural network, except that it is based on a physical equation, and it uses features instead of raw data. Results from this network identify patterns of behavior that display whether the system has any faulty states.  The architecture of this network includes two feature-based neuro-symbolic networks, one for the x-axis and one for the z-axis. Each of these networks has four inputs and four outputs, and includes one hidden layer.In order to verify performance of this feature-based diagnostic system, a working aircraft model has been equipped with pressure sensors on its wing surface, and data has been taken during flight. By using computational fluid dynamic analysis, pressure contours along the wing have been developed. These pressure patterns have been used as input for our developed feature-based neuro-symbolic networks to predict the state of the model aircraft in real-time. Based on these research results, we have developed a neuro-symbolic diagnostic technique which can be applied to fault detection of large-scale systems, using local diagnostic information.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Mechanical engineering--Artificial intelligence--Aircraft structural health monitoring--Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD)--Feature-based diagnostics--Global diagnostics--Neural network--Neuro-symbolic network</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>116</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63858</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63858</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Shoureshi, Rahmat</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Yi, Yun-Bo</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gao, David</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lengsfeld, Corinne</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63856</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:49:29Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ibn Khaldun and the Modern Social Sciences: A Comparative Theoretical Inquiry into Society, the State, and Revolution</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Garrison, Douglas Herthum</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This thesis represents a link in a long chain of recent Western scholarship that has attempted to bring the work of Ibn Khaldun, the late 14th century Tunisian jurist and historian, into the mainstream of historiographic, political, and sociological learning. Why Ibn Khaldun? What makes his work stand out among the classics of pre-modern and early-modern political and social theory? Why are his ideas still relevant to the study of politics and societies today? My thesis attempts to answer these questions through the lenses of comparative political theory and theoretical reinterpretation.The study hinges on a thematic comparison of Ibn Khaldun&apos;s major ideas to those authors considered mainstays in the pantheon of Western social science: Thucydides, Machiavelli, Hobbes, Rousseau, and Hegel. Such comparison is necessary, I believe, to emphasize the vast contextual differences among the authors while simultaneously highlighting their many theoretical similarities. By doing so, I demonstrate both the surprisingly contemporary relevance and lasting theoretical value of Ibn Khaldun&apos;s conceptualization of political power, the state, and social change.Through careful comparison, this study attempts to simultaneously deepen and strengthen extant understandings of Ibn Khaldun&apos;s ideas while unearthing additional aspects either marginalized or neglected by the predominant scholarship. Moreover, it seeks to demonstrate Ibn Khaldun&apos;s lasting contribution and value to the modern social sciences--especially as it relates to the study of political rebellion and social change</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Political Science--Philosophy--Comparative political theory--Ibn Khaldun--Political ethics</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>83</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63856</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63856</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Hashemi, Nader</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gilbert, Alan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Stanton, Andrea</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63868</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:49:34Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Russian Foreign Policy in the Middle East: Priorities and Effectiveness</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schneider, Brett A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This paper analyzes contemporary Russian Foreign Policy toward the Middle East.  Six factors are identified as most critical to Russian foreign policy in the region: Islamic terrorism, arms transfers, natural resources, influence over former Soviet Spaces, general trade, and great power status.  With rare exceptions, these principles are shown to guide Russian foreign policy in the Middle East since 2000.The paper continues by considering the effectiveness of Russia in achieving its desired policy outcomes in the Middle East.  This includes assessing situations in which two or more priorities run counter to each other.  Generally, Russia is shown to be effective at achieving its more pragmatic goals, and ineffective at achieving its abstract ones.Finally, the paper considers whether or not Russian foreign policy has remained consistent through the Arab Spring.  The conclusion is that Russia is presently unable to move beyond policies that represent clear mutual benefits with Middle Eastern states.  As such, Russia is not a threat to undermine fundamental United States policy objectives in the region.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>International relations--Arab Spring--Foreign Policy--Middle East--Relations--Russia</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>111</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63868</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63868</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Szyliowicz, Joseph S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sciarcon, Jonathan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hashemi, Nader</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63855</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:49:39Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Protein Aggregation through Acoustic Cavitation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Giarratano, John Angelo</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Bioengineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Therapeutic proteins represent an essential piece of a health management plan for diseases such as diabetes, cancer, hemophilia, Crohn&apos;s Disease, and myocardial infarction. These proteins, however, must be maintained in their correct, biologically active conformation throughout processing, transportation, and delivery. This requirement poses serious engineering challenges because of a protein&apos;s susceptibility to thermodynamic instabilities resulting from the weak bonds driving the tertiary structure of the molecule.  A particularly problematic type of protein degradation is aggregation. Administration of aggregated proteins, a particularly problematic degradation form, can have dire consequences, including blocking a patient&apos;s responsiveness to therapy, inducing immunogenicity, and even anaphylactic shock and death. Normal shipping and delivery methodologies are suspected of causing protein aggregation after the normal quality control process has been completed. This work investigates the effect of acoustic cavitation on protein aggregation as a function of impurity level, gas-liquid surface to value ratios, protein concentration, solution viscosity, density, surface tension, and nebulization time. A 0.2M and pH of 4.2 Glycine buffer solution was utilized with IVIg protein at 0.5, 1.0, 5.0, and 10.0 mg/ml and 20ºC. Protein aggregates were characterized using Microflow imaging and NanoSight tracking analysis. Transient cavitation and formation of radicals was monitored using classical iodine assays.  Higher protein aggregation is observed in solutions that initially contain greater amounts of impurities or have a larger contact area with the gas interface. Aggregate production in hyper clean solutions, with no gas-liquid interface, initially increases with protein concentration, but eventually decreases at high concentrations.In contrast, aggregation rates in hyper clean solution with a gas-liquid interface continue to fall with increasing protein concentration.  The size of the particulate in these two conditions suggests different degradation pathways. The small sizes when a gas interface is available are likely a result of the large area over which the process takes place. The effect of concentration is actually an effect of diffusion or availability for proteins at the surface. The large sizes found in conditions with no gas interface suggest a much more concentrated process consistent with an intense energy release at a single location. Moreover, monitoring of the formation of I3- from iodine as a function of nebulization time shows increasing production or radicals. All this supports the hypothesis that ultrasonic pressure waves in protein solutions cause transient cavitation which upon bubble implosion release hydroxyl radicals that can attack the protein in solution.  In this circumstance, a rise in viscosity at higher protein concentration inhibits cavitation by elevating the lowest pressure region based on a specified pressure drop.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Pharmaceutical sciences--Aggregation--Cavitation--Nebulization--Protein</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>70</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63855</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63855</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Lengsfeld, Corinne S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Davidson, Bradley</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Angleson, Joseph</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Zelas-Hahn, Michelle</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63854</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:49:44Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Reduce, Reuse, Recycle?   An Examination of Factors Influencing Environmental Behavior in Denver, Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kasper, Dan</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Non-recycling and non-composting of municipal solid waste have important natural resource management implications, in that they both reduce energy, water, and raw natural resource use.  Responsible waste management also likely has positive climate impacts by virtue of reducing greenhouse gas emissions.  Recycling and composting are pro-environmental behaviors that have been shown to be influenced by numerous socio-demographic and psychological factors.  This study analyzes the correlation of a number of variables with frequency of recycling and composting in select census tracts in Denver, CO, USA, with the goals of informing waste management policy and contributing to the overall pro-environmental behavior literature.  The results show that habit strength as quantified by the Self-Reported Habit Index has the strongest correlation with both recycling and composting behavior.  Overall, waste management policy should focus on influencing habit formation, using literature to dissuade residents from placing plastic bags into recycling bins, and consider charging a minimal fee for recycling.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Behavioral sciences--Natural resource management--Geography--Composting--Environmental Behavior--New Ecological Paradigm--Recycling--Self Reported Habit Index--Waste Management</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>181</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63854</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63854</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Taylor, Matthew</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Reichardt, Charles</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Goetz, Andrew R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sullivan, Donald</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63835</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:49:49Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Cascading Failures and Fundamental Uncertainty: Divergence in Financial Risk Assessment</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Spray, Alexander Kent</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Economics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>By applying common financial risk assessment models to the network economy formalized in Delli Gatti et al. (2006), and by contextualizing both in the broader literature on complexity in economic systems, the question of convergence in economic models is addressed. Critically, a formal state condition is identified which can contribute to the emergence of periods of extreme divergence from expected conditions even in a model characterized by restrictive assumptions regarding agent choice and market structure. The strength of the impact of this state condition, here the topology of a credit network, on the dynamics of the economic system is furthermore shown to be highly dependent upon the structure of the market. The existence of such state conditions has fundamental implications for the evaluation of risk and institutional design in economic systems</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Economics--Finance--Agent Based Modeling--Fundamental Uncertainty--Value at Risk</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>74</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63835</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63835</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Schneider, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63857</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:49:54Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>0300 - 0430</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sierra, Jesus M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Mass Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Night, a time everyone experiences and few contemplate.  It is a time of darkness both figuratively and literally.  Darkness of the soul and of the mind, when some rest and others are restless.  We live in an age of endless day where the night is nothing more than a time to be blinded by electronic light.  With this in mind the question becomes how was our night seen in the past?  Also, how was the night and the darkness represented throughout time?  To answer these questions I researched the topic of night and made a film entitled 0300 - 0430.The film was only recorded between three and four-thirty in the morning and delved into what occurs at night and by whom.  Moving from mountain nightscapes to bustling cities the film explores what it means to be up at night.  Working, partying or at rest each has a part to play.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Film studies--Darkness--Documentary--Night--Poetic--Sagan</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>86</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63857</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63857</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Gault, Tony</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Waldman, Diane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Buxton, Rod</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Fajardo, Rafael</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63853</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:49:59Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sub-Saharan Africa: Searching for a Social Contract</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mayen, David Deng</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This thesis examines the phenomenon of civil war and state failure in sub-Saharan Africa (SSA) from a social contract perspective. Its main hypothesis is that authoritarianism will lead to state failure in the context of SSA.  In this regard, SSA states are political communities that have not done enough to promote and develop a social contract that is compatible with the region&apos;s sociopolitical and structural peculiarities. Since civil war and state failure have hampered different dimensions of human progress in SSA, analyzing the main patterns of conflict will inevitably lead to an underlying incompatibility between existing governing political structures and the region&apos;s social structures. In this case, one major characteristic pattern of civil war and state failure in SSA is that they are caused by delegitimization of government authority by ethnic groups whose allegiance to internal traditional authority is still stronger than to centralized government. Hence, a social contract that will allow ethnic groups to legitimize state authority is what SSA lacks and needs.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>African studies--Civil War--Delegitimization--Social Contract--Sociopolitical--State Failure--Tribe and Ethnic groups</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>189</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63853</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63853</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Griffith, Lewis K.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Feste, Karen A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Goetz, Andrew R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63827</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:50:04Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bottom-Up Methodologies in Emerging Models</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Cahoon, Thomas Sean</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Religious Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The post-modern turn in the millennial generation has prompted a response toward religious and organizational authorities, whose organizations do not keep with the changing demand of post-modern individuals. The shift in preferences is marked by a movement from top-down hierarchical models, toward a de-centralized, bottom-up style demonstrated in recent movements. This paper examines the shift of doctrine and praxis within the American evangelical church and a simultaneous development of new methodologies in social justice organizations in these response movements.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Religion--Theology--Bottom up--Emergent--Emerging Church--Social justice</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>60</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63827</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63827</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Leon, Luis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wadsworth, Nancy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Raschke, Carl</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63820</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:50:19Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nutraceutical Antioxidants and Their Therapeutic Potential in Neurodegeneration</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ross, Erika Kristine</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Biological Sciences</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a fatal neuromuscular disease that affects motor neurons of the brain and spinal cord. Many studies indicate that mitochondrial oxidative stress (MOS) is a principal mechanism underlying the pathophysiology of this and other devastating neurodegenerative diseases. Here, we investigated a unique whey protein supplement (Immunocal®) to determine its neuroprotective efficacy in several in vitro models of MOS and in an in vivo mouse model of ALS. This non-denatured whey supplement contains cystine which is an oxidized form of cysteine, an essential precursor for synthesis of the endogenous antioxidant, glutathione (GSH). In primary cultured rat cerebellar granule neurons (CGNs), pre- incubation with Immunocal® completely protected against MOS induced by HA14-1, an inhibitor of the pro-survival Bcl-2 protein. This effect was prevented by co-incubation with the gamma-glutamyl cysteine ligase inhibitor, buthionine sulfoximine, demonstrating that the de novo synthesis of GSH underlies the neuroprotective mechanism of Immunocal®. Additionally, Immunocal® displayed significant protection against an array of MOS-inducing agents, including sodium nitroprusside, copper, and aluminum, supporting its ability to upregulate mitochondrial antioxidant capacity. In accordance with these findings in CGNs, Immunocal® decreased cell death due to both H2O2 and glutamate toxicity in NSC34 motor neuron-like cells. Immunocal® also significantly protected CHO cells from MOS evoked by overexpression of amyloid precursor protein (APP). Immunocal® treatment in NSC34 motor neuron-like cells decreased cell death caused by both H2O2 and glutamate glycine. Most compelling are our findings in the hSOD1G93A mouse model of ALS. These mice were given Immunocal® (3.33% solution in drinking water) ad libitum, beginning at 60-days-old. Although no effect on overall survival was observed, Immunocal®-treated mice displayed a significant (7 ±1.08 day) delay in disease onset, compared to mutant control mice. Importantly, Immunocal®-treated mice showed a highly significant decrease in the rate of decline in grip strength. Finally, using HPLC-ECD we found that whole blood and lumbar spinal cord GSH levels were each depleted by nearly 50% in end-stage hSOD1G93A mice, and these reductions were essentially prevented in mutant mice receiving Immunocal®. These findings suggest that sustaining GSH by supplementation with Immunocal® may help to mitigate the progression of ALS through suppression of MOS.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Biology--Neurosciences--Molecular biology--Anthocyanin--Apoptosis--Cysteine--Glutathione--Neuroprotection--Nutraceutical</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>90</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63820</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63820</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Linseman, Daniel A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lorenzon, Nancy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Patterson, David</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Miller, Keith</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description> 
 <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63833</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:50:30Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Financial Crisis Documentary</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gardner, William Leddy</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Mass Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>&lt;bold&gt;Abstract&lt;bold&gt;This project was a documentary film focused on exploring the 2008 financial crisis in the United States. The documentary incorporates interviews with former Senators, Congressmen and local business leaders in an effort to better understand the causes and effects of the crisis.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Film studies--2008--Documentary--Film--Finance--Gardner</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>87</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63833</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63833</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Howard, Deborah</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Buxton, Rodney</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Botta, Renee</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Waldman, Diane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63840</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:50:44Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Cultural Diabetes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Noll, Keri</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Mass Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Diabetes has become a cultural problem across America, but particularly in the Midwest and Southern regions.  For my film, I explored these two areas and compared the food and exercise culture to one of the healthier regions, the West.  Having moved from Indiana to Colorado, I used my own personal experiences to analyze why people in the Midwest struggle with diabetes and obesity at such a higher rate than those nearer to the Pacific Ocean.  Through a series of interviews with close friends and observational analysis of each state, I came to learn something very important about health: our food culture is embedded and encouraged by the people that surround us, and changing the way we behave is more than just being taught healthy activities.  People can change, but unfortunately I believe the problem is going to have to get worse before America takes it seriously enough to fix it.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Mass communication--Diabetes--Documentary--Film--Food culture--Obesity--United States of America</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>85</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63840</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63840</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Waldman, Diane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Helstosky, Carol</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Schroeder, Sheila</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Schofield-Clark, Lynn</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63867</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:50:59Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ANALYZING THE INTERACTION BETWEEN MELANOCORTIN 5 RECEPTOR, MELANOCORTIN RECEPTOR ACCESSORY PROTEIN 1, AND MELANOCORTIN 2 RECEPTOR IN RAINBOW TROUT</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hill, Domicinda Marie</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Biological Sciences</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Using CHO cells we sought to explore and characterize the functional relationship of rainbow trout MC5 receptor (rtMC5R) with zebrafish MRAP1 (zfMRAP1)  and rainbow trout MC2 receptor (rtMC2R), as well as how the effect of such relationships may play a significant role in Hypothalamic-Pituitary-Adrenal/Interrenal axis activation.  This research demonstrated that rtMC5R can be successfully expressed and functionally activated in CHO cells and, in a manner similar to mammals, α-MSH is the preferred ligand for rtMC5R.  The presence of MRAP1 does not seem to inhibit the expression or function of rtMC5R, rather it appears that it may increase expression and total activation levels.  In contrast, the presence of MRAP1 in conjunction with MC2R reduces expression and total activation levels of rtMC5R.  Findings indicate that rtMC5R may function in three different ways in a cell, depending upon the presence of other local proteins.   The interaction of rtMC5R with MRAP1 and MC2R, and the implications of such interactions will be described in this thesis.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Endocrinology--Biology--MC2R--MC5R--MRAP1--Rainbow Trout</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>56</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63867</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63867</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Dores, Robert M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pegan, Scott</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Linseman, Daniel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lorenzon, Nancy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63815</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:51:10Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Health Insurance Exchanges: A Panacea or A Band-aid?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sanchez de Tagle, Luisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Economics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>In 2010, the 111th Congress passed the first national health care reform in the United States, the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (ACA). This landmark legislation is intended to &quot;fix&quot; a health care system renowned for decreasing access and escalating costs.  This paper examines one of the principal reforms in the ACA, the state health insurance exchanges.  The author finds theoretical and empirical evidence to support the exchanges&apos; potential (in conjunction with other relevant ACA reforms) to increase access, decrease insurers&apos; excess profits and shift health care costs away from those least able to afford them.  The exchanges fall short of becoming a panacea, however, as they leave a large number of people uninsured, even in optimal scenarios.  Thus, the exchanges are essentially another band-aid for the system which covers additional people, yet does not cure the U.S. health care system&apos;s ills.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Economics--Health care management</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>126</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63815</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63815</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Yasar, Yavuz</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kahn, Haider</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Freeman, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Piovani, Chiara</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63814</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-11T16:51:22Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>MODELING OF GROWTH KINETICS AND CHARACTERIZATION OF MEMBRANE MECHANICS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nava, Antonio</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Physics and Astronomy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>One growing field in alternative energy is biofuel production through microorganisms. This field of research includes hydrogen and biofuel production through the cultivation of algae.  In this work, we have selected two different algae to study, Anabaena sp. cpcc 387 and Tetraselmis. Through mathematical modeling of Anabaena we investigated the complex multicellular relationships and colony stability when noise is introduced. We developed a mathematical model using a system of differential equations that simulates the population growth through optical density over time of Anabaena. When the model was compared to experimental data obtained through growing Anabaena in a photobioreactor, we found a strong linear correlation of 0.98 suggesting that the model reasonably simulates the lag, exponential and stationary phase. As a result, the model may be used to study the effects of varying different parameters in Anabaena&apos;s environment in order to predict what effect it will have on colony growth pattern and population.In conjunction with researchers at the National Renewable Energy Laboratory, we characterize Tetraselmis cells&apos; membrane elasticity. Through use of an Atomic Force Microscope (AFM), varying forces were applied to the cell membrane that was used to find the modulus of elasticity to be 79.8 KPa ± 19.8 and 46.9 KPa ± 2.04 for two differentcells tested. Having found the modulus of two cells is the starting point for collecting more data on this strain and other strains along with various other pretreatments. This will allow for cross comparisons between cell membrane strength and give quantitative evidence for which strain and pretreatment yield the weakest cell membrane to allow to lipid extraction.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.S.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Physics--Biophysics--Anabaena--Atomic Force Microscopy--Cell Membrane Characterization--Mathematical Modeling--Photobioreactor--Tetraselmis</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>40</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63814</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63814</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Shaheen, Sean Eric</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Calbi, Maria M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sher, Anna A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ghosh, Kingshuk</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
 </ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
