<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
 <responseDate>2014-12-14T16:41:49Z</responseDate>
 <request verb= "ListRecords">http://digitaldu.coalliance.org/oai2</request>
 <ListRecords>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_68174</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-12-12T04:56:49Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_68140</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Building a Digital Collection at a Small Non-Profit Organization: Opportunities and Challenges</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Thomas, Wendy</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:creator></dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:type>Poster</dc:type>
  <dc:language>Eng</dc:language>
  <dc:format></dc:format>
  <dc:format></dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:description>This poster provides an overview of the process of setting up the first digital library project at a non-profit organization by a group of graduate students and volunteers. It will present the workflows and tools used in building a pilot project and examine the challenges of undertaking digital projects at a small cultural heritage institution with limited technical infrastructure and expertise. 

The Rocky Mountain Philatelic Library is a small non-profit organization run solely by volunteers and funded through membership dues, donations and auctions of donated stamps and ephemera. To keep pace with technology and make their special collections accessible online, the RMPL has piloted a project to digitize a collection of historic postcards.  Working with minimal funds and no technical infrastructure, the project is relying on donated equipment and open source software.   Collaborating on the project are one faculty member and two graduate students from the University of Denver Library and Information Science program and two professional librarians, all participating as volunteers.  The open source content management system Omeka was selected for its flexibility, ease of use and low cost. Steps in the process include creating scanning workflows and standards, creating taxonomies and metadata schema based on Dublin Core and pilot testing all workflows. </dc:description>
  <dc:description>This is a copy of a poster created by Wendy Thomas, graduate student in the Library and Information Science.  The poster describes the process of building a digital postcard collection at the Rocky Mountain Philatelic Library. The poster was presented as part of the Digital Liaisons program at the Annual Meeting of ASIS&amp;T (Association for Information Science and Technology) in Seattle November 3, 2014. </dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Digital collections; Digitization; Postcards; Scanning; Metadata</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage>Colorado</dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Rocky Mountain Philatelic Library</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier></dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier></dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier></dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>© Wendy Thomas</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:68174</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
 </ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
