<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
 <responseDate>2014-05-05T01:05:09Z</responseDate>
 <request verb= "ListRecords">http://digitaldu.coalliance.org/oai2</request>
 <ListRecords>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63843</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:11:19Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Meta-Analytic Review of Cooperative Learning Practices in Higher Education:  A Human Communication Perspective</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Huddy, William Patrick</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Human Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The phrase cooperative learning refers to a pedagogical learning and teaching technique in use in schools from kindergarten through higher education.  The technique involves the structuring of an active classroom environment with students working in groups to discover, solve, and at its basic, provide a framework for dialogue and conversation.  Cooperative learning is grounded in the development of a theory of social interdependence (Morton Deutsch) which states that individuals, working in groups, can in most cases provide for greater productivity and ideas than individuals working alone.  The development of cooperative learning was greatly expanded in the late 1960&apos;s and early 1970&apos;s with the invention of specific group learning techniques led by researchers David and Robert Johnson (Learning Together), Elliot Aronson (Jigsaw), and Robert Slavin (STAD).  These researchers established guidelines (rules) and taxonomies that provided a basis for research in the area of cooperative learning.  At the center of all of these techniques is an element of human communication, most often through the oral/aural communication channel, where group learning and discovery takes place.Cooperative learning and collaborative learning techniques differ in the amount andimplementation of teaching guidelines required in the methodology.  This study (a meta-analysis) weaves through more than 14-hundred published pieces of literature in a varietyof disciplines, narrowing it down to 19 published articles which investigate (through experiments) the effectiveness through learning outcomes of cooperative learning in higher education (college and university level).With studies including more than 2-thousand student-participants in the research, data indicates no significant difference between those classrooms utilizing a cooperative learning format, and those using a traditional lecture/discussion format (d =0.05, 95%, C1:-05 to .14, p&gt;.05, k = 21, N = 2,052).  Though there is no statistical difference between the two teaching techniques, researchers do offer a list of positive classroom observations/variables, which provides a launching point for future research into the use of cooperative learning techniques in higher education.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Communication--Education--Communication--Cooperative Learning--Public Speaking</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>170</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63843</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63843</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Morr Serewicz, Mary Claire</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wood, Roy V.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Dance, Frank E. X.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63089</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:13:08Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Study of Arabic Women and English Language learning</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alkarni, Ream Ali</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Curriculum and Instruction</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The main goal of this study was to interview Arabic women students at Spring International Language Center to record their perceptions, rationale, goals, stories, and opinions about learning English in a U.S. language school. This research was conducted to understand the purposes and goals of Arabic women who come to the United Stated to study the English language, and the importance of English language proficiency, both within and outside the United States.The findings of this study are not only relevant to English language centers in the United States, but also those in other countries. The information and methods used can provide background material to guide further study of Arabic women in general and those who come to the United States to study English for Arabic scholarship agencies and others who have a vested interest in the topic. Furthermore, the findings of this study indicate that English language programs should hire more qualified and experienced instructors. Evaluations of instructors can be used, as a tool for improvement and development of programs, and should also encourage participation by Arabic women inside the classrooms to increase their interaction and involvement with other students. Classes on U.S. culture could be offered before Arabic women come to the United States to learn the English language.The findings of this study provide a basis for future studies of Arabic women and English language learning. The timing of this study is important. The number of Arabic women studying the English language at academic language centers in the United States is increasing rapidly because Arabic countries, such as Libya and Saudi Arabia, are providing scholarships to citizens to promote a more highly educated population.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Adult education</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>134</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63089</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63089</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Uhrmacher, Bruce</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Valdez, Jesse</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Michalec, Paul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62948</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:14:41Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ACCURATE PLAYER MODELING AND CHEAT-PROOF GAMEPLAY IN PEER-TO-PEER BASED MULTIPLAYER ONLINE GAMES</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pittman, Daniel Everett</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Computer Science</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>We present the first detailed measurement study and models of the virtual populations in popular Massively Multiplayer Online Role-Playing Games (MMORPGs). Our results show that, amongst several MMORPGs with very different play styles, the patterns of behaviors are consistent and can be described using a common set of models.In addition, we break down actions common to Trading Card Games (TCGs) and explain how they can be executed between players without the need for a third party referee. In each action, the player is either prevented from cheating, or if they do cheat, the opponent will be able to prove they have done so. We show these methods are secure and may be used in many various styles of TCGs. We measure moves in a real TCG to compare to our implementation of Match+Guardian (M+G), our secure Peer-to-Peer (P2P) protocol for implementing online TCGs. Our results, based on an evaluation of M+G&apos;s performance on the Android (TM) platform, show that M+G can be used in a P2P fashion on mobile devices.Finally, we introduce and outline a HYbrid P2P ARchitecture for Trading Card Games, HYPAR-TCG. The system utilizes Distributed Hash Tables (DHTs) and other P2P overlays to store cached game data and to perform game matchmaking. This helps reduce the network and computational load to the central servers. We describe how a centralized server authority can work in concert with a P2P gameplay protocol, while still allowing for reputation and authoritative account management.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Computer science--Architecture--MMORPG--MOG--Networking--P2P--TCG</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>158</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62948</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62948</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Gauthier Dickey, Chris</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lopez, Mario</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Leutenegger, Scott T.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sturtevant, Nathan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63019</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:19:45Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An Emerging Hispanic Serving Institution Looks Toward the Future: A Case Study on a Collaborative, Community-Based Systemic Change Effort at an Urban Land-Grant College</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dunker, Eric</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Curriculum and Instruction</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Many higher education organizations face the issue of structural isolation (Ruben, 2004) based on a lack of integration and functional coordination between faculty, staff, and students. Community-based research (CBR) offers higher education a more collaborative, wider reaching avenue of organizing a variety of stakeholders around social change. The CBR model is an atypical change model due to its interdisciplinary, participatory, and collaborative structure that values multiple sources of knowledge and focuses on social justice action. As opposed to serving as the &apos;experts&apos; who were performing research on a community of people, academics and community members who utilize CBR focus on the importance of co-learning, capacity building, findings to benefit all partners, and a long-term commitment to reduce social disparities. Taken in the context of higher education, CBR allows students, faculty, staff, and other stakeholders to work together as partners around areas that involve social justice issues.This dissertation highlights an instrumental case study that took place between 2006-2012 involving an Emerging Hispanic Serving Institution and its effort to use principles similar to those found in CBR around organizational change. Themes that were identified in the study include cynicism/fear, sustainability, participatory action, commitment to social justice, transparency, and interdisciplinary spirit.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Higher education--Organizational behavior--Case Study--Change--Community Based Research--Denver--Hispanic Serving--Urban</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>185</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63019</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63019</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Cutforth, Nick</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Martinez, Lisa</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Uhrmacher, Bruce</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Michalec, Paul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63831</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:23:14Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Cayley-Dickson Loops</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kirshtein, Jenya</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Mathematics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>In this dissertation we study the Cayley-Dickson loops, multiplicative structures arising from the standard Cayley-Dickson doubling process. More precisely, the Cayley-Dickson loop Qn is the multiplicative closure of basic elements of the algebra constructed by n applications of the doubling process (the first few examples of such algebras are real numbers, complex numbers, quaternions, octonions, sedenions). Starting at the octonions, Cayley-Dickson algebras and loops become nonassociative, which presents a significant challenge in their study.We describe basic properties of the Cayley-Dickson loops Qn, e.g., inverses, conjugates, orders of elements, and diassociativity. We discuss some important subloops of Qn, for instance, associator subloop, derived subloop, nuclei, center, and show that Qn areHamiltonian. We show that all subloops of Qn of order 16 fall into two isomorphism classes, in particular, any such subloop is either isomorphic to the octonion loop, or the quasioctonion loop. We discuss automorphism groups, inner mapping groups, and multiplication groups of the Cayley-Dickson loops, and describe the progress made on the study of their subloop structure. We also provide incidence tetrahedra for the sedenion loop and other subloops of order 32, generalizing the idea of the octonion multiplication Fano plane.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Mathematics--Cayley-Dickson doubling process--Loop theory--Multiplication group--Nonassociative--Octonion--Sedenion</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>119</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63831</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63831</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Vojtechovsky, Petr</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Daniels, J. Michael</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kinyon, Michael</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ball, Richard</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Galatos, Nikolaos</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Richard</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63328</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:24:43Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Christian Progress and American Myth: A Deep Cultural Analysis of Spatiality and Exceptionalism in Struggles over American Indian Lands</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Klein, Bradley James</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Religious and Theological Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Although typically characterized in politico-economic, social, and environmental terms, land struggles involving American Indian communities can be more accurately and valuably characterized as deep culture conflicts over the problem of space. As scholars like Vine Deloria Jr. and Tink Tinker contend, a significant distinction can be noted between the traditional American Indian and White Western approaches to this problem regarding how human communities should relate to particular spatial locations. In short, while Indian peoples tend to situate their identities relative to clearly defined places or lands, individuals of European descent are inclined to subordinate spatial relations to temporal concerns. Considering this distinction in light of the United States&apos; particular context of power, this dissertation explores the connection between spatiality and faith in American Exceptionalism.I argue that the widespread Exceptionalist faith depends profoundly upon the perpetuation of a fundamental disorientation to space deep within the dominant culture. American Exceptionalism, as a particular discursive formation within the master narrative about America, functions to prevent local communities from meaningfully and relationally engaging the spaces in which they exist. It does so in part by shaping thought about American identity and history through a deceptive set of images of the land. Conversely, the cultural influence of a deeply embedded disorientation to space ensures that only those types of behavior which support Exceptionalism can be deemed logically acceptable and ethically proper. This largely unconscious cognitive-behavioral approach legitimizes and extends politico-economic hegemony, creating an oppressive feedback loop of privilege into which only those individuals deemed &quot;American-enough&quot; are enabled to enter. The feedback loop is sustained both deliberately and implicitly, as the privileged seek to protect their advantage and the marginalized are socialized not to question the claims of the master narrative.The illicit bond between spatial disorientation and Exceptionalist faith touches nearly every corner of American life. However, its complex nature is exposed perhaps most explicitly and thoroughly through struggles over American Indian lands, which demonstrate the intimate interconnection between environmental exploitation and the exploitation of those types of beings (both human and non-human) habitually classified as &quot;Other.&quot;Based firmly in the disciplinary realm of cultural studies and utilizing discursive-semiotic analysis as a primary methodological tool, the dissertation is advanced through a theoretical synthesis which illustrates the enduring influence of Western cultural mores and Christian theological values. The synthesis is built upon a two-level deconstruction of deep cultural symbols related to space. First, spatial cognition is considered in light of four well-known yet deceptive images which index how the land should be conceptualized. These four images include promised land, terra nullius (&quot;uninhabited land&quot;), frontier wilderness, and city upon a hill. Next, spatial behavior is investigated in relation to four broadly accepted themes which signify how the land should be treated. These themes are categorized as privilege, property, positivism, and progress. Finally, the theoretical synthesis is evaluated in light of three distinctive responses to the natural world present and active within the dominant culture-dominion, stewardship, and deep ecology-and three case studies involving historical struggles over Indian lands: Newe Sogobia (&quot;Land of the People&quot;) and the Western Shoshone of the Nevada region, Crandon Mine and the Sokaogon Ojibwe of northern Wisconsin, and the &quot;Save San Onofre&quot; campaign and the Acjachemen of southern California.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Environmental justice--American studies--Cultural anthropology--American Exceptionalism--Christianity--Colonialism--Deep Culture--Land--Spatial Disorientation</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>539</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63328</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63328</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Tinker, Tink</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hamilton, Sally</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Clemmer-Smith, Richard</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wadsworth, Nancy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63063</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:26:28Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Cognitive Reappraisal Ability as a Protective Factor: Resilience to Stress Across Time and Context</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Troy, Allison S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Emotion regulation is crucially involved in individuals&apos; psychological health. For example, the frequent use of cognitive reappraisal, or changing the way one thinks about an emotional event, is positively associated with psychological health. Recent cross-sectional findings have shown that the ability to use cognitive reappraisal (cognitive reappraisal ability; CRA) is associated with lower depression in the context of high stress. However, two important questions about CRA remain unexamined: 1) Does CRA predict long-term adjustment to stress? 2) Do the protective effects of CRA depend upon the type of stress encountered? To examine these questions, a community sample of men and women (n=181) who had recently experienced a stressful life event was recruited and a prospective longitudinal design was employed. Life stress severity, stressor controllability, and depressive symptoms were measured at Time 1 and at Time 2 (6 months later). CRA was measured using a multi-method laboratory challenge at Time 1.  The results of Question 1 revealed a significant prospective relationship in which CRA interacted with changes in life stress to predict changes in depression between Time 1 and Time 2. Specifically, among individuals with greater increases in stress, those with high CRA reported significantly smaller increases in depressive symptoms relative to those with low CRA. For Question 2, results indicated that the protective effects of CRA depend upon the stressors&apos; controllability. Specifically, in highly stressful contexts that were uncontrollable, the protective effects of CRA remained, such that high CRA was associated with lower levels of depressive symptoms. In highly stressful contexts that were controllable, the protective effects of CRA were reversed, such that high CRA was associated with higher levels of depressive symptoms. Thus, CRA appears to be adaptive in uncontrollable but maladaptive in controllable stressful contexts. Overall, these results suggest that, for highly stressed individuals, CRA is an important protective factor against long-term increases in depression. Importantly, however, these protective effects depend upon the type of stressful context encountered. These results have important implications for understanding how emotion regulation ability contributes to risk and resilience in the face of stress, for clinical interventions and prevention programs, and for understanding what constitutes adaptive emotion regulation across contexts.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Experimental psychology--Physiological psychology--Social psychology--Cognitive reappraisal--Context--Depression--Emotion regulation--Resilience--Stress</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>107</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63063</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63063</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Mauss, Iris B.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McRae, Kateri</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Jones, Arthur</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McIntosh, Daniel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Shirk, Stephen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject> 
 <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62887</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:27:37Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>DEVELOPMENT OF A MEASURE ASSESSING KNOWLEDGE AND USE OF INTERNAL PUNCTUATION TO SIGNAL SYNTACTIC RELATIONSHIPS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Howard, Pamela Sue</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Educational Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>A literary debate has been ongoing from the early 1900s regarding not only the place of grammar instruction in the classroom but even of the veracity of a grammatical standard, such as Standard American English, by which grammar skills may be measured. Very little empirical research has been attempted to compare the effectiveness of teaching methods because grammar assessment has been given even less attention. Therefore, to address this gap in the literature and to explore whether objective testing is suitable for assessing grammar skills, a 51-item measure was constructed to test the use of internal punctuation (commas, semicolons, and colons) and identification of syntactical structures (phrases and clauses). Rasch analysis found the measure as a whole possibly supporting a second dimension; therefore, the measure was analyzed as two scales: (a) a 34-item test of internal punctuation use and (b) a 16-item identification of syntactic structures. Both scales were found to be sufficiently unidimensional and reliable. In addition, scalar invariance of both was determined through DIF analysis by educational level. Validity evidence was obtained through a series of correlations with survey items assessing self-confidence and knowledge of the constructs tested in each scale. With the promising results of this endeavor in that objective testing can be effective, perhaps the debate may inspire researchers and educators alike to consider formal instruction of grammar in the context of a standard.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Educational tests &amp; measurements--Teacher education--Educational evaluation--Education Measurement--Grammar--Grammar Tests--Item Response Theory--Rasch Modeling--Secondary Education</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>141</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62887</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62887</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cheesman, Elaine</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63859</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:29:03Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>DEVELOPMENT OF A MEASURE OF CORPORATE SAFETY CULTURE FOR THE TRANSPORTATION INDUSTRY</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Colarossi, David Vincent</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Counseling Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This project was designed to develop the Corporate Safety Culture Scale, a unique measure of corporate safety culture that is supported by a strong theoretical foundation.  Items were developed conceptually, discussed in cognitive interviews, and submitted to expert review.  Survey items were administered to employees of a large public transportation organization.  Principle components analysis reduced the data and identified an empirical model.  The empirical model held two domains identified as: 1) &quot;Values,&quot; and 2) &quot;Behavior.&quot;  Confirmatory factor analysis compared the fit of the empirical model with that of a modified empirical model, and the hypothesized model, which held the following three domains: 1) &quot;Behavior,&quot; 2) &quot;Values,&quot; and 3) &quot;Meaning Systems.&quot; Goodness of fit indices (Chi-Squared, RMSEA, CFI, ECVI) identified the modified empirical structure as the model with best fit.   The similarities between the hypothesized and modified empirical models suggested that the CSCS carries strong theoretical support.The measure&apos;s reliability was tested using Cronbach&apos;s Alpha.  The full CSCS and each identified domain were shown to have strong Alpha values.  One-way between groups analysis of variance, was used to evaluate the relationship between scores on the full measure and a categorical safety behavior item.  Findings suggested that high scorers on the CSCS were safer workers than those with lower scores on the measure.  A post hoc analysis using Tukey&apos;s HSD showed that scores on the full CSCS, and the &quot;Behavior&quot; domain were significantly related to safety behavior.  The analysis of variance and the post hoc results indicated that a relationship exists between the CSCS and safety behavior.  This finding added to the validity of the measure.  The CSCS was shown to be a theoretically supported, valid and reliable measure that can be used to evaluate corporate safety culture.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Psychology--Business--Management--Confirmatory Factor Analysis--Corporate Culture--Exploratory Factor Analysis--Safety--Safety Culture--Transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>134</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63859</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63859</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Sherry, Patrick</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Fukami, Cynthia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Zhang, Duan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Chao, Ruth</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63818</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:31:30Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Disrupting the deficit discourse on historically Black colleges and universities: An organizational identity case study of Philander Smith College</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Davis, Shametrice Ledora</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Higher Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The federal Higher Education Act of 1965, as amended, defines a historically Black institution of higher education as &quot;any historically Black college or university that was established prior to 1964, whose principle mission was, and is, the education of Black Americans.&quot; Today, there are approximately 105 HBCUs, more than half private, the rest public, and a few two-year institutions (Allen, Jewell, Griffin, &amp; Wolf, 2007). While currently only 14 percent of Black college students attend HBCUs, 70 percent of all Black doctors and dentists, 50 percent of all Black engineers and public school teachers, and 35 percent of all Black attorneys received their bachelor&apos;s degrees at an HBCU (Avery, 2009). Despite these notable statistics, leaders associated with HBCUs have felt insecure about their future since the 1950s for a variety of issues; namely low enrollments, low endowments, loss of accreditation, and severe decreases in fiscal resources (Avery, 2009).However, missing from the discourse is a discussion of which HBCUs are currently staying ahead of the national and higher education economic crises by implementing effective leadership and financial management strategies. The academic literature fails to explicitly highlight HBCUs that are not only surviving in these times of economic difficulty, but actually thriving and remaining credible and supportive institutions in the respective community.In an effort to go against the trend of only highlighting the myriad financial and accreditation issues plaguing HBCUs, this doctoral dissertation study will illuminate the ways in which these institutions are efficiently addressing such problems, and typically doing so with less fiscal resources than other institutions of higher education (Gates, 2010). Philander Smith College has consistently been referenced in the journalistic literature as one HBCU that is successfully navigating historical and current problems stemming from a lack of fiscal resources. An organizational identity case study of this institution will shed light on the effective leadership and fiscal management strategies being executed by HBCUs in the 21st century. The findings of this study result in the construction of a model of best operational and leadership practices. It is the author&apos;s hope that both models will be adaptable and useful for other HBCUs.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Higher education--African American studies--Educational leadership--Black leadership--Education--Historically Black colleges--Leadership--Philander Smith--Social justice</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>337</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63818</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63818</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Patton, Lori</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cutforth, Nick</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Minor, James</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Chevillot, Frederique</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63842</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:32:56Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Establishing a Normative Profile on the MMPI-2 for Missionary Candidates</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dimos, Jonathan Keet</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Counseling Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The present study examined MMPI-2 data of 377 missionary candidates who presented for psychological assessment at Missionary Care Services. The purpose of the study was to establish a normative profile for missionary candidates to enhance interpretive validity and reduce missionary attrition. Mean T scores were established for the missionary candidate sample on the F, L, and K validity scales and the ten Clinical Scales. Analyses were conducted to compare the mean T scores of the missionary candidate sample to the mean T scores of the nonclinical normative population of persons taking the MMPI-2 for employment purposes. For both males and females, 10 of the 13 scales analyzed were significantly different from the nonclinical normative population. Results indicated that caution is suggested in interpreting the K scale. Further implications for increasing interpretive validity are discussed. Analyses were conducted to assess trends for MMPI-2 profiles of the missionary candidate sample over time. Results indicated that the mean T score on the K Scale for candidates tested between 1992 and 2002 was significantly higher than the mean T scores for candidates tested between 2003 and 2006 and candidates tested between 2007 and 2010. Analyses were conducted to assess trends by date of birth. Results indicated that the mean T score on the K Scale for Generation Y candidates was significantly lower than the mean T scores for Baby Boomer and Generation X candidates. Results also indicated that the mean T score on Scale 1 for Baby Boomer candidates was significantly higher than the mean T score for Generation Y candidates. Implications of analyses by date of testing and date of birth for the missionary candidate assessment process are discussed. Future research is needed to further enhance the quality of the missionary candidate assessment process.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Psychology--Candidate assessment--Missionary--Missions--MMPI-2--Psychological assessment</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>137</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63842</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63842</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>McRae, Cynthia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hasz, Monte</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gomez, Mary</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63123</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:34:34Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluating Violence and (Non)violence: A Critical, Practical Theology of Social Change</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Todd, Julie Marie</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Religious and Theological Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This dissertation uses a practical theological approach to evaluate Christian (non)violence in light of interviews with twelve scholars and activists in the United States about the means of social change and the relationship of those means to social location. Social location conditions an understanding of what violence is and how different groups justify and respond to various uses of violence and (non)violence within society and for social change. The project sets Christian (non)violent practice within the context of direct, structural and cultural violence, and implicates Christian tradition, theology and practice in each level of violence. The qualitative data exposes the rationalizing mechanisms of the dominant culture&apos;s violence: the denial of violence; the reversal of the perpetrators of violence, and; the entitlements of privileged social location. When Christian (non)violence emerges from a dominant social location and does not address these levels and mechanisms of violence, it functions ideologically to obscure the operation of political and economic power, maintains the violence and privilege of those in power, thereby undermining fundamental social transformation. Interviewee data also portrays a comprehensive constellation of effective practices of social change, be they violent or (non)violent, that destabilize the dominant trajectory of rationalizing violence. Emergent qualitative perspectives on questions and practices of organized violence and (non)violence point towards renewed Christian praxis for social transformation. The practical theological model offers an approach to social change which values: practices determined in the context of social struggle over theological abstractions; collective modes of action that undermine individualism; disruption over pacification; and self-critical, Christian solidarity that welcomes differences in belief regarding the justifiability of various means of social change.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Theology--Peace studies--Nonviolence--Oppression--Privilege--Social Change--Solidarity--Violence</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>345</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63123</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63123</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Turpin, Katherine</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gilbert, Alan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Alumkal, Antony</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63127</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:36:06Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>FIRE-DERIVED CHARCOAL ALONG AN ECOLOGICAL GRADIENT IN   THE COLORADO FRONT RANGE</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Licata, Christopher William</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Biological Sciences</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Terrestrial ecosystems are shaped by natural disturbances such as wildland fire. In the intermountain western United States, forests, shrub and grasslands adapt to repeated fires. An important long-term legacy of wildland fires is black C (BC) commonly referred to as char or charcoal. Black C is a recalcitrant C form that has been long known to influence soil physical, chemical, and biological processes that they vary across landscapes and over time. The objective of this research is to address two key areas in the emerging field of ecosystem BC research; 1) how much BC as charcoal C is formed per fire at a watershed scale and 2) how much charcoal C and total soil organic C are in mineral soil pools in the predominant Colorado Front Range vegetation types. For the former, we combined fire model results for fuel consumption with published charcoal conversion constants to create maps of predicted charcoal C per fire. These maps represent the first spatial estimates shown at a watershed scale. For the latter, we measured charcoal C pools in surface soils (0-10 cm) at mid-slope positions on east facing aspects in five continuous shrublands and forests from grassland to tundra. We found a significant statistical effect of vegetation type on soil charcoal C pools along this ecological gradient, but not a linear pattern of increasing charcoal C amounts with elevation gain. This study yielded the largest collection of soil samples analyzed for charcoal C in the United States. The geospatial data and thermo-chemical analysis methods developed here are an advance in the framework for evaluating the two critical phases in ecosystem black C cycling. Future modeling and field-based efforts are called for after revealing a landscape-pattern of SOC and charcoal C pools.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Ecology--Black carbon--Charcoal--Conifer forest--Fire--Fire regime--Rocky Mountains</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>130</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63127</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63127</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Sanford, Robert L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aplet, Greg</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sher, Anna</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Anderson, Sharolyn</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63331</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:38:14Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Fostering and Foreclosing Student Learning Potential: Portraits of Performativity, Emotion, and Relationality in the Classroom</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jacobs, Jeanne Marie</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Human Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This dissertation endeavors to build a much-needed bridge between the fields of communication and education.  Using critical pedagogy and critical communication pedagogy as theoretical frameworks, this project advances an understanding of classroom communication as constitutive of power relations, and teachers and students as agents who can work together to foster learning potential and social justice.   I look to interdisciplinary scholarship on affect to craft a nuanced conceptual framework of the connection between communication and emotion, and how they create learning opportunities for some students and construct barriers to learning for others.  Through ethnographic fieldwork at an urban magnet school, I explore the interactions between and among three teachers and their students over an entire academic year.  I present compelling portraits of each classroom that illuminate the impact of performativity, emotion, and relationality on students&apos; potential to learn.  I conclude by assessing how the circulation of teacher and student desires can lead to mutually empowering pedagogies.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Communication--Education--Pedagogy--Communication--Desire--Emotion--Learning potential--Performativity--Relationality</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>327</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63331</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63331</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Willink, Kate G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hao, Richie N.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wood, Roy V.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Uhrmacher, Bruce</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63816</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:40:21Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Gender Depiction in Preschool Books:  A Comparison Between Early Care and Education Classrooms in the United States and Norway</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Floyd, Cathrine Aasen</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Educational Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Preschool children&apos;s perceptions around gender identity and development can be influenced by their experiences.  With many children spending a portion of their day in child care, the environmental factors of these programs are important.  One aspect of the environment can impact preschool children is the books that are available to them.  For over 40 years, children&apos;s literature in the United States has been studied and found to be biased in their portrayal of males and females.  Males were more often found as main characters and depicted as capable leaders and thinkers.  Female characters were shown as weaker, often appearing in home settings and in traditional work roles.This study was conducted in Denver, Colorado and Oslo, Norway to compare the preschool literature between the two countries, since Norway has consistently ranked as one of the most gender equal countries in the world.  The question was whether the greater equality in Norwegian society would be reflected in the books that are read to its young children.The results of the study indicate that while both countries continue to need improvement on the proportion of male and female main characters, Norway had nearly three times the number of books that depict a male and female main character sharing the role of main character.  This could indicate a pattern of shared responsibilities between the sexes in Norwegian culture, as compared to the more patriarchal American society.   The United States had significantly more instances of fact books, such as letter and number recognition.The investigation of traditional role depiction of male and female characters showed additional significant differences between the two countries.  The United States literature depicted females in traditional roles more often and included lower instances of characters in non-traditional roles.  Norwegian books were most likely to depict characters in gender neutral roles.It does appear that the cultural norms of gender equity in Norway are reflected in the literature that is available to the children in their preschool programs and that American teachers may be able to learn how to more closely examine their own classroom libraries for bias.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education--Scandinavian studies--Women&apos;s studies--Books--Early education--Gender bias--Literature--Preschool--Young children</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>80</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63816</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63816</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Seidel, Kent</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hartnett-Edwards, Kimberly</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Maloney, Virginia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63822</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:41:58Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Group treatment for adult survivors of childhood sexual abuse: The relationship between social bonds and symptom severity</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lange, Robin Elena</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This study examined the session-to-session change in symptom severity and social bonding ability in the participants of groups for survivors of sexual trauma. The concept of social bonding ability was addressed by examining the participants&apos; beliefs about the availability of social support, their beliefs about themselves, and their beliefs about their relationships with their group leaders. Group leader ratings of the level of process focus of their group were also measured. Twenty women between the ages of 19 and 55 receiving group treatment at three community agencies in Colorado were included in the study. Groups included in the study were either open or closed, were targeted at sexual trauma survivors and met for a minimum of 10 weeks. Assessment measures utilized included the Outcome Questionnaire 45 (OQ-45), the PTSD Checklist-Civilian Version (PCL-C), The Interpersonal Support Evaluation List (ISEL) the Working Alliance Inventory-Short Form Revised (WAI-SR), the Childhood Sexual Abuse Questionnaire (CSAQ), and the Sexual Experiences Survey Short Form Victimization (SES-SFV). Participants completed the SES-SFV, CSAQ, ISEL, WAI-SR, PCL-C and the OQ-45 prior to treatment. Participants also completed the OQ-45, WAI, and ISEL prior to each group therapy session for sessions two to 10, for a total of 10 weeks of data. Data were analyzed with profile analyses, hierarchical multiple regression, and paired sample t-tests. Results showed that there were significant pre to post treatment changes on all measures of symptom severity and bonding ability after 10 sessions of treatment.  There were significant differences in symptom severity based on ability to form social bonds. However, after controlling for pretreatment symptom severity, level of bonding ability was not a significant predictor of post treatment symptom severity. There were no significant differences in the ability to form social bonds over time based on level of process focus of the group and all groups including some amount of focus on process increased the ability to form social bonds. Regardless of level of process focus, group treatments produced significant increases in the ability to bond to the therapist over time. There were no significant differences in bonding ability or symptom severity between participants in the open and closed groups, and both groups experienced similar rates of reduction in symptoms over time. Overall, these findings suggest that brief group treatment for sexual trauma survivors may improve social bonding ability and decrease ratings of symptom severity. Also significant for sexual trauma group psychotherapy research is the ability for women to benefit from either open or closed group treatments. Further research on a larger scale is needed to learn how level of group process focus affect group members and how social bonding ability develops in psychotherapy.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Psychology--Childhood Sexual Trauma--Group therapy--Profile Analysis--Psychotherapy outcome research--Social Bonds--Trauma</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>184</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63822</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63822</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Riva, Maria T.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McIntosh, Daniel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sherry, Patrick</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63813</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:43:45Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Homework Adherence in Cognitive-Behavioral Therapy for Adolescent Depression</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jungbluth, Nathaniel John</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2010</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Homework is a defining component of cognitive-behavioral therapy (CBT), however, few studies have examined homework adherence in youth CBT. Homework adherence was coded from audiotapes of school-based CBT for 50 depressed adolescents and evaluated as a predictor of proximal and distal treatment outcomes. Six therapist behaviors hypothesized to promote homework adherence were also coded from audiotapes of early sessions and examined in relation to subsequent homework adherence. Results showed no significant associations between client homework adherence and outcomes. Results also revealed several therapist behaviors to be associated with homework adherence in the context of planned moderator analyses. Adolescents considered at risk for non-adherence tended to show better adherence when therapists provided strong rationale for homework tasks, spent more time assigning homework in Session 1, and elicited client reactions and troubleshot obstacles in Session 2. Methodological and clinical implications are discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Clinical psychology--Adolescent depression--CBT--Homework--Therapist behavior--Treatment process</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>87</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63813</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63813</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Shirk, Stephen R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DePrince, Anne P.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wadsworth, Martha E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Reichardt, Charles S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63839</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:46:02Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>IMPLICATING BITZER&apos;S RHETORICAL SITUATION IN COMPARATIVE AND NON-VIOLENT RHETORIC: A RHETORICAL ANALYSIS OF THREE ECOFEMINIST MOVEMENTS FROM EAST TO WEST.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mat Nayan, Shahreen</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Human Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>In the study of social movement rhetoric, scholars often focus on movements based in Western nations, foregoing study of social change in Asia, Africa, the Middle East, and other parts of the world. Similarly, the focus on non-violent rhetoric has also been lacking, despite its use by great leaders such as Mahatma Ghandi and Martin Luther King. This dissertation contributes to the study of social change in a globalized world, by taking a comparative approach to non-violent rhetoric in three diverse case studies. As sub-areas, both comparative rhetoric and non-violent rhetoric require further deliberation due to the numerous debates concerning their meanings and approaches. Comparative and non-violent rhetoric are significant areas of study because they encourage mutual understanding by striving for common ground among people of different cultures, faith traditions, and political opinion. In this dissertation, I will demonstrate how Western and non-Western forms of social movement rhetoric complement each other to enhance our understanding of comparative rhetoric. I turn to both Western and non-Western ecofeminists to examine how the women optimize non-violent rhetoric, and the ways in which their cultural statushelp advance and/or hinder their activism. I specifically turn to the Chipko movement in India, Wangari Maathai and the Green Belt Movement in Kenya, and Julia Butterfly Hill in the United States, for an in-depth understanding of non-violent rhetoric in direct action. I use rhetorical criticism and Bitzer&apos;s (1968) rhetorical situation, to analyze the exigency, audience, and constraints in the three case studies. I argue that Bitzer as a theoretical framework is broad enough to study a variety of cultures/situations; yet, it is sufficiently well-defined to allow for useful analysis. I also contend, non-violent rhetoric is a tactic and manifestation of a philosophy that aims to address exigencies, and amend the relationship of the adversary to an ally. Non-violent rhetoric does not only address the material conditions of a situation, but also incorporates the spiritual and/or religious as a mode of address. Including a spiritual/religious dimension in the study of social movements enhances our understanding of social movements beyond the instrumental.The case studies in this dissertation reveal that non-violent tactics are selected and practiced as they align with spiritual/moral/religious values. My analysis also demonstrates how non-violence is used in some cultures to counter irresponsible environmental practice in the name of &quot;development.&quot; Finally, I provide extended definitions for both comparative and non-violent rhetoric and suggestions for futureresearch.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Communication--Rhetoric--Comparative rhetoric--Ecofeminism--Non-violent rhetoric--Non-Western rhetoric--Social movements</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>167</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63839</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63839</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Foust, Christina R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Leon, Luis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wood, Roy V.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hicks, Darrin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63863</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:47:23Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>In Search of a Contextual Pastoral Theology for Dalits in India</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Petta, Johnson</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Religious and Theological Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Current approaches to the ministry of pastoral care and counseling in the South Indian context lack a serious grasp of the critical needs of survival, liberation and cultural identity of the Dalit Christian communities. Prevailing models of care that are individualistic and based on clerical hierarchy have failed to give adequate attention to the systemic, cultural and psychological dimensions of the contextual needs of the Dalit Christians and foster a shared understanding of their problems. The theological and cultural sources that inform the pastoral care practices are not indigenous to their context and therefore fail to provide a critical and constructive perspective on the needs that arise in the context of caste oppression.This study develops a communal contextual and intercultural approach to pastoral care and theology that is interdisciplinary in nature and informed by indigenous sources of knowledge, Dalit liberation theology as well as Latin American liberation psychology to respond to the contextual needs of the Dalit people. The communal contextual approach seeks to understand pastoral needs in their wider sociocultural and political contexts that include the realities of caste prejudice, patriarchy and sexism, among others. The communal contextual approach also expands the ministry of care from being the exclusive domain of the ordained clergy to include caring resources of the faith community, thereby affirming the collective subjectivity of the Dalit communities. The intercultural approach offers a framework not only for facilitating a healthy, constructive and respectful interaction with other cultures, but also for empowering marginal communities such as the Dalits. This approach encourages Dalits to resist the hegemonic nature of the dominant discourses while also affirming and privileging Dalit cultural perspectives and resources to build and strengthen Dalit cultural identity. As an intercultural approach, it pays particular attention to the power dynamics that come into play when two cultures interact. Dalit liberation theology provides the theological rationale and cornerstone for this communal contextual and intercultural approach to care. This theology is operationalized using strategies of intervention from narrative theory as conceptualized by Michael White and David Epston. This dissertation, written from a Dalit perspective, argues that this new model of pastoral care and theology creates new possibilities that theologically empower Dalits to not only to reimagine their `Dalitness&apos; by reclaiming their cultural heritage, but also to effectively address their critical issues of survival, liberation and developing a cultural identity.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Regional studies--Dalit--Dalit Psycholo--Pastoral Care--Pastoral counseling--Pastoral Theology</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>333</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63863</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63863</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Graham, Larry Kent</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ishimatsu, Ginnie</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Doehring, Carrie</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63357</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:49:57Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Interferometric, Astrometric, and Photometric studies of epsilon Aurigae: Seeing the disk around a distant star.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kloppenborg, Brian Keith</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Physics and Astronomy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Epsilon () Aurigae is a binary star system that has baffled astronomers for 170 years.  In 1821 it was first noticed that the star system had dimmed by nearly 50%.  After many decades of photometric monitoring, the 27.1 year period was finally established in 1903.  A few years later, in 1912, Henry Norris Russell published the first analytic methods for binary star analysis.  Later application of these formulae came to an interesting conclusion; the system was composed of two stars: the visible F-type supergiant, and an equally massive, but yet photometrically and spectroscopically invisible, companion.Several theories were advanced to explain this low-light to high-mass conundrum, eventually settling on the notion that the companion object is obscured from view by a disk of opaque material.  With this topic solved, the debate shifted the evolutionary state of the system.  Two scenarios became dominant: the system is either relativity young, and composed of a massive, 15 M&lt;sub&gt;o&lt;/sub&gt; (solar mass), F-type supergiant and a nearly equally massive main sequence companion inside of the disk; or a much older and significantly less massive, 4 M&lt;sub&gt;o&lt;/sub&gt;, F-type post-asymptotic giant branch object with a more massive, 6 M&lt;sub&gt;o&lt;/sub&gt;, companion surrounded by a debris disk.In this dissertation I disentangle the two evolutionary states by comparing the photometric behavior of the F-type star to known supergiant and post-asymptotic giant branch objects; and deriving a dynamical mass for the two components using astrometric, radial velocity, and interferometric data.  Along with this, I provide the first interferometric images during the eclipse which prove the 50% dimming is indeed caused by an opaque disk.The first chapter presents the reader with the status quo of  Aurigae research and the topics I wish to address in this dissertation.  Chapter two presents an analysis of nearly 30 years of photometry on the system, concluding the star periodically exhibits stable pulsation on 1/3 orbital timescales.  The next two chapters are complementary in many ways.  Chapter three presents the first interferometric images of  Aurigae during eclipse and models the star and eclipsing body in unprecedented detail.  Chapter four presents new combined astrometric and radial velocity orbital solutions using a myriad of historical data sources and modern analysis techniques.  Lastly in Chapter five I conclude that the system is in the high-mass evolutionary state and provide estimates of the system component masses and distance.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Astrophysics--Astronomy--Physics--Astrophysical disk--Eclipsing binary--Epsilon Aurigae--Interferometry--Orbital solution: radial velocity--Astrometry--Photometry</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>214</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63357</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>epsAur_OIFITS.zip</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63357</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Eaton, Gareth R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Stencel, Robert E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hoffman, Jennifer L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ueta, Toshiya</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63082</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T16:51:21Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Invisible Ink: An Analysis of Meaning Contained in Gender, Race, Performance, and Power Discourses</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Griggs, Susan Annette</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Higher Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The number of females in senior level leadership positions in higher education is substantially fewer than males. Yet female students in these same institutions represent over half the population (National Center for Educational Statistics, 2010). The leadership gender gap is a phenomenon that has undergone numerous studies in search of reasons and solutions. Yet the gap remains. One cause of the underrepresentation of women in higher education leadership is ideological views regarding gender and leadership that result in stereotypes regarding who qualifies for leadership, what leadership behaviors are deemed best, who exhibits those behaviors, and what happens when those stereotypes are disrupted (Eagly &amp; Karau, 2002).In higher education leadership classrooms, students read and discuss texts on leadership theory. The leadership texts used in leadership courses in higher education programs produce discourses which influence the way students view women in leadership and the way women view themselves as leaders (Basow, 2004). Additionally, the discourses create relationships of power that serve to maintain the status quo and support male dominance (Wodak, 2001). These forces contribute to the leadership gender gap by creating relationships between the discursive message and the students, reinforcing the social issue of female under-representation.This study uses a feminist discourse analysis method to analyze four discourses in a commonly used leadership course text. By examining the discourses of gender, race, performance, and power, I locate the messages that work to sustain the power, control, and male dominance in senior level leadership positions in higher education and within the leadership classroom.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Higher education administration--Critical Discourse Analysis--Gender--Leadership--Performance--Power--Race</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>208</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63082</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63082</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Agans, Lyndsay</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Linder, Christina</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Tuitt, Frank</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62953</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T17:38:02Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Just a Mutt: A Narrative Ethnography of the Denver Dog Park Master Plan Process</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Griffin, Stephen M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Human Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This ethnographic study explores the phenomenon of citizen participation in the decision-making process of their local government.  The researcher explored this topic by observing the Dog Park Master Plan process conducted by the Parks and Recreation Department of the City and County of Denver from June 2009 through April 2011.The researcher attended and observed seven meetings of a citizens committee convened by the Denver Parks and Recreation Department to act as a mini-public to test the elements of the Dog Park Master Plan before presenting the Plan to the public, and the three public meetings held to allow the public at large to comment on the Plan.  The researcher conducted interviews with citizens and city staff involved in the process.  The researcher collected and analyzed textual artifacts generated in the process or related to it.  Using these data sources the researcher constructed a narrative ethnography describing the Dog Park Master Plan process.In the chapter on the academic literature, the research explores the literature on democracy, public participation, and having voice in decision making, and uses it to explain what occurred in the process.  The researcher concentrates on the practical applications of the ideals of democracy and public participation, and democratic participation as envisioned in the concept of having voice put forth by Cheney et al (1998) and Senecah (2004).  The researcher also explores as part of having voice in decision-making the principles of representation arising from culture and communication (Alcoff, 1991) and political theory (Young, 2000), as well as procedural justice (Tyler &amp; Blader, 2000).From his observations the researcher has concluded that the Dog Park Master Plan process unfolded as a process in which the Denver Parks and Recreation Department saw themselves as the experts on the matter, and so, conducted the process in such a way that the participation of the citizen committee and the public at large was to a large extent ignored.  As would be predicted by the literature on public participation and procedural justice, this led to dissatisfaction with the process by the participants in it.  The dissatisfaction with the process led a powerful interest group to intervene in the approval and adoption process on the Plan through opaque methods (Harnik, 2000) to short circuit the process and prevent many of the Plan elements coming out of the process being included in the final Plan.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Communication--Decison-making--Democracy--Ethnography--Local government--Public participation</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>314</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62953</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62953</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Wood, Roy V.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Foust, Christina F.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>East, Jean F.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Suter, Elizabeth A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63156</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T17:39:55Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Leading Schools Through a Generational Lens: Perceptions of Principals&apos; Change Leadership Disaggregated by Principal Generation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kuhn, Matthew Scott</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Educational Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The purpose of this descriptive quantitative study was to investigate possible differences in school leadership within a change process, as perceived by teachers. Grouped by generation, this study investigated principals&apos; perceptions of change order and that of their teachers, as well as how their teachers perceived their principal&apos;s leadership capacity when leading 1st and 2nd order change. This was done by analyzing data from Mid-continent for Education and Learning&apos;s Balanced Leadership Profile. McREL surveyed principals about the order of school change initiatives and their capacity to lead change. McREL also surveyed teachers about the 1st and 2nd order change leadership of their principals according to 21 leadership responsibilities.The first part of this study first looked at the differences between what principals estimated the order of change to be for their school improvement initiatives and what the teachers personally thought the order of the change was for themselves. The second part of this study looked at the perceptions teachers had of their principals&apos; leadership when their principals were leading 1st or 2nd order change for principals overall and for five generational cohorts of principals.Using t-tests for significant differences, results were summarized into five major findings: 1. a significant gap seems to exist between how principals judged the order of change they were leading and how teachers perceived the same change; 2. the top and bottom five ranked leadership responsibilities were similar for all generational groups; 3. principals tended to self-rate their leadership capacity higher than average compared to their teachers&apos; ratings, especially under 2nd order change conditions; 4. teachers seemed to rate the leadership capacity of Gen-X principals lower than average under 1st order change conditions. Conversely, teachers seemed to rate the leadership capacity of their Gen-X principals higher than average under 2nd order change conditions; and 5. teachers seemed to rate the leadership capacity of Generation Jones principals higher than average under 1st order, and lower than average under 2nd order, change conditions.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Educational leadership--Demography--Sociology--Change--Cohort--Education--Generation--Leadership--School</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>261</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63156</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63156</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Korach, Susan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Connolly, Daniel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Seidel, Kent</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Davis, Anthony</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62928</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T17:44:01Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>LEVELING THE FIELD IS NOT ENOUGH: PROMOTING CULTURALLY RESPONSIVE PEDAGOGY IN TEACH FOR AMERICA THROUGH THE EVALUATION OF INTERCULTURAL COMPETENCE, COLORBLINDNESS, WHITE RACIAL IDENTITY ATTITUDES, AND THE BELIEF THAT CULTURE MATTERS IN EDUCATION</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kim, Amber Kay</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Curriculum and Instruction</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This research study examined constructs and beliefs essential to culturally responsive teachers for the purpose of understanding corps members&apos; needs and promoting culturally responsive pedagogy (CRP) in the Colorado region of Teach for America (TFA).  This study employed a transformative, sequential mixed methods design with a theoretical lens of CRP and a corresponding framework for preparing culturally responsive educators described by Villegas and Lucas (2002).  First, a quantitative phase assessed participants&apos; levels of intercultural competence, colorblind racial attitudes, and White racial identity attitudes at two times--upon entering TFA (n = 139) and after one year of teaching and training (n = 78).  The quantitative data were used to describe corps members and to determine change over time.   Next, a qualitative phase employed stratified sampling with replacement based on Time 2 levels of intercultural competence as measured by the IDI (Hammer, 2009).   A total of seven corps members were grouped into three levels of intercultural competence--low (n = 3), mid (n = 3), and high (n = 1)--and were individually interviewed about beliefs regarding the role of culture in teaching and learning.  The qualitative data were analyzed for emerging beliefs within groups and themes across groups.  The qualitative data added richness to the quantitative profiles and furthered the understanding of corps members&apos; needs.Results of this mixed methods research study indicated that TFA&apos;s current program, selection, and training processes may result in colorblind corps members who minimize cultural differences, including the strengths and experiences of students of color, and negate the importance of CRP.  Because Colorado TFA is seeking to adopt a culturally responsive approach, Colorado TFA must intentionally and explicitly shift: (1) its outcomes for students; (2) its desired teacher actions; (3) its professional development and training.  Educational theory on CRP and preparing culturally responsive educators suggests that the development of intercultural competence, color-consciousness and White racial identity will produce culturally responsive educators and will ultimately result in positive and transformational outcomes for students.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Multicultural education--Teacher education--Pedagogy--Colorblindness--Cultural competence--Culturally responsive pedagogy--Racial Identity--Teach for America--Transformative</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>167</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62928</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62928</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Salazar, Maria</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cutforth, Nicholas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Puma, Jini</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62994</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T17:46:08Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Maintaining or Disrupting Inequality: Diversity Statements in the University</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Merkl, Linda A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Higher Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The purpose of my study was to identify whether university Diversity Statements aid in maintaining or disrupting inequality in the university. Using critical discourse analysis, I analyzed an initial sample of eleven Diversity Statements to develop a list of common themes found within the diversity statements. Using a maximum variation method, I then reduced my sample to four universities to provide breadth of information for the final study (Miles &amp; Huberman, 1994). In my case analysis, I first conducted an individual analysis of each of the four Diversity Statements using the common themes from my critical case analysis, common functions of the Diversity Statement, and potential limitations from my review of the literature (Doolittle, Horner, Bradley, Sugai, &amp; Vincent, 2007; King &amp; Cleland, 1978; Meacham &amp; Gaff, 2006; Sevier, 2003). Next, for each of the universities I then compared the Mission Statement to the Diversity Statement, analyzed common university statistics, and evaluated website pictures. Last, I conducted a cross-case analysis to identify patterns and considered the implications of those patterns in my findings.My analysis evidenced similarities across cases and provided insight to be applied in developing a framework for writing a Diversity Statement. Conclusions from my study suggest the Diversity Statement has the potential to be a powerful tool in disrupting inequality in the university. However, limiting factors decrease this ability. The recommendations suggest careful attention in preparing to write a Diversity Statement, appropriate content, and full dissemination of the Diversity Statement can increase the ability of the Diversity Statement to disrupt inequality in the university.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Higher education--Diversity--Diversity statements--Inclusivity--Mission statements</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>258</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62994</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62994</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Agans, Lyndsay</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hegeman, Diane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Tuitt, Frank</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Uhrmacher, Bruce</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63819</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T17:48:10Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>MAPPING THE CONCEPTUAL TERRAIN OF WORK CALLING:Exploring the intersections of meaningful work, spiritual communication, and organizational rhetoric </dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Molloy, K. Arianna</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Human Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Communication researchers have much to gain and contribute by paying sustained attention to the implications, contributions, and consequences of the interpretation and (re)production of work as a calling. While work calling has been theoretically and quantitatively conceptualized in a number of disciplines, it remains lacking in evidence of how the lived experiences and sensemaking discourses of participants serve to (re)construct this concept. Thus, the current study is qualitatively guided by asking, how people from different professional domains communicate about their experiences of work as a calling. To begin, I assess the overarching themes related to work calling in the areas of organizational psychology, sociology, theology, and business. Second, I suggest that interweaving meaningful work, spiritual communication, and organizational rhetoric creates rich academic space for the study of work calling as a communicative concept. Third, using thematic analysis, I identify participant communication about work calling from twenty-nine interviews, informal observations, and artifact analysis. Three dominant themes emerged: (a) definitional markers, (b) inherent interaction, and (c) significant costs. The theme of definitional markers provides a conceptualizing basis for work calling, the theme of inherent interaction relates to the enactment of work calling, and the theme of significant costs describe potential consequences of this approach. From such discourse, work calling is revealed as a complex, constitutive, and contested term, providing promising avenues of research.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Communication--Calling--Meaningful Work--Organizational Communication--Organizational Rhetoric--Qualitative--Spiritual Communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>267</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63819</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63819</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Foust, Christina R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McRae, Cythia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lair, Daniel J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Willink, Kate G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_65296</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T17:49:52Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Matching Educational Interventions to Behavioral Phenotypes:  Spatial Temporal Math as a Mathematics Achievement Intervention for Students with Autism Spectrum Disorders</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Grell, Erin Slason</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Child, Family &amp; School Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Autism Spectrum Disorders (ASDs), a rapidly growing group of neurodevelopmental disorders, affect nearly all aspects of development. The knowledge base of ASDs has increased significantly over the past half century due to translational research models (Rutter, 1999). Basic science and applied clinical work have informed research in a bi-directional manner. Through these models, much is now known about the language, behavioral, and cognitive difficulties associated with ASDs. However, autism research would benefit from further delineation of the differences between ASD types through the development of behavioral phenotypes. Behavioral phenotypes are expressions of particular aspects of disorders that may aid in further differentiation of subtypes of disorders (Hoddapp &amp; Dykens, 1997).In particular, little is known about math achievement and math interventions for students with ASDs. Despite federal mandates (IDEIA, 2004; NCLB, 2001) that strive to ensure that students with disabilities are held to the same high academic standards as other students, the research base on math interventions for students with ASDs is inadequate (Minshew, Sweeny, Bauman, &amp; Webb, 2005). ST Math, a computerized, pictorially-based math intervention contains many features that support the strengths of students with ASDs.To better understand the effect ST Math might have on the math achievement of students with ASDs, 10 students from a private school in Denver, Colorado participated in the ST Math program over the course of one school year. Individual behavioral phenotypes were developed for these students, based on information obtained from Individual Education Plans (IEPs). A combination of comparative and single-case analyses approaches were used to examine the effectiveness of ST Math for students with ASDs. As a whole, students performed better on post-ST Math assessments, compared to pre-ST Math assessments. Three students completed ST Math consistently and regularly, allowing for the use of Concomitant Time Series Analysis to examine the temporal dynamics between time on task and percentage of items answered correctly. Two of the three students showed significant, positive relationships between time on task and percentage of items answered correctly. Commonalities in the behavioral phenotypes of students who successfully participated in ST Math are compared to the behavioral phenotypes of students who did not. Implications for current practice and future research are discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Special education--Educational psychology--Mathematics education--Autism Spectrum Disorders--Behavioral phenotypes--Computer-assisted instruction--Math intervention--Time series analysis--Translational research</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>149</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:65296</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:65296</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Riley, Karen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Epstein, Rachel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Whitehouse, Shayna B.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Meyer, Laura</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type> 
 <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63823</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T17:52:28Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Micro channel cooler performance improvement by insonation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Higgins, Peter Webb</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The motivation for this work is the need to remove waste heat from laser diodes and high speed transistors in processes which are exponentially increasing past 1 kW/cm2 as anticipated by Moore&apos;s Law. The hypothesis guiding the work is that ultrasonic insonation of micro coolers employed to dissipate these heat loads can improve heat removal. It is thought that the mechanism promoting the benefit is enhancement of the ability of the coolant to remove latent heat in two-phase operation by managing entrained bubble size near the cooler&apos;s exit so as to forestall flow reduction or blockage caused by large bubbles, wedges and slugs accumulating there. Insonation experiments to prove the hypothesis have been done on several micro channel coolers in the range 4-80 kHz to quantify improvement in heat flux removal. In order to understand how insonation would produce benefit in heat removal, a research effort was undertaken to study the affect of 5-30 Pa acoustic fields on air bubbles rising in small aquariums. This involved developing a Faraday cage shielded acoustic probe, along with a force-beam calibration tool, for measuring field levels near a strongly electromagnetic-radiating ultrasonic source. Experiments were conducted on columns of pseudo monodisperse, sub-millimeter diameter air bubbles in water, and other fluids using bubble generators optimized for this purpose. A numerical analysis model based on energy balance of the acoustic work done on a bubble resulted in predicting mass transfer flux, and in quantifying bubble shrinkage and growth when irradiated on either side of its resonance. The model, and experiments show that bubble populations can be predictably altered by ultrasound. The research was concluded by identifying and quantifying micro channel cooler performance change when insonated in the range 4-80 kHz. It was discovered that 28 and 58 kHz radiation of exchangers having hydraulic diameters spanning 0.02 to 0.6 mm could produce heat flux removal improvements of 5 W/cm2 in devices normally removing less than 30 W/cm2, a factor of 17%. Peak thermal resistance improvement approaching 60 % has been observed.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Mechanical engineering--Heat transfer improvement--Microchannel coolers--Ultrasonic nsonation</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>162</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63823</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63823</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Danielson, Phillip B.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lengsfeld, Corinne S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gordon, Matthew</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wilson, James C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cobb, Wes</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63273</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T17:55:18Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nonprofit Marketing Education in the United States: An Examination and Interpretation of the Prevalance and Nature of Curricula</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Conley, Theresa Meier</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Curriculum and Instruction</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The nonprofit sector is a large, growing, and essential part of the United States economy. There is a history of inspired ideas and complex change in the nonprofit sector that marketing educators and business school administrators must understand if they are to be leaders in the continuing evolution of nonprofit marketing education.This manuscript includes a summarized historical perspective, a selective review of literature from existing nonprofit management and marketing education, a discussion of relevant contemporary issues for consideration, and mixed-method research results regarding the prevalence and nature of nonprofit marketing education. The mixed-method research strategy includes three phases; the first is quantitative, followed by two qualitative phases.The research results reveal four distinct themes that contribute new information to the practice of nonprofit marketing education: 1) undergraduate and graduate programs have similar curricula, but should be different so each is focused and delivered based on their respective experiences and outlooks while complementing business school realities; 2) the general tone of curricula elements and project work is often altruistic, and as a consequence is not effective in preparing undergraduate and graduate students to meet the marketing challenges unique to the nonprofit sector; 3) certificate programs in nonprofit marketing are few and represent a unique and untapped area of opportunity for business schools to leverage existing resources and provide a needed service for existing nonprofit employees with little or no marketing education; and 4) the lack of uniform and clear terminology related to or associated with nonprofit marketing hampers the ability of faculty members to reach educational objectives on behalf of their students.This manuscript concludes with discussion, interpretations, and recommendations to guide and further evolve curricula for nonprofit marketing education in the United States.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Higher education--Curriculum development--Marketing--Cause marketing--Curriculum development--Higher education--Nonprofit education--Nonprofit marketing--Nonprofit sector</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>221</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63273</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63273</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Uhrmacher, P. Bruce</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Uhrmacher, Bruce</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Patti, Chuck</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Maloney, Virginia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63862</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T17:57:03Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>PEAK-TO-AVERAGE-POWER-RATIO (PAPR) REDUCTION TECHNIQUES FOR ORTHOGONAL-FREQUENCY-DIVISION- MULTIPLEXING (OFDM) TRANSMISSION</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alhasson, Bader</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Wireless communication has experienced an incredible growth in the last decade. Two decades ago,the number of mobile subscribers was less than 1% of the world&apos;spopulation. As of 2011, the number of mobile subscribers has increased tremendously to 79.86% of the world&apos;s population.Robust and high-rate data transmission in mobile environments faces severe problemsdue to the time-variant channel conditions, multipath fading and shadow fading. Fading is the main limitation on wireless communication channels. Frequency selective interference and fading, such as multipath fading, is a bandwidth bottleneck in the &quot;last mile&quot; whichruns from the access point to the user. The &quot;last mile&quot; problemin wireless communication networks is caused by the environment of free space channels through which the signal propagates. Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiplexing (OFDM)is a promising modulation and multiplexing technique due to its robustness against multipath fading. Nevertheless, OFDM suffers from high Peak-to-Average- Power-Ratio (PAPR), which results in a complex OFDM signal. In this research, reduction of PAPR considering the out-of-band radiation and the regeneration of the time-domain signalpeaks caused by filtering has been studied and is presented. Our PAPR reduction was30% of the Discrete Fourier Transform (DFT) with Interleaved Frequency Division Multiple Access (IFDMA) utilizing Quadrature Phase Shift Keying (QPSK) and varying the roll-off factor. We show that pulse shaping does not affect the PAPR of Localized Frequency Division Multiple Access (LFDMA) as much as it affects the PAPR of IFDMA. Therefore, IFDMA has an important trade-off relationship between excess bandwidth and PAPR performance, since excess bandwidth increases as the roll-off factor increases.In addition, we studied a low complexity clipping scheme, applicable to IFDMA uplink and OFDM downlink systems for PAPR reduction. We show that the performance of the PAPRof the Interleaved-FDMA scheme is better than traditional OFDMA for the uplinktransmission system. Our reduction of PAPR is 53% when IFDMA is used instead ofOFDMA in the uplink direction. Furthermore, we also examined an important trade-off relationship between clipping distortion and quantization noise when the clipping schemeis used for OFDM downlink systems. Our results show a significant reduction in the PAPR and the out-of-band radiation caused by clipping for OFDM downlink transmission system.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Engineering--Electrical engineering--Interleaved Frequency Division Multiple Access (IFDMA)--Localized Frequency Division Multiple Access (LFDMA)--Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiplexing (OFDM)--Peak-to-Average- Power-Ratio (PAPR)</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>131</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63862</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63862</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Matin, Mohammad A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Bo-Yi, Yun</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DeLyser, Ron</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gao, David</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62959</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T17:58:38Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Performed and perceived masculinity in father-son relationships from the perspective of sons: A thematic narrative analysis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Strasser, Daniel Steven</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Human Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The current study qualitatively explored father-son relationships and the perceptions and performances of masculinity within that relationship from the perspective of sons. Through the utilization of symbolic interactionism and narrative as theoretical and conceptual frameworks narratives were collected as a means to make sense of participants&apos; experiences and interactions with their fathers throughout their lives. Through a multi-phase analysis and utilizing Riessman&apos;s (2008) thematic narrative analysis as an ideological and practical basis, RQ1, which asked what themes underlie sons&apos; narratives surrounding the performance and perceptions of masculinity within their father-son relationships, yielded the following three themes: (1) traditional masculinity; (2) responsibility; and (3) non-traditional masculinity. From RQ2 which asked what themes underlie sons&apos; narratives surrounding the construction of sons&apos; identities, roles and relationships within father-son relationships, the following three themes emerged: (1) perceptions of father(ing); (2) sons&apos; perceptions of self; and (3) turning point perspectives. RQ3 which asked what themes underlie sons&apos; narratives surrounding father-son contextual differences/similarities offer insight into both the performance and perception of masculinity and father-son relationships, resulted in four main themes: (1) history/family; (2) romantic/interpersonal relationships; (3) culture; and (4) sex and gender. Lastly, RQ4 which asked which themes stemming from sons&apos; dialogue and performances within the context of interviews offer insight into their narratives surrounding father-son relationships and masculinity gained further comprehension in to specific thematic dialogic and performative instances within participant responses. From these results this study added insight and understanding conceptually, ideologically, theoretically, and methodologically into the areas of family communication, gender communication and masculinity studies. Finally, the current study contributes further pragmatic understanding for individuals inside and outside father-son relationships when negotiating identities, roles and relationships regarding masculinity.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Communication--Gender studies--Father-son Relationships--Masculinity--Narrative Analysis--Perception--Sons&apos; Perspective--Symbolic Interactionism</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>259</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62959</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62959</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Suter, Elizabeth A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Erin K.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hanna, Michele D.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Morr Serewicz, Mary Claire</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63861</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:00:29Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>PHOTOELECTROCHEMICAL WATER SPLITTING FOR HYDROGEN PRODUCTION WITH METAL OXIDE (HEMATITE AND CUPRIC OXIDE) BASED PHOTOCATALYSTS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tang, Houwen</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Solar hydrogen is one ideal energy source to replace fossil fuel, as it is sustainable and environmentally friendly. Solar hydrogen can be generated in a number of ways. Photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting is one of the most promising methods for solar-to-chemical energy conversion. In this research project, metal oxide-based photocatalysts, especially hematite (&lt;em&gt;f&lt;/em&gt;-Fe2O3) and cupric oxide (CuO), were investigated for use as electrodes in PEC water splitting for solar hydrogen production.In our research project of hematite-based electrodes, we started with the incorporation of transition metal, particularly titanium (Ti), in hematite thin films to modify the valence and conduction band edges of hematite. We found that Ti impurities improve the electron conductivity of hematite and consequently lead to significantly enhanced photocurrents. We further investigated the Ti and Mg co-alloyed hematite. In this case, Ti is the donor and Mg is the acceptor in hematite. The co-alloying approach enhanced the solubility of Mg and Ti, which led to reduced electron effective mass and therefore increased electron mobility. Also, co-alloying tunes the carrier density and therefore allows the optimization of electrical conductivity. The densities of charged defects were found to be reduced, and therefore carrier recombinations were reduced. As a result, the Ti and Mg co-alloyed hematite thin films exhibited much improved performance in PEC water splitting as compared to pure hematite thin films.For the study of cupric oxide-based electrodes, we first investigated the possibility of reducing the electrode corrosion of cupric oxide in aqueous solutions by incorporating Ti as an electrode corrosion inhibitor. We found that Ti alloying can enhance the stability of cupric oxide in base solutions at the cost of reducing its crystallinity and optical absorption, and consequently lowering its photon-to-electron conversion efficiency. In order to balance the stability and the generated photocurrent, we developed a two-layer structure in which a thin layer of Cu-Ti-O was deposited on bare CuO thin film as a protective layer. Our experimental results indicated that this two-layer structure has an ideal thickness for the protection layer and is suitable for high-performance and long-term application for PEC water splitting.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Electrical engineering--Energy--Hydrogen production--Metal oxide--PEC--Photocatalyst--Water splitting</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>104</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63861</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63861</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Yi, Yun Bo</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Matin, Mohammad A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Zhang, Jun</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Yan, Yanfa</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gao, David</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_65270</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:02:30Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>PLACES OF PURPOSE, PURPOSEFUL PLACES: AN EXPLORATION OF THE PHYSICAL ENVIRONMENT OF PRIMARY LEVEL CLASSROOMS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jones, Shannon Britton</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Curriculum and Instruction</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The physical environment of the classroom impacts teachers and students. In many settings teachers are given some autonomy but little guidance in the establishment of the physical environment of the classroom.  Relatively few studies examine issues related to the totality of the physical environment of the classroom. This study is intended to provide a bridge between multiple disciplines and classroom application by describing and interpreting the intentions and decision making process of three teachers in the establishment of the physical environment of their classrooms.The five questions that guided this study focused on intentions of the teacher related to the physical environment, her/his philosophical and pedagogical beliefs, if the intentions were realized (or not) within the practice; impact of physical environment on teaching practice and the significance of examining the relationship between the physical environment of the classroom and the teacher&apos;s values and intentions.The methodology utilized for this study is Educational Connoisseurship and Criticism. This investigation provides detailed descriptions and interpretation of the experiences of three classroom teachers in vastly different school sites. Data collection includes multiple observations, interviews and artifact review.Several key findings emerged: 1) Teacher intentions for the physical environment to of the classroom were influenced by personal experiences and educational beliefs, 2) There is a symbiotic relationship between the physical environment of the classroom and the other dimensions of the classroom including curriculum offerings, instructional strategies and pedagogical techniques, classroom structure and organizational systems 3) Architectural elements exerted force over several of Eisner&apos;s dimensions of school including teacher intentions, and 4) the teacher&apos;s view of the flexibility of the space impacted both intention and use of the physical environment.This study has a variety of implications within the field of education as well as across disciplines. Implications from this study impact teacher education programs, practicing school administrators and planners, the school reform movement as schools with specific philosophies seek to create environments which support their mission and cross-disciplinary issues related to building design and planning, school furnishing design, lighting and color theory, and environmental hazard and impact.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education--Teacher education--Elementary education--Architecture of elementary classrooms--Classroom design--Elementary classroom environment--Elementary classroom spaces--Inspired classroom environments--Physical environment of classroom</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>298</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:65270</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:65270</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Uhrmacher, P. Bruce</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McRae, Cynthia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Russell, Nicole M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sampson, Nancy S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63009</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:06:14Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Posthumanist Rhetorical Agency</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dunn, Matt</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Human Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The postmodern criticism of humanist agency initiated by Dilip Gaonkar nearly twenty years ago set in motion a discipline wide discussion concerning the conceptualization rhetorical agency. Rhetorical agency is difficult but vital to conceptualize because the term bears directly on the discipline&apos;s theorizing about the speaker or rhetor, the effect of the speaker or rhetor&apos;s rhetoric on an audience, and the extent to which the speaker or rhetor&apos;s agency is constrained by ideology and discourse. What emerged from this discussion about agency did distance the discipline from the humanist conceptualization of rhetorical agency that persisted at the time Gaonkar published his argument, but conceptualizing rhetorical agency remains an evolving endeavor. The postmodern critique created two interrelated problems for the conceptualization of rhetorical agency in the discipline. The first concerns the role of discourse in the formation of rhetorical agency; the second concerns the impact ideology has on the formation of rhetorical agency. The response to the critique often assumes postmodern philosophy maintains the subject or agent is determined by discourse, and second, that the philosophy suggests ideology is virtually totalizing for subjectivity. I believe no postmodern author actually maintains either of these positions. The conceptualization of rhetorical agency which emerges in the recuperative effort predicated upon these two phantom criticisms results in the rehabilitation of the humanist paradigm Gaonkar&apos;s criticism suggests we reject. I argue we need not rehabilitate those aspects of agency postmodernism calls into question, but rather should direct our attention to the conceptualization of rhetorical agencies that Gaonkar presumes exist in discourse practices. Lacan&apos;s theory of discourse corrects for these errors because it assumes there are four discrete manifestations of rhetorical agency in discourse. The psychoanalytic terminology Lacan provides compliments the study of rhetoric not only because rhetoric was central to Lacan&apos;s thinking, but also because his theory provides a model for isolating and explaining rhetorical agency in discourse practices.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Communication--Desire--Four discourses--Lacan--Rhetorical agency</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>236</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63009</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63009</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Lair, Dan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Dobyns, Ann</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Calafell, Bernadette</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hicks, Darrin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63851</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:17:12Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>QUANTIFYING AND FORECASTING VULNERABILITY TO DYADIC CONFLICT IN AN INTEGRATED ASSESSMENT MODEL:  MODELING INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS THEORY</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moyer, Jonathan David</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The character of state interaction matters. This dissertation quantifies this interaction from 1960-2001 and then forecasts it from 2010-2050. I contribute to the field of International Relations by improving traditional measures of Realism and Liberalism, quantifying new perspectives sensitive to cultural interaction, and statistically evaluating these indices relative to the occurrence of conflict. It is the first step in an academic research agenda that desires to expand the scope of possibility regarding the modeling of International Relations theory for the purpose of theory evaluation and policy analysis.This dissertation spans two fields of study that do not typically overlap:  International Relations and Integrated Assessment Modeling. I begin by laying a broad foundation to bridge this chasm. I do this by first exploring knowledge constraints associated with forecasting. This leads to an overview of my conceptual and empirical tool for calibrating my final model: the historic occurrence of international conflict. Next, I introduce conceptual and applied systems theory, which leads to an overview of the International Futures (IFs) model.I then explore Liberalism and Realism as they have been traditionally operationalized at the macro-level.  A newly quantified variable--referred to as the Cultures of Interaction Index-- is introduced that builds on Liberal notions and tries to explain some aspect of intersubjective norms and values operating in a dyad. I perform statistical analysis on these indices and show that using IR theories in conjunction explains more of the historic occurrence of conflict--and thus the character of state interaction--than using any theoretical tradition in isolation. I then endogenize Liberalism and Realism in IFs and use the cultural measure as an exogenous constant. I am interested in whether the stock of culture in a dyad and growth in Liberal notions of interdependence can off-set negative pressures arising from Realism.Most dyads improve their character of interaction to 2050, but some become more conflictual, including China - US and China - India. The analysis is extended by looking at long-term structural shifts in the global system:  depleted fossil fuel reserves, stressed fresh water availability and tension from domestic instability. I conclude by offering a series of next steps that builds upon this work and recommendations for policy planners concerned with the future of interstate relations.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>International relations--Forecasting IR--Measuring IR--Quantifying IR</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>345</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63851</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63851</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Hughes, Barry B.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sisk, Tim</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Donnelly, Jack</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63213</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:18:45Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Reconciling Eros and Agape: The English Catholic Artistic Response to Reforms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Coonradt, Nicole M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>English</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This study explores the English Catholic artistic response to reforms--reforms being both internal and external to the Catholic Church--as part of the Catholic Reformation. &quot;Response,&quot; for the purposes of this project, may be defined in terms of an &quot;answer&quot; in an ongoing dialogue about the Catholic position and may be seen as both conciliatory and apologetic in nature. Understanding this response is useful when we consider the role of rhetoric and poetry in society and the attendant contemporary theories thereof, in their historical context, especially the duty of the poet. The recent &quot;revisionist&quot; history is central to understanding art contextually. While identifying the key doctrinal debates between Catholics and Protestants, this study traces these elements in the English Catholic art of Edmund Campion, Robert Southwell, and William Byrd and focuses, especially, on the way art attempts to reconcile man&apos;s human and divine natures, or Eros and Agape. This can enrich our understanding of the degree to which the spiritual may be found in the temporal to represent how important the concept of the soul and its believed afterlife was to Renaissance artists and their audiences particularly during a time of sustained religious unrest, censorship, and persecution. From the Catholic perspective, a significant recurring trope is the Blessed Sacrament in the then-forbidden rite of the Catholic Mass and its meritorious powers: to impart grace--even when simply gazed upon; to unify members of the Church as Christ&apos;s Earthly Body and Bride; to nourish the soul; and, ultimately, to secure the salvation necessary for eternal life. As rhetoric, poetry, and drama are the fruits of education central to the Ignatian charism of &quot;helping souls,&quot; the Jesuit influence on Byrd and other lay figures among the Catholic recusant community such as Sir Thomas Tresham and Sir John Harington may be detected in music, buildings, and verse. This project endeavors to broaden the critical base for additional studies concerned with reforms in sixteenth- and seventeenth-century England to enrich our understanding of artistic work in this period, most pointedly in terms of reconciling Eros and Agape.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Literature--Religion--Edmund Campion--English Jesuits--Reformation--Renaissance Poetics--Robert Southwell--William Byrd</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>218</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63213</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63213</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Bensel-Meyers, Linda</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Warlick, M. E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McNees, Eleanor</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Davis, Clark</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62936</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:20:19Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Relationship between Employee Involvement Management Practices and Burnout Among Military Mental Health Providers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fernandez, Raymond</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Counseling Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This study will investigate the relationship between EmployeeInvolvement Management Practices, Burnout, and work-related consequences of Burnout. The sample for this study was drawn from a population of Military Mental Health Providers in the United States Navy. Based on research information about work stress, direct service work, and the costs of interpersonal work, there is a strong potential for Burnout to occur among individuals working in such a setting.  Burnout has been shown to lead to negative organizational consequences such as increased employee turnover, reduced organizational commitment, reduced job satisfaction, emotional exhaustion, and cynicism, all of which canresult in reduced consistency and quality of care for patients. Employee Involvement Management Practices have shown a potential for moderating Burnout related issues such as organizational commitment, job satisfaction, and reduced turnover in other work settings. This study will assess subjects&apos;perception of Employee Involvement Management Practices at their work site, and will assess Burnout, Turnover Intentions, Organizational Commitment, and Job Satisfaction.  The author&apos;s hypothesis is that where Employee Involvement Management Practices are perceived, subjects will report lower scores of Burnout, lower Turnover Intentions, higher Organizational Climate, higher Organizational Commitment and higher Job Satisfaction. The Emotional Exhaustion section of the Maslach Burnout Inventory and Interview was used to assess Burnout. The Work Environment Scale Clarity and Control scales assessed attitudes about organizational climate. The Organizational Commitment Questionnaire was used to assess organizational commitment.  Two questions drawn from the Organizational Commitment Questionnaire were used to assess respondents&apos; Turnover Intentions. The Employee Involvement Practices Scale was used to assess perceptions of Employee Involvement Management Practices at the respondents&apos; work site. The Job In General Index was used to assess respondents&apos; ratings of job satisfaction.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Psychology--Burnout--Employee Involvement--Job Satisfaction</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>123</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62936</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62936</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sherry, Patrick</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Uhrmacher, Bruce</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Zhang, Duan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McRae, Cynthia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_65297</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:22:01Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Responses to Domestic Violence Public Service Ads: Memory, Attitudes, Affect, and Individual Differences</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Welton-Mitchell, Courtney Elizabeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Public service ads (PSAs) are an increasingly visible part of efforts to decrease the occurrence and consequences of domestic violence. Like other advertising, domestic violence PSAs are designed to grab attention, influence attitudes, and enhance memory for ad content. Over the years, images in domestic violence PSAs have changed substantially; agencies have started using pictures that generate emotions - either vivid negative images (bruised faces or body parts), or positive images (smiling faces) that contrast with the negative text. It is not clear, however, how different types of ad images influence memory for the message and attitudes about domestic violence, and what role affect may play in such responses. Moreover, the extent to which individual differences (trauma history, posttraumatic distress - PTSD symptoms) influence outcomes is not known. In three studies with undergraduate and community samples, using methods ranging from psychophysiology to self-report, the impact of images on attitudes and memory for ad content are investigated, also considering affect and individual differences. Results indicate graphic negative images enhanced memory for ad content, are rated as more persuasive, and are more likely to compel the viewer to act. Affective responses to ads also differed based on image type, and in some cases, partially mediated the relationship between ads and outcomes. Trends in the data suggest further study of the role of individual differences (trauma history, PTSD symptoms) is needed. This research provides information specifically relevant to the design of domestic violence public service campaigns and broadly relevant to understanding the role of emotional responses and individual differences on outcomes associated with public service ads.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Psychology--Cognitive psychology--Social psychology--Affect--Attitudes--Domestic violence--Memory--Public service ads--Trauma</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>112</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:65297</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:65297</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>DePrince, Anne P.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McIntosh, Daniel N.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Riva, Maria T.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Potts, George R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62941</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:25:35Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Rewriting the Future: The Construction of Masculine Subjectivity within Articulations of Russia&apos;s Post-Soviet National Idea</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nowakowski, Arianna L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This dissertation evaluates the construction, negotiation, and contestation of masculine Subjectivity within articulations of Russia&apos;s post-Soviet national Idea. As Russia endeavors to define itself after years of turmoil and strife, gender identities have become deeply enmeshed in understandings of quintessential Russianness. From discourses of the state under Vladimir Putin to those of the Russian Orthodox Church, actors with significant social and political power have constructed particular understandings of what it means to be Russian, and in so doing, have delineated the parameters of normal, or natural gender identities and sexualities for men.Drawing from the ideas of Michel Foucault, Jacques Lacan, Slavoj Zizek, and others, I analyze the ways in which male corporeality is articulated as an embodiment of the nation, and point to the consequences of articulations that serve to &quot;naturalize&quot; or &quot;normalize&quot; certain masculinities over others. Many of the discourses under consideration have constructed a gendered conceptualization of Russia&apos;s national Idea by mythologizing nostalgic signifiers of the past and orienting them toward a future ideal in a way that finalizes the meanings of such signifiers and makes them appear to be eternal and authentically Russian. Combined, such discourses constitute a national Idea that serves to monologize conceptions of masculinity, reducing them to an artificial essentialism. Yet perhaps most importantly, this work demonstrates the constructed and unfinalizable nature of imposed identities--and the ability, through creative discursive mechanisms such as literature and film, to push back against the establishment and resist the centripetal forces of &quot;traditional&quot; modernity.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>International relations--Gender studies--Russian history--Discourse--Gender--Lacan--Masculinity--Performativity--Russia</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>230</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62941</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62941</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Adelman, Jonathan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Donnelly, Jack</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Beaudoin, Luc</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_65271</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:30:42Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Searching for Truth(iness): Mapping the Religio-Political Landscape and Identity of Christian Emerging Adults through a Reception Study of &lt;italic&gt;The Colbert Report&lt;/italic&gt;</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dierberg, Jill Elizabeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Religious and Theological Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Utilizing textual analysis and in-depth interviews of self-identified Christian participants ages 18-35 (n=20), this dissertation explores the way Comedy Central&apos;s &lt;italic&gt;The Colbert Report&lt;/italic&gt; portrays Christianity, how young Christian viewers negotiate their religio-political identity in relation to the show, and what this negotiation says about the religio-political landscape of Christian emerging adults (19-29) (Arnett, 2004) in the United States. I conclude that &lt;italic&gt;The Colbert Report&lt;/italic&gt; provides a contextual occasion for critical religio-political reflection, and that Christian emerging adults of myriad Christian subcultures negotiate their religio-political identity in relation to &lt;italic&gt;The Colbert Report&lt;/italic&gt; to varying degrees as they select differing reference points within the show as a means of shaping and strengthening previous and ongoing identity markers.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Religion--Sociology--Colbert--Emerging adults--Identity</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>241</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:65271</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:65271</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Schofield Clark, Lynn</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Waldman, Diane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Alumkal, Antony</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62932</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:32:52Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Structural Polymorphism in Tau Filaments: An Implication for Neurodegenerative Diseases</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Siddiqua, Ayisha</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Chemistry and Biochemistry</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Tau filaments are the pathological hallmark of &gt;20 neurodegenerative diseases including Alzheimer&apos;s disease, Pick&apos;s disease, and progressive supranuclear palsy. In the adult human brain, six isoforms of tau are expressed that differ by presence or absence of the second of the four semiconserved repeats. As a consequence, half of the tau isoforms have three repeats (3R tau), whereas the other half has four repeats (4R tau).Site-directed spin labeling of recombinant tau in conjunction with electron paramagnetic resonance spectroscopy was used to obtain structural insights into tau filaments. The studies showed that the filaments of 4R tau and 3R tau share a highly ordered core structure in the third repeat with parallel, in-register arrangement of beta-strands. This structure in 3R and 4R is conserved regardless of whether full-length isoforms (htau40 and htau23) or truncated constructs (K18 and K19) are used. When mixed, 3R tau and 4R tau coassembled into heterogeneous filaments. Hence, these findings indicate that there are at least three compositionally distinct types of filaments: homogeneous 3R tau, homogeneous 4R tau, and heterogeneous 3R/4R tau.In vitro experiments show that the seeded filament growth, a prerequisite for tau spreading in tissue culture and brain, is crucially dependent on the isoform composition of individual seeds. Seeds of 3R tau and 3R/4R tau recruit both types of isoforms whereas seeds of 4R tau can recruit 4R tau, but not 3R tau, establishing an asymmetric barrier. Conformational templating of 4R tau onto 3R tau seeds eliminates this barrier, giving rise to a new type of tau filament.Conformational studies at the molecular level of tau filaments were done using Double electron-electron resonance spectroscopy, which allows the determination of distances between pairs of spin labels. These studies revealed structural differences between filaments of 3R tau and 4R tau. Furthermore, they indicated that 4R tau assumed the conformation of 3R tau when templated on 3R tau seeds. Our measurements have also provided insights into the heterogeneity of tau filament structure.Conformational differences due to variation in filament composition and seeding properties of tau filaments have shown that they are structurally polymorphic in nature. This structural polymorphism of tau filaments has widespread implications in understanding and treatment of neurodegenerative diseases.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Chemistry--Biochemistry--Biophysics--Aggregation kinetics--Conformational study of filaments--Double Electron-Electron Resonance (DEER)--Electron Paramagnetic Resonance (EPR)--Neurodegenerative diseases--Tau</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>150</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62932</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62932</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Margittai, Martin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pegan, Scott</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Eaton, Sandra</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Miller, Keith</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Angleson, Joseph</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63847</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:34:58Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Student School Engagement as a Potential Predictor of High School Completion</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Albanes, Jennifer</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Child, Family &amp; School Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>There is a dropout epidemic in the United States. In the US, 25% of high school students do not graduate on time. For Latinos, the number is worse, with only 64% graduating from high school. Current research is clear that 9th grade is a critical year for keeping students in school. Students that earn all their credits for their core classes in 9th grade are more likely to graduate than students who fail one or more class during their freshman year. Prior to this study, engagement has been connected to dropout in the literature, but with differing ideas of how to measure engagement. The Student School Engagement Measure (SSEM) could be one tool used to estimate levels of engagement and identify students at risk of dropping out. This study used structural equation modeling to identify whether 8th grade SSEM scores were a significant predictor of credits earned by the end of 9th grade. The results of this study indicated that 8th grade SSEM scores were not a significant predictor of credits earned at the end of 9th grade, supporting previous research has found that engagement changes from year to year. These findings suggest that measuring engagement over the course of a single year, instead of using the SSEM as a long term predictor, might be a more useful use of the SSEM.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Psychology</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>93</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63847</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63847</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Hazel, Cynthia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Walls, Eugene</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Zhang, Duan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Dittrick Nathan, Karin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63860</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:36:44Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Thank you, dear: Examining the association between gratitude and relationship well-being</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ragan, Erica Pearse</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The current study replicated and extended existing research on gratitude by examining the ways in which gratitude is related to both individual and relationship well-being. A total of 387 participants completed the pre assessment and were randomized into the study, with 251 participants completing the full study (i.e., pre, post, and follow-up assessments). Participants were randomly assigned to list relationship-focused gratitudes, amusing events, or general events that happened during their day for 14 days. The differential impact of the three interventions on both individual and relationship variables was investigated.  The relationship-focused and general events conditions experienced decreased negative affect from the pre to post assessment compared to the amusement condition. There were no other group differences. Participants across conditions experienced increases in life satisfaction, gratitude, and relationship confidence, as well as decreases in negative interaction. There also appeared to be short-term decreases in positive affect and positive connection for participants in all conditions. Changes in gratitude were associated with increases in relationship well-being. Additionally, cross-sectional analyses indicated that gratitude was associated with both individual and relationship well-being. Possible explanations for the lack of group differences as well as implications for future research are discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Psychology--Clinical psychology--Couples--Gratitude--Positive Psychology--Romantic Relationship--Well-being</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>122</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63860</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63860</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Markman, Howard J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Smith-Acuna, Shelly</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Stanley, Scott M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Shirk, Stephen R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McIntosh, Daniel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63866</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:38:32Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>&quot;That&apos;s what families do&quot;: Rewards and challenges of informal kinship care</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hay, Betsy Anne</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Social Work</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Informal kinship caregivers take on the responsibility of raising a relative&apos;s children in situations where those children cannot remain with their parents and are not in the custody of child welfare. The phenomenon is increasing, however it is difficult to obtain information from these families because of the difficulty locating them. As a result, there is limited research on this specific group of kinship care families. The purpose of this study was exploratory, using qualitative methods to gather information from informal kinship caregivers about their experiences caring for a relative&apos;s children with a focus on the rewards and challenges within those experiences. A second purpose was to enable participants to tell their stories so that information could be used by practitioners and policymakers. The 14 participants in this study described a path to informal kinship care that began with precipitating events that resulted in the children&apos;s not being able to live with their parents, followed by the decision to provide care, and then the quest to obtain legal custody of them. The caregivers next began a journey through the experiences of being informal kinship caregivers, which included both rewards and challenges. Four themes emerged to characterize those rewards and challenges: experiences with family, experiences with systems, financial experiences, and emotional experiences. Participants provided recommendations for both practitioners and policymakers, which included requests for more recognition and respect as well as more emotional, social, legal, and financial support. Despite all the difficulties, none of the participants regretted their decision to care for their relative&apos;s children.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Social work--Informal kinship care--Kinship care</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>183</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63866</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63866</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>East, Jean F.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Smith-Acuna, Shelly</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Parker, Lynn</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ohman, Kathleen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63830</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:42:01Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The R Factor: Centering Race in the Mentoring of African American College Students</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Coble, Bridgette</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Higher Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Mentoring provides personal support, academic assistance and career guidance to college students of color whose experiences have been documented to be very different from those of their White counterparts. Achievement inequity, problems of persistence, experiences of racism and student reports of feeling marginalized and misunderstood threaten the ability of students of color to succeed in college. While it may be assumed that race plays a central role in the mentoring relationships of students of color, this assumption may be misguided.  The existence of formal mentoring programs and informal mentoring relationships that support students of color does not necessarily ensure that the confounded issue of race is appropriately embedded as a shaping force in the mentor/mentee association. This paper will deconstruct the assumption that approaches to the mentoring of students of color automatically consider race by applying Critical Race Theory as a theoretical framework to examine if and how race is present in the relationship between mentors and their African American student mentees at predominantly White institutions of higher education. Using phenomenological research design, this study brings race out of the rhetoric of higher education and places it in the center of examination to uncover student perceptions of race and how it operates within the mentoring relationship to help us better understand how we ensure high quality mentoring can be actively applied in our efforts to support the success of college students of color.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Higher education--African American--Mentoring--Race</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>393</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63830</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63830</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Tuitt, Franklin A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Jones, Art</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Valdez, Jesse</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Patton, Lori</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63825</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:43:43Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN MIDDLE SCHOOL STUDENTS&apos; PERCEPTIONS OF PHYSICAL ACTIVITY, STUDENT ENGAGEMENT, AND ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENT</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moretti, Jeremy D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Child, Family &amp; School Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Physical activity is important, and many adolescents are not meeting the recommendation that youth participate in at least 60 minutes of physical activity most days of the week (CDC, 2011). Physical inactivity among middle school students is on the rise and may be a contributing factor to a decline in academic performance. Prior research has focused  primarily on bodily health; however, growing evidence supports the benefits of physical activity for academic achievement (Chomitz et al., 2009). This  study  examined the relationship between middle school students&apos; perceptions of physical activity and student engagement they relate to academic achievement among 179 middle school students in one suburban middle school. Additionally, this study sought to investigate  students&apos; perceptions of physical activity as well as the context within which these perceptions take place, which may lead to more effective strategies to help improve academic achievement. Propositions from Bronfenbrenner&apos;s ecological theory were used to examine the different factors influencing the relationship between middle school students&apos; perceptions of physical activity and student engagement as they relate to academic achievement.This study is predominantly a correlational and regression design, which examines relationships and predictive ability of key variables. This research design will add depth to the study by investigating the social influences in schools regarding the relationship between physical activity, student engagement, and academic achievement</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education--Health education--Academic Achievement--Obesity--Physical Activity--Student Engagement</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>143</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63825</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63825</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Riley, Karen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ohman, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cutforth, Nicholas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63394</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:45:48Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN RISK AND RESILIENCE, RACIAL MICROAGGRESSION, ETHNIC IDENTITY, AND WELL-BEING IN YOUNG ADULTHOOD</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Forrest-Bank, Shandra Star</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Social Work</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Young adulthood is the developmental period characterized by the transition from adolescence to the roles and responsibilities of adulthood. While most young adults experience positive growth and accomplishments, many others struggle, especially those with disadvantaged childhoods who lack financial, social, and emotional resources. Substance abuse, crime, educational failure, unemployment, and mental health problems are common among young adults. Unfortunately, many of these problems occur at disproportionately high rates for young people of color. Considerable knowledge of the child and adolescent risk and protective factors that contribute to the onset of problem behavior or to well-being during adolescence has been developed. However, evidence from longitudinal studies spanning childhood, adolescence, and adulthood indicates that little is known about the influence of early risk and protective factors on the onset, remittance, or persistence of problem behavior or well-being during adulthood. In addition, few studies have examined the effects of racial discrimination and ethnic identity on problem behavior and well-being. This study examined the relationship between child and adolescent risk and protective factors for problem behavior, perceived racial and ethnic microaggression, ethnic identity, and the young adult outcomes of self-efficacy, substance abuse, and criminal intention. Data were collected from a randomly selected sample of college students (N=486; Mean Age=24) attending an urban college in Denver, Colorado. Findings from structural equation modeling revealed that the early onset of problem behavior was significantly related to both substance abuse and criminal intentions during young adulthood. Childhood school engagement was positively related to college self-efficacy, and negatively related to criminal intentions. Perceived racial microaggression and ethic identify were significantly related to academic self-efficacy. One-way analysis of variance tests revealed significant differences in mean scores on the microaggression and ethnic identity scales between racial and ethnic groups. All nonwhite groups reported significantly higher levels of microaggression than their white peers. Mean cognitive ethnic identity scores were significantly higher for black and Latino/Hispanic subjects compared to Asian and white participants. The implications of these findings for practice, policy, and research with young adult populations are identified.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Social work--Development--Discrimination--Ethnicity--Race--Risk and resilience--Self-efficacy</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>195</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63394</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63394</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Jenson, Jeffrey M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Brisson, Daniel S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Bender, Kimberly</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63183</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:47:45Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN TEACHER CULTURAL COMPETENCY AND STUDENT ENGAGEMENT</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Robinson, Erin Nicole</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Educational Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This exploratory study investigated teachers&apos; cultural competency and their students&apos; engagement within international high schools located in Hong Kong. Cultural competency is defined as a combination of knowledge about cultural groups as well as attitudes towards and skills for dealing with cultural diversity (Betancourt, 2003). The literature indicates that cultural competency will continue to play an increasingly important role in the professional work place as culturally diverse people become more interdependent. When examining the classroom experience, cultural competency equates to a teacher&apos;s ability to successfully instruct and engage culturally different students.The students in this study reported over 30 different nationalities. Many of these students were internationally mobile and lived outside of their home country for a significant portion of their lives. As Third Culture Kids, these students grew up between cultures and reflect our global society (Pollock &amp; Van Reken, 1999). In turn, the teachers in these international schools worked with a culturally diverse population of students. An unsubstantiated assumption follows that as educators increase their cultural competency, student engagement and achievement also increases.  Thus, this study sought to determine if a relationship exists between teachers&apos; cultural competency and their students&apos; engagement.The study involved 70 high school teachers and 520 high school students within two international schools in Hong Kong. Two survey instruments were used to measure teacher cultural competency and student engagement. The Multicultural Awareness Questionnaire (Culhane-Pera, et al., 1997) measures cultural competency along three subconstructs: knowledge, skills and attitude. The Student Engagement Survey (Skinner, 1991) measures a four factor model of engagement.  A quantitative analysis determined several salient findings. International school teacher perceptions of their cultural competency are primarily in an ethnorelative frame. The study also revealed that teacher self-reported cultural competency does not have a significant correlation with student engagement. However, students&apos; perceptions of their teacher&apos;s cultural competency does bear a strong positive relationship with student engagement.This study has ramifications for both educators and researchers. There are recommendations for instructional practice and school leadership. As a foundational study, additional research is required to further explore the impact of teachers&apos; cultural competency on student success.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education--Multicultural education--Cultural competency--Cultural proficiency--Intercultural sensitivity--International schools--Student engagement--Third Culture Kids</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>238</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63183</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63183</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Seidel, Kent</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hazel, Cynthia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Korach, Susan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salazar, Maria</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63864</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:51:14Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>THERMALLY ACTUATED RESONANT SILICON CRYSTAL NANOBALANCES</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hajjam, Arash</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Electrical Engineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>As the potential emerging technology for next generation integrated resonant sensors and frequency references as well as electronic filters, micro-electro-mechanical resonators have attracted a lot of attention over the past decade. As a result, a wide variety of high frequency micro/nanoscale electromechanical resonators have recently been presented. MEMS resonators, as low-cost highly integrated and ultra-sensitive mass sensors, can potentially provide new opportunities and unprecedented capabilities in the area of mass sensing. Such devices can provide orders of magnitude higher mass sensitivity and resolution compared to Film Bulk Acoustic resonators (FBAR) or the conventional quartz and Surface Acoustic Wave (SAW) resonators due to their much smaller sizes and can be batch-fabricated and utilized in highly integrated large arrays at a very low cost.In this research, comprehensive experimental studies on the performance and durability of thermally actuated micromechanical resonant sensors with frequencies up to tens of MHz have been performed. The suitability and robustness of the devices have been demonstrated for mass sensing applications related to air-borne particles and organic gases.In addition, due to the internal thermo-electro-mechanical interactions, the active resonators can turn some of the consumed electronic power back into the mechanical structure and compensate for the mechanical losses. Therefore, such resonators can provide self-sustained-oscillation without the need for any electronic circuitry. This unique property has been deployed to demonstrate a prototype self-sustained sensor for air-borne particle monitoring.I have managed to overcome one of the obstacles for MEMS resonators, which is their relatively poor temperature stability. This is a major drawback when compared with the conventional quartz crystals. A significant decrease of the large negative TCF for the resonators has been attained by doping the devices with a high concentration of phosphorous, resulting in even slightly positive TCF for some of the devices. This is also expected to improve the phase noise characteristics of oscillators implemented utilizing such frequency references by eliminating the sharp dependence to electronic noise in the resonator bias current.Finally it is well known that non-uniformities in fabrication of MEMS resonators lead to variations in their frequency. I have proposed both active (non-permanent) and permanent frequency modification to compensate for variations in frequency of the MEMS resonators.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Electrical engineering--Nanotechnology--Mechanical engineering--Mass Sensors--MEMS (Micro Electromechanical Systems)--Nano-Balances--NEMS (Nano Electromechanical Systems)--Oscillators--Resonators</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>145</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63864</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63864</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Pourkamali, Siavash</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Matin, Mohammad</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wilson, James C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lengsfeld, Corinne</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63268</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:55:06Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>TRANSFORMATIVE PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT THROUGH THE EYES OF JACK MEZIROW AND THOMAS GUSKEY</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stahl, Leslie Diane</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Higher Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The key to improving education is the classroom teacher. Students must haveskillful, highly effective teachers who have consistent access to on going professionaldevelopment. NCLB offers guidelines for effective professional development. Statesinterpret these guidelines and add their own varied legislative requirements. The currentresult is an eclectic mix of ideas, methods, and approaches. This investigation exploredthe current professional development literature through the lens of Jack Mezirow&apos;stransformational theory of adult learning. Overlaid with theory wasThomas Guskey&apos;smodel of effective professional development which resulted in a tool for planning andevaluating ongoing teacher education. A survey crafted around Guskey&apos;s five levels ofprofessional development was given to 186 elementary classroom teachers in an innercity school district. Qualitative research methods were used to examine the district&apos;scurrent program effectiveness and to inform recommendations for improving its efficacyfor all stakeholders. This study confirmed professional development that valued ateacher&apos;s personal background, included their present teaching context and focused onreal time applications was considered effective by teachers and thus more likely to effectchange in their classroom pedagogy. Additionally, it was beneficial when professionaldevelopment included time for participants to both personally reflect on and to dialogwith other colleagues about their learning. This investigation has implications for thoseinvolved in the ongoing education of teachers at every level from inception to evaluation.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Higher education--Educational leadership</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>162</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63268</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63268</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Tuitt, Franklin A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salters, Roger</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Michalec, Paul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63850</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T18:58:25Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Trauma in Transportation: Factors Contributing to Positive and Negative Outcomes of Involvement in Trauma for Railroad Workers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pinarowicz, Jill Veronica</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Counseling Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This study explored several predictors of Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) and Post Traumatic Growth (PTG) in a sample of 136 train employees. The first objective was to examine the influence of number of work related traumas, number of life traumas, age, personality characteristic extroversion, personality characteristic openness, social support, positive cognitive coping, and negative cognitive coping in the prediction of PTSD. The second objective was to assess the influence of number of work related traumas, number of life traumas, age, personality characteristic extroversion, personality characteristic openness, social support, positive cognitive coping, and negative cognitive coping prediction of PTG.Freight train employees from a major transportation company in the United States participated in the study. There has not been a thorough exploration of negative and positive outcomes of trauma in the literature with this population. The study attempted to gain further understanding of PTSD and PTG in train employees by using simple linear regression analyses to investigate number of traumas in predicting PTSD and PTG. The study then utilized hierarchical regression analyses to investigate how number of work related traumas, number of life traumas, age, personality characteristic extroversion, personality characteristic openness, social support, positive cognitive coping, and negative cognitive coping were related to PTSD and then in a separate regression using the same variables to predict PTG.Results of this study indicated that number of work traumas predicted PTSD, although number of work traumas did not predict PTG. Also, factors in the hierarchical model that were significant predictors of PTSD were number of work traumas, number of life traumas, negative cognitive coping, and positive cognitive coping.  In the model predicting PTG, social support, negative cognitive coping, and positive cognitive coping were statistically significant. The field of PTG is relatively young in comparison to the study of more pathological trauma, PTSD. Previous research has indicated personality factors, social support, and cognitive processing to have theoretical bases in the emergence of growth, and can also serve as protective factors for negative trauma reactions.  This is the first study to look at PTG in train employees and to also apply personality characteristics, social support, and cognitive coping. The results of the study provide evidence that social support, negative cognitive coping, and positive cognitive coping are related to PTG. Further, results indicated that number of work traumas, number of life traumas, positive cognitive coping, and negative cognitive coping predicted PTSD.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Psychology--Counseling psychology--Cognitive coping--Post traumatic growth--Post traumatic stress disorder--Social support--Transportation--Trauma</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>178</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63850</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63850</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Sherry, Patrick</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ohman, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McRae, Cyndy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62898</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T19:00:49Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>When talking helps: A Quantitative study of privacy and resilience after bereavement</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>West, Carrie Lynn</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Human Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Using the theoretical framework of Communication Privacy Management, this study sought to determine how trait resilience, state hopefulness, distress disclosure, use of social networks, and boundary turbulence relate to bereaved spouses&apos; life satisfaction. Bereaved spouses (N=149) completed questionnaires at Camp Widow, a weekend-long conference for bereaved spouses held in San Diego, from August 12-14, 2011. Participants were single, engaged or remarried. The average age of the participants is 46.24 years. The average age at time of bereavement reported was 43.71 years. The amount of time that had passed since the death of their spouse was 2.83 years, and the average time participants reported being married was 17.7 years. The percentage of participants who reported having children at the time of their spouse&apos;s death was 83.67%. Only 6% of participants were remarried at the time of the study. The average annual income reported by participants was $67, 689. Finally, 93% of participants were white, 142 were female and 7 were male.  Using the data collected at Camp Widow, three structural equations models were evaluated for best fit to the data. Results indicate that trait resilience directly predicted state hopefulness, distress disclosure, and boundary turbulence, and that state hopefulness and boundary turbulence predicted life satisfaction. Resilience reported an indirect effect on life satisfaction. Results also indicate the model that best fit the data from the current study was the one in which the relationship between trait resilience and life satisfaction was mediated by state hopefulness, distress disclosure, use of social networks, and boundary turbulence. This study further supports the role of communication in the process of resilience. Possible avenues for further research are explored.Keywords: communication privacy management, bereaved, resilience, boundary turbulence, hope, social support</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Communication--Boundary Turbulence--Communication Privacy Management--Hope--Resilience--Social Support--Spousal bereavement</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>138</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62898</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62898</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Morr Serewicz, Mary Claire</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Botta, Rene</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Foust, Christina R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Erin K.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62910</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T19:02:50Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Whether a One-State Solution to the Palestinian-Israeli Conflict: A comparative Study of Settler-Colonial Domination Systems in South Africa and Palestine</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ayoub, Hasan Saleh</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The purpose of this dissertation is to answer the question: why do ostensibly similar ethno-national conflicts within a system of settler-colonial domination see such wide variation in their outcomes? How they emerge from conflict through power sharing and social integration versus the endurance of separation and systems of domination and control? The study identifies causal paths that resulted in the decline of domination systems of this type.Ethno-national conflicts that feature certain similarities develop in different trajectories due to certain conditions that culminate in transforming the structures of these conflicts towards integration (the establishment of a single political entity) or separation (independence in separate entities). The goal of the dissertation is to examine the Palestinian-Israeli conflict through a comparative lens in order to specify the conditions that led to the persistence of the two-state solution and to examine the prevalence or lack of necessary and sufficient conditions for the emergence of a one civic-democratic state.Building on the comparative approach I argue that ethno-national territorial underpinnings of the conflict and the &quot;regimes of territorial legitimation&quot; of the dominant group are the most crucial explanatory factor in determining the trajectory and outcome of the conflict. &quot;Regimes of territorial legitimation&quot; are the practices, procedures, systems of meaning, and institutional designs that found the relationship between a nation, people, or ethno-national group and geography/territory. The dissertation features a qualitative structured and focused comparison of the conflicts in South Africa, and Palestine. Method of difference is applied for a case-oriented interpretive inquiry that focuses on the complexity of each of the two cases and aims at capturing the historical diversity of these similar cases.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Comparative literature--International relations--Apartheid--Domination--Ethno-territorial--Nationa-territorial-nexus--One-state--Settler-colonialism</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>443</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62910</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62910</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Sisk, Timothy D.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Botta, Renee</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hashemi, Nader</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Giacaman, George</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_65268</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-02-27T19:04:34Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Withholding Political Authority: Civil Society and People&apos;s Power in Zimbabwe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>DuPree, A. Scott</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The relationship of civil society to the state is rarely antagonistic and at most times supportive. The political regime and civil society are taken to be interdependent social structures that interact through hegemonic, supportive and socially constructed dimensions. Given this interdependency, when does civil society challenge authority or does its efforts rise to the level of a people&apos;s power revolution? When does it act to dismantle the political regime or seek to reconstruct it? This project attempts to shed light on how civil society mobilizes a people&apos;s power capable of challenging political authority through the story of its ongoing struggles to pursue social objectives in Zimbabwe in the 1990s.Since 1980, the Zimbabwe African National Union (Zanu) controlled the only post-colonial government Zimbabwe has known. Drawing from its revolutionary credentials it set out to finish the interrupted war for Zimbabwean Independence. This objective resonated with civil society less and less over time as groups began to see Zanu&apos;s promises as hollow and its corruption and patronage systems as the primary obstacle in accomplishing their objectives. This development is explored through a grassroots empowerment movement, the Organisation of Rural Associations for Progress, the widespread protests in 1997 catalyzed by the Zimbabwean Congress of Trade Unions and the efforts to rebuild the constitutional order spearheaded by the National Constitutional Assembly.The story points to at least three civil society strategies to locate power within the people and counter political power: 1) constructing political alternatives within the existing regime, 2) mass withdrawal of support for the authority of the regime and 3) reconstruction of the social contract. Nevertheless, civil society did not succeed in dismantling the political regime, hampered by the continuing capacity of the state to exert hegemonic control, remove the pillars of civil society support and exploit polarized values within civil society.Despite the terrible destruction of social and economic fabric of the country by the political struggles of the 2000s, the ongoing development of democratic values and the diminishing importance of the interrupted revolution can provide a glimmer of hope for the future transformation of the country.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Political Science--International relations--African studies--Civil society--People&apos;s Power--Revolutions--Social Change--Social Justice--Zimbabwe</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>221</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:65268</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:65268</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Gilbert, Alan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Nanda, Ved</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Donnelly, Jack</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kuhn, Randall</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66609</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-05-06T21:00:36Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Cortisol in middle childhood : associations with genetic polymorphisms and early environmental risk</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pikovsky, Irena Y.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Watamura, Sarah E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pennington, Bruce</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Dmitrieva, Julia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:date>Aug. 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:type>thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:format>iv, 100 p. : ill.</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Early life stress is known to have an enduring impact on individuals health
trajectories, however, some show greater resiliency to early life stress than others. The
exploration of candidate genes and gene-environment interactions may be one promising
window on risk versus resilience trajectories. However, prior work involving three
polymorphisms (COMT Val158Met, MAOA-LPR, and 5-HTTLPR) has yielded well
publicized but inconsistently replicated associations with mental health. Part of this
inconsistency may be due to the limited exploration of mechanistic explanations for how
these gene-environment interactions lead to variations in health. Thus, this dissertation
examines gene-gene and gene-environment interactions in predicting basal cortisol at age
eight (assayed from a single blood sample). Data for this project comes from 813 families
participating in the Avon Longitudinal Study of Parents and Children (ALSPAC). Early environmental risk is characterized by three well-documented factors (maternal
depression, maternal stress exposure, and child stress exposure) compiled across the
developmentally salient 0-6 year age range. Contrary to expectation, genetic risk was not
related to childrens basal cortisol in middle childhood, and neither were the tested geneenvironment
interactions. Most measures of environmental risk were also unrelated to
childrens cortisol, however maternal stress exposure when the child was 48-61 months
old was related to higher basal cortisol. Analyses and discussion describe patterns of environmental risk exposure across early childhood in an effort to better characterize risk
trajectories in this sample. Although the current findings do not support HPA axis
dysregulation as a mechanism by which gene-environment interactions impact health,
methodological limitations likely contributed to these null findings. Future studies should
continue to explore such mechanistic explanations in order to create effective
interventions for children at high risk for stress related disease.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Copy is available with a DU login: https://digitaldu.coalliance.org/fedora/repository/codu:66609</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Hydrocortisone</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Genotype-environment interaction</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Developmental psychology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Genetic polymorphisms</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dissertations, Academic</dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66609</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>Access to this ETD is restricted to members of the DU community. Other users may submit an ILL request.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66609</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66602</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-05-06T21:05:26Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ice age child</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Burns, Logan</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Ramke, Bin, 1947-</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pessin, Sara</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Arts and Humanities</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:date></dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:type>thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:format>1 electronic resource (iii, 72 p.)</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>The creative section of my dissertation reflects the learning process. With specific interests in cognitive development and language learning, this collection of poems, titled Ice Age Child, serves as a mode of inquiry into the developing mind.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Copy is available with a DU login: https://digitaldu.coalliance.org/fedora/repository/codu:66602</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Religion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dissertations, Academic</dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66602</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>Access to this ETD is restricted to members of the DU community. Other users may submit an ILL request.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66602</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Sikelianos, Eleni</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Saterstrom, Selah, 1974-</dc:contributor>
  <dc:subject>Poetry</dc:subject>
  <dc:contributor>English</dc:contributor>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66603</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-05-06T21:09:22Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>From California, on</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Denrow, Jennifer</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Sikelianos, Eleni</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pap, Jennifer</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kiteley, Brian</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Arts and Humanities</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>English</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:date>May 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:type>thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:format>iii, 86 p.</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>This manuscript is an effort to determine the world and how we are to each other. It is also an effort to come into meaning. How imagination is part of that. The escape here has to do with the inability to make things meanit feels like if I try hard enough there can be a resolution via the imagination. But sometimes when we make things they overcome us. Its difficult to know the appropriate boundary for imaginationat what point it moves from an attempt to decipher the world into a construction of the reality of the world. I cant ever tell the difference but I continue to try. Some of what went into this manuscript has is the thinking about neuroscience (neurotheology). My interest in perceptions of reality and what can be obtained from a negotiation of those perceptions leads itself easily into research of the brain: What information is available to us though the technological investigation of brain and what can be determined from research regarding how consciousness is discussed physiologically. Much of the current research in the neuroscience community is occupied with the placement and location of consciousness and self. My own interest within these considerations is centered in the nature of self, place and imagination, and how the correspondence between these given fields of activity allow us to make decisions about what we understand as the world and ultimately how we determine it.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Copy is available with a DU login: https://digitaldu.coalliance.org/fedora/repository/codu:66603</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>American literature</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dissertations, Academic</dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66603</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>Access to this ETD is restricted to members of the DU community. Other users may submit an ILL request.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66603</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66604</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-05-06T21:12:16Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>P. sphinx teen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dickinson, Joan</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Hunt, Laird</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kiteley, Brian</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Chevillot, Frederique</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hunt, Laird</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Arts and Humanities</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>English</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:type>thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:format>v, 274 p. : ill.</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>P. sphinx teen is a novel and creative dissertation that can be classified as 
a descent narrative, or katabasis, employing various literary formspoems, short prose, essays, 
journal entries, interviews, and illustrations to tell one story: the death, from pneumonia, of 
my mothers 15-year-old sister. Within the narrative, suggestions of origins are made as a way to 
affix the idea of a descent through generations and time. However, those origins are quickly set 
aside allowing the story to branch like a treeitself the shape of a simultaneous katabatic and 
anabatic narrative.
The originating story took place in Detroit, Michigan between 1935 and 1939, and is framed by others: Sigmund Freuds collection of antiquities and its escape from Vienna in late 1938; the making of Charlotte Salomons opus Life? or Theatre?; Anais Nins simultaneous marriages; Walter Benjamins radio program called Enlightenment for Children. Motifs and characters are interchangeable passes for voices both distinct and indistinct. The author, at times, takes the form of an I lifting the life of her lineage to view and, with the suspicion of reincarnation, changing place with the main character, Patricia, who is, simultaneously, one and many. In researching the family story in relationship to historical events and figures associated with 
those events, I discovered an irregularity in record keeping that lead me to question whether my 
aunt had, in fact, died from pneumonia or something less natural.  Because the pertinent family 
members were dead, I turned, first, to a medical chart that my grandmother kept as she tended to 
her sick daughter constructing a series of horary astrological charts that were then interpreted by 
four paranormal industrialists with astonishing results.
P. sphinx teen attempts to manifest the lawless nature of grief as a thumbing of ones nose at 
those who would have it otherwise or who would make of mourning something compact and manageable. 
It is a book of many voices, ghost-driven, and made equally uncanny by human ineptitude, 
wickedness, and grace.







</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Copy is available with a DU login: https://digitaldu.coalliance.org/fedora/repository/codu:66604</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Ghost stories</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Grief</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Youth and death</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dissertations, Academic</dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66604</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>Access to this ETD is restricted to members of the DU community. Other users may submit an ILL request.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66604</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66605</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-05-06T21:16:23Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>My education</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gardiner, Christine</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Sikelianos, Eleni</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pap, Jennifer</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ramke, Bin, 1947-</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kiteley, Brian</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Arts and Humanities</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>English</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:date>August 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:type>thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:format>iv, 169 p.</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>My dissertation is entitled My Education. It is a poetic meditation on the nature
of knowledge. The manuscript is a triptych, each section of which corresponds to a
common source of knowledge.
The first chapter is a collection of poems entitled As Seen On TV. The poems
borrow conceptual metaphors and visual gestures from television programs in order to
investigate the values that produced them and norms that are produced by them. The
poems are concerned with mimesis: the troubled relationship between art and life.
Organized as a day spent in front the television, the book opens with the morning news,
and ends with late night reruns and static. These poems are about the passage of time, the
female body, and the violence of its rapid obsolescence.
The second chapter, Boy Friends, is an alphabetical primer on romance. The
alphabet contains the units of literacy, of knowledge. It is an organizational method. The
alphabet book is a didactic form; it teaches the order of things. In this work, the speaker
lists the men in her life alphabetically, describing her affairs and thwarted love interests,
beginning with Adam and ending with Zachary. The twenty-six lineated poems are
followed by a prose addendum entitled &quot;Roll Call,&quot; in which the speaker tries to list every
boy she ever met and explain what has become of him since she knew him. Many of the
names from Boy Friends recur here, and a sense of narrative develops and acts as a
bridge into the final chapter.
The third section, Confessional Poetry, is a collection of prose essays modeled
after the Roman Catholic Sacrament of Penance. In this work, I confess a sin to
correspond to each on the Ten Commandments. This numeric organization (1-10) mirrors
the alphabetical organization (A-Z) of Boyfriends. This is a work of spiritual
accounting. In it, I tally the wrongs I have done to see how it all adds up. Unfortunately I
am not very good at math. I do not know the final answer. I do know that each of these
stories is an act of contrition.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Copy is available with a DU login: https://digitaldu.coalliance.org/fedora/repository/codu:66604</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Penance, Poetry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>American poetry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Television programs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Interpersonal relations</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>University of Denver</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dissertations, Academic</dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66605</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>Access to this ETD is restricted to members of the DU community. Other users may submit an ILL request. </dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66605</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66608</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-05-06T21:31:23Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Exploring a debriefing intervention : a mixed methods study of a clinical staff intervention</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Matera, Dawn R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Ohman, Kathleen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Nicotera, Nicole</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Social Work</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:date>July 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:type>thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:format>viii, 168 p.</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>In the last twenty years, researchers, theorists, and clinicians have begun to identify the personal toll on clinicians who work with traumatized clients. Mental health professionals may experience disruptions in their cognitive schema due to their clinical experiences. Clinicians may also struggle with depression, cynicism, alienation from friends and colleagues and an array of psychological and physical symptoms. While researchers have begun to explore how vicarious trauma manifests with clinical staff, there remains a need to identify interventions that are effective in mitigating vicarious trauma, burnout, and intent to leave.
The purpose of this mixed methods study was to investigate the relationship between levels of debriefing interventions and vicarious trauma, burnout, and intent to leave. To that end, a convergent parallel mixed methods design was used to analyze quantitative and qualitative data. The convergent parallel design is a triangulation design where data were collected concurrently using quantitative and qualitative methods. The results of this study addressed whether the debrief intervention is a viable intervention associated with rates of vicarious trauma, intent to leave, and burnout for mental health clinicians who work with children and adolescents with histories of trauma.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Copy is available with a DU login: https://digitaldu.coalliance.org/fedora/repository/codu:66608</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Burnout</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Psychological debriefing</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Mental health personnel</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vicarious trauma</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dissertations, Academic</dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66608</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>Access to this ETD is restricted to members of the DU community. Other users may submit an ILL request.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66608</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66610</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-05-06T21:35:29Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The week</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ruocco, Joanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Kiteley, Brian</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Urquhart, Robert</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hunt, Laird</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ramke, Bin, 1947-</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Arts and Humanities</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>English</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:date>Nov. 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:type>thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:format>iv, 144 p.</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>THE WEEK is a collection of short stories. These stories engage the
politicized (if not overly political) question of what it means to be human and to be in
relation to other humans in the world. Some of the stories are quite compressed; I
attempt to create effects in these pieces through subtraction, ellipsis, parataxis, and
surprise. Other stories are more sustained, producing voices that address the reader
directly or voices that follow the involutions of a thought, dwelling on minute details
of consciousness; these pieces play with conventional short story elements (character,
plot, rising action, falling action, etc.), although they often fizzle or turn sharply to
unsettle reader expectation. I have found that it is very difficult to be human. That
being human is a problem is both the premise and the conclusion of this book.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Copy is available with a DU login:https://digitaldu.coalliance.org/fedora/repository/codu:66610</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>American literature</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fiction</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Short stories</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dissertations, Academic</dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66610</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>Access to this ETD is restricted to members of the DU community. Other users may submit an ILL request.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66610</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66611</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-05-06T21:38:52Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The effect of power and colonialism on religion and secularization : expanding Taylor&apos;s A secular age</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Yuhas, Stephanie</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Vial, Ted</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Clemmer-Smith, Richard</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Seeburger, Frank</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Religious &amp; Theological Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:date>Aug. 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:type>thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:format>iv, 274 p.</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Drawing on Charles Taylors historical analysis in A Secular Age, this dissertation
reveals connections between the process of Euro-Western secularization and its roots in
the universalizing project of Christianity. This work asserts that religion, a term often
identified with Christianity, developed in conjunction with secularization and concludes
that these theoretical constructs influenced international legal principles which
marginalized indigenous cultures that did not conform to its tenets. Not only did
Christianity and the secular arise from the same roots, but both were shaped by
colonialism.This paper provides a detailed overview of the development of international
law as a colonial project that combined theological and secular interpretations of natural
law and the law of nations creating a vehicle for land acquisition and resource extraction
by examining the writings of Francisco de Vitoria, Hugo Grotius and John Locke. In
order to trace the effects of flows of power from religious authority to state authority, this
paper examines the views of Michel Foucault and Talal Asad on power, agency, identity
and freedom through the lens of religion and the secular. This project focuses on the
Native American experience to demonstrate the interface between Christian missionizing,
the imposition of discipline and civilization and the current American legal system that
asserts a separation of church and state.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Copyright is available with a DU login: https://digitaldu.coalliance.org/fedora/repository/codu:66611</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Religion, History</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Secularization</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Freedom of religion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>International law</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject>Asad, Talal</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Taylor, Charles, 1931-</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Foucault, Michel, 1926-1984</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dissertations, Academic</dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66611</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>Access to this ETD is restricted to members of the DU community. Other users may submit an ILL request.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66611</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63365</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-07-02T19:17:19Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>AN EXPLORATION OF THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN MENTORING OF NEW TEACHERS AND STUDENT PERFORMANCE</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Shadwell, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Educational Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>While much research has explored the positive correlation between mentoring programs and resulting reduction in teacher attrition, the relationship between mentoring activities and student learning remains equivocal. The purpose of this study was to investigate the possible relationship between frequency and depth of mentoring activities in which high school teachers in their first three years of teaching report engaging, on the 2011Colorado TELL (Teaching, Empowering, Leading and Learning) Survey, and examining concurrent student achievement growth and shifts in growth gaps as measured by the Colorado Growth Model in those teachers&apos; schools. This mixed methods study also entailed open-ended interviews of five high school teachers in their first three years of teaching regarding their mentoring experiences. Responses were coded and themes were captured to add depth of understanding regarding the dynamics of mentoring of teachers and their students&apos; achievement. As 50% of teacher evaluation in Colorado will be anchored to student academic growth by 2014, the relationship between mentoring and student learning is especially salient for school districts implementing mentoring programs, as well as for teachers who are relying in part on mentoring to help them positively impact student learning.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Educational leadership--Educational administration--Academic growth--Closure of growth gap--Mixed methods study--Multilinear correlation--New teacher mentoring</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>110</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63365</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63365</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Seidel, Kent</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Bussey, Marian C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Brookhart, Linda</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Korach, Susan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62921</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-09-09T20:57:22Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Dragon Takes Flight: China&apos;s Journey toward Building its C-919 Large Passenger Aircraft and its Impact on the US and Boeing</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Levine, Derek Adam</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Despite the enormous risk associated with the development of a large indigenous airliner, China after a failed attempt in the mid-1980s, since 2003 has decided once again to embark on a journey toward the development of a 190 seat commercial airliner.  Nations are typically interested in the development of indigenous airliners because of the potential spillover effects that years of research and development have on the economy and the military. Equally important is that China no longer wants to relinquish its large commercial airplane market to foreign companies such as Boeing and Airbus with their market expected to constitute nearly 25% percent of the world&apos;s demand worth $340 billion.With the aviation industry naturally driven toward a natural monopoly, the Chinese government has agreed to not only subsidize the C919&apos;s development, removing the potential risk associated with launching a technologically advanced aircraft, but upon the aircraft&apos;s arrival, which is expected in 2016, but also guarantee sales of the plane by forcing its State-owned airlines to purchase it. This could potentially be harmful to current commercial aircraft producers Airbus and Boeing. If the three manufacturers: Boeing, Airbus and COMAC split the market in three ways, it will dig deep into the profits of all three manufacturers. This may force Boeing to contract the size of their work force, including skilled engineers and scientists, thus slowing down the process of innovation and product efficiency and the ability of the military and the economy reaping such benefits.This dissertation weaves the work of Peter&apos;s Evans&apos;s &quot;Embedded Autonomy and Michael Porter&apos;s &quot;Determinant Model&quot; to determine that given the current nature of the Chinese state, it possess an adequate level of embedded autonomy to implement favorable policy for constructing an internationally competitive airliner, which consists of both creating an innovative airliner and selling enough of them to develop scale economies.  A state&apos;s institutional configurations whether it possess a high level of autonomy, high level of embeddedness, or a balance between the two, influence the essential society variables in Porter&apos;s Determinant model for developing industry differently.Using a combination of primary source and secondary data from China, the United States and France, which include conducting interviews with key officials and experts in the aviation field from those countries, this research project compares and contrasts the institutional arrangements of China in the 1980&apos;s during its failed attempt at commercial aircraft development with today and concludes that different internal structures lead to different levels of effectiveness and success with respect to implementing policy choices favorable to the development of the commercial aviation industry.Secondly, this Dissertation looks at the potential implications the success of the C919 may have on the United States and Boeing and the ways in which Boeing might prepare to meeting the challenges it faces.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>International relations--Asian studies--Political Science--Airbus--Boeing--China--Industrial Policy--Institutions</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>373</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>Levine_denver_0061D_10556.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author. This object is subject to an open-ended embargo. Only the citation and abstract may be made available online. Permission to view the object must be granted by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62921</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Szyliowicz, Joseph S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gilbert, Alan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Laird, Frank</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66588</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-10-03T23:28:58Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Meta-analysis of Testing Accommodations for Students with Disabilities: Implications for High-stakes Testing</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Vanchu-Orosco, Michelle</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Martinussen, Monica</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cutforth, Nicholas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Olmos-Gallo, Antonio</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Bacon, Donald</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Test accommodations are designed to ensure the comparability of test scores between students and their typically developing counterparts by eliminating as much construct-irrelevant variance and construct-irrelevant difficulty as possible. Although those involved in test creation endeavor to create tests with suitable accommodations for students with disabilities, there is lack of consensus regarding accommodation efficacy. Using meta-analysis and meta-regression to summarize previous research, this study examined whether test accommodations differentially boost test scores of students with disabilities, and whether accommodated conditions provided a more effective and valid assessment of students with disabilities. Results from the meta-analysis of 34 studies (119 effect sizes) lend support to the differential boost hypotheses, whereby students with disabilities (mean effect size  = 0.30, k = 62, p &lt; 0.001) are positively impacted by test accommodations while their typically developing peers (mean effect size = 0.17, k = 57, p &lt; 0.001) gain little from test accommodations.Presentation assessment accommodations (mean effect size  = 0.22, k = 41, p &lt; 0.001) had a small statistically significant impact on the performance of students with disabilities, while use of timing/scheduling accommodations (mean effect size  = 0.47, k = 17, p &lt; 0.001) had a small, bordering on medium, statistically significant impact on these students. The effect for presentation accommodations intensified when narrowing the focus to students with learning disabilities (mean effect size  = 0.36, k = 23, p &lt; 0.001) but not for timing/scheduling accommodations (mean effect size  = 0.48, k = 13, p &lt; 0.001). Overall results for setting (k = 1) and response (k = 3) accommodations were not available as there were too few studies for an overall comparison.The results of meta-regression analyses examining the effects of assessment accommodations on test scores for students with disabilities showed that 42% of the heterogeneity in test score could be explained by an overall model examining population description, test characteristic, results dissemination, and researcher-manipulated (test accommodation effect size for students with disabilities) variables. Population description and test characteristic variable sets explained the greatest amounts of variability for mean increase in test score, R2=0.22 and R2 =0.35 respectively; researcher-manipulated variable (test accommodation) and research dissemination explained little variance, R2 =0.07 and R2 =0.01, respectively.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66588</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66588</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator></dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vanchu-Orosco, Michelle</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Riley, Karen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Research Methods and Statistics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Morgridge College of Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>xiii, 361 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Educational tests &amp; measurements</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>accomodations</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>differential boost</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>high-stakes test</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>meta-analysis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>meta-regression</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>students with disabilities</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66587</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-10-03T23:29:12Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Leading in Times of Change: Principals&apos; Perspectives of their Role in a New Pay-For-Performance System</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Ortiz-Torres, Amanda Lela</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Seidel, Kent</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The purpose of this qualitative study was to explore principals&apos; perspectives on how they make sense of their leadership roles in a new pay-for-performance system. The study describes the perceptions of six principals, two each from elementary, middle, and high school levels, regarding leadership in a recently changed system. Principals were asked about their leadership roles in implementing a pay-for-performance system, and responses focused on leadership styles, actions, beliefs, preparation, and experience of leading in a time of change. Four themes emerged from the data as significant aspects of leading change in a pay-for-performance system: (a) supporting a culture of excellence, (b) leading through sense making, (c) maintaining balance, and (d) providing instructional leadership.The theme of &quot;culture of excellence&quot; refers to the standpoint of preparing students for higher learning expectations. Participants discussed creating a &quot;high culture of excellence&quot; as setting a sense of urgency for learning. Principals&apos; responses were generally about how to set the stage to prepare students for learning. However, there was an underlying message that leaders must be able to establish a climate for learning by involving people throughout the process. The theme of &quot;leading through sense-making&quot; includes ideas that the leader needs to be able to make sense of a changing system for self and others, understand the significance of the change, and work actively with others as a change agent. The theme of &quot;maintaining balance&quot; describes participants&apos; feelings that money is not the sole motivation factor for teachers in a pay-for-performance system; it is more important to find the right balance of intrinsic and extrinsic rewards. Maintaining balance includes finding the right staff members, providing the right level of support, and balancing rewards for good teaching. Finally, the theme of &quot;providing instructional leadership&quot; focuses on the principal as a master of instructional practices. All of the participants felt that the most important role as a principal in a pay-for-performance system is to be an active instructional coach for their teaching staff. To foster improvement of teacher performance, the principal needs to provide instructional coaching and feedback, create a team atmosphere, and make regular visits to classrooms to establish a climate focused on improvement.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66587</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66587</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Ortiz-Torres, Amanda Lela</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Korach, Susan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Michalec, Paul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Fukmai, Cynthia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Educational Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Morgridge College of Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>viii, 124 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Educational leadership</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>leadership</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>pay-for-performance</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66586</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-10-03T23:30:57Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Attending high school Algebra I: In search of well-managed, engaging, culturally relevant, and caring classrooms</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Gannett, Cassandra Dunn</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Uhrmacher, Bruce</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The inequities in learning between the rich and the poor have become pervasive in United States. This is evidenced by the high school graduation rates, college attendance percentages, and employment statistics. Upon another wave of reform, the Common Core State Standards in mathematics are currently being adopted in hopes of increasing learning for all students, with a focus on college and career readiness.   This study is intent on finding ways to remedy the inequities in mathematics between the high income and low income schools by focusing on one of the great glass ceilings to high school graduation and beyond, high school Algebra I.  This study gives examples of how successful teachers are providing opportunities for learning Algebra I despite barriers that students, administrators, and policy-makers deliver in low-income schools amidst the latest reform movement. The researcher provides a portrait of how three different algebra teachers in three different low-income high schools, in the same city in Colorado, teach within the confines of various reform mandates to meet the diverse needs of their students. The research was conducted with a particular focus on the classroom management strategies, student engagement strategies, culturally relevant pedagogy, and caring relationships contributed to the learning in these classrooms. Using observations, teacher interviews, and student interviews, the researcher employs the method of Educational Criticism and Connoisseurship to answer the research question. The question that guided this study was: What practices do effective algebra teachers employ in high poverty, diverse high school algebra classrooms to implement the curriculum and influence student learning? This question was supported by the sub-questions: (a) What classroom management strategies contribute to student learning?; (b) Which teaching strategies contribute to student engagement?; (c) Which culturally relevant pedagogy practices contribute to students&apos; opportunity to learn?; (d) How do relationships in the classroom support students&apos; opportunities to learn?; and (e) How are classroom management strategies, engagement strategies, culturally relevant pedagogy, and caring relationships intertwined in classrooms today? The findings of this study provide a stark warning to overly prescribed curricula and pedagogy, along with the heightened use of standardized tests tied to teacher evaluation. Answering the primary question using Eisner&apos;s (1998) dimensions of schooling and Uhrmacher&apos;s administrative dimension, paints a bleak picture for low-income schools under the current movement for accountability using student test scores. The negative consequences of a punitive administrative oversight on the teaching and learning of students paints a depressing scene for low-income schools. Conversely, the efforts of teachers to provide classroom management and student engagement supported by culturally relevant practices and caring relationships give a picture of hope if we focus on supporting and keeping in the schools that need them the most.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66586</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66586</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator></dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gannett, Cassandra Dunn</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Cutforth, Nicholas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Michalec, Paul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Curriculum and Instruction</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Morgridge College of Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>ix, 282 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Mathematics education</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>algebra</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>effective teaching</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>equity</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>high school</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>reform</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>teacher evaluation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66585</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-10-03T23:31:11Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Noble or Malevolent in a Moment of Dismay:  How Postsecondary Students Construe and Characterize Bystander Action in School Violence Shooting Incidents</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Underhill, Dyan Whitlow</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Tuitt, Franklin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Uhrmacher, P.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Bowman, Linda</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rhodes, Martin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lines, Cathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Multiple incidents of postsecondary school shooting violence have occurred in American society--prompting concern about safety on college campuses, administrators&apos; roles in prevention, and proactive and responsible bystander actions.  Active shooter plans have become more established in educational environments, with efforts are directed toward both the perpetrator and the victims.  Limited information, however, has been provided regarding how bystanders would, or even should, construe and characterize their roles in such incidents.  Numerous professional and governmental researchers in organizations throughout the United States (e.g., the Center for Disease Control Injury Center, National Center for Injury Prevention and Control, National Consortium on Violence Research-Carnegie Mellon University, and the Violence Prevention Research Program-University of California, Davis) have identified that prevention remains the best action.  The American Colleges Health Association (ACHA) leaders asked postsecondary educational institutions&apos; leaders to become engaged more actively in prevention efforts. In the current study, the researcher&apos;s own reconditioned hermeneutic design was used to examine appropriate bystander action during an incident of school shooting violence based on an Adapted Social Systems Model.  Internal and external socioeconomic factors with influence on student bystander action were addressed.  School administrators might find insight from the findings, implications, and future directions for research as discussed.  The results include a framework for the development of the ARISE bystander action model, a school violence ecological model in which the student bystander is placed in the center.  The ARISE model might be used as an action strategy for postsecondary institutions with a multidisciplinary approach to informing new policies and procedures.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66585</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66585</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Underhill, Dyan Whitlow</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Higher Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Morgridge College of Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>xi, 199 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Higher education</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>bystander</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>post-secondary</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>shooting</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66584</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-10-03T23:31:25Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Lamination of Inverted Organic Photovoltaics and Associated Physical Properties</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Bailey, Brian Appleby</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Shaheen, Sean</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kopidakis, Nikos</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Balzar, Davor</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Zink, Barry</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>van de Lagemaat, Jao</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Olson, Dana</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Calbi, Mercedes</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>This dissertation is the result of a series of studies involving hot press lamination of inverted organic photovoltaics.  It first gives background and develops a lamination process for fabrication.  Then, the process is used to answer fundamental questions about organic photovoltaics and to fabricate previously impossible or overly complicated devices.  Finally, the author examines the scientific theory which describes the process and aligns that theory with related measurements.The field of organic photovoltaics is introduced and the lamination process is developed and optimized.  In the lamination process, part of the solar cell is deposited onto a rigid substrate, and the rest is deposited onto a flexible one.  The two substrates are pressed together under heat to complete the device.  Laminated devices are shown to perform as well or better than those made with standard fabrication methods, and the process shows benefits to both large scale production and scientific exploration of OPV devices.The lamination process is then used to answer physical questions and solve problems related to OPV.  After diversifying the procedure to include lamination at either the electron or hole contact, a series of semitransparent electrode materials are integrated into devices.  These materials are difficult or impossible to integrate into inverted devices without lamination.  Then bare metal contacts are pretreated and laminated into devices in order to investigate the mechanisms for time evolution in inverted devices.  Finally, two active layers are laminated to make a tandem device.  It is shown that the performance of the tandem is limited not by the procedure, but by the materials used in the interconnect layer between the two subcells.An investigation is performed that explores the physics behind the basis of lamination: adhesion.  Different mechanisms of adhesion are proposed, and calculations of adhesion forces based on known materials properties are made.  The resulting range of calculated forces is quite large, but within the range of measured values for adhesion force.  A general picture of the physics involved in lamination processes and their adhesion forces emerges.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66584</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66584</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Bailey, Brian Appleby</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Physics and Astronomy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Natural Sciences and Mathematics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>x, 124 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Physics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>organic electronics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>organic photovoltaics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>photovoltaic</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66582</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-10-03T23:31:56Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Korean American Adolescents&apos; and Their Parents&apos; Attitudes and Expectations toward Group Counseling</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Lee, Myoung Ah</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Riva, Maria</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Valdez, Jesse</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cornish, Jennifer</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Zhang, Duan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>The purpose of the current investigation was to examine the relationships between three important cultural factorsacculturation, self-disclosure, and gender and Korean American adolescents attitudes and expectations about group counseling. In addition, the relationships between two of these factorsacculturation and self-disclosure, and Korean parents expectations and attitudes about group counseling as a potential treatment modality for their adolescents were examined. Ninety-three Korean high school students who attended 9 private afterschool programs provided by the Korean Institute of Southern California (KISC) in the Los Angeles area and their 93 corresponding Korean parents participated in the present study. For the student sample, the four subscales of the Acculturation Attitudes Scale (Integration, Assimilation, Separation, and Marginalization), the Self-Disclosure Questionnaire, and gender served as predictor variables, and the Group Therapy Survey was used as an outcome variable. The multiple regression results indicated that integration and assimilation significantly contributed to the prediction of Korean adolescents attitudes and expectations about group counseling, with the integration being the strongest predictor of the other modes of acculturation. Results also indicated that integration was correlated with Korean adolescents positive attitudes and expectations about group counseling, whereas assimilation was correlated with their negative attitudes and expectations about group counseling. The level of
iii
comfort with self-disclosure and gender were not significant predictors of group counseling expectations among the Korean adolescents. For the parent sample, five predictor variables (the four modes of acculturation and self-disclosure) were entered into another multiple regression model to investigate the impact of these variables on Korean parents expectations about group counseling for their adolescents. The results indicated that integration and self-disclosure were significant predictors of the parents expectations about group counseling. Implications and limitations of the present study, and directions for future research are discussed. Additionally, some recommendations for school counselors who work with Korean students and their families are presented in Chapter 5.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>codu:66582</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66582</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Lee, Myoung-Ah</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Morgridge College of Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Counseling and Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>iv, 212 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66583</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-03-07T16:48:27Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Mixed-Methods Exploration of Teacher Perceptions: Background, Practices, and Attitudes Related to Student Achievement</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Faust, Deborah Isabell</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Zhang, Duan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cutforth, Nicholas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Korach, Susan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>Denver (Colo.)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Education policy has focused on teacher quality and student achievement since the implementation of the No Child Left Behind Act, which defined teacher quality in terms of teachers&apos; professional qualifications and certification.  This is consistent with a history of econometric studies examining the effects of teacher background characteristics on student achievement.  More recently, researchers have argued that investigations of teacher effectiveness should examine what actually happens in the classroom, and that teacher attitudes and instructional practices are conspicuously missing from the prior research.This study uses a two-phase parallel mixed methods design to explore teacher perceptions of the influence of their background characteristics, attitudes, and instructional practices on student achievement.  The first phase is a quantitative analysis using structural equation modeling and data from the Early-Childhood Longitudinal Study, Kindergarten Class of 1998-1999 (ECLS-K) to examine the relative effects of teacher background characteristics, attitudes, and instructional practices on student achievement.  The second phase is a case study of an innovative elementary school meeting State expectations for student growth.The results of the quantitative analysis revealed that teacher attitudes typically have a significant effect on student achievement, but teacher background characteristics and perceptions related to their instructional practices do not.  The teachers in the case study agreed that teacher attitudes are important and are likely to have an effect on students, as well as on other teachers.  However, the teachers in the case study also perceived that a number of instructional practices are crucial to increasing student achievement and closing achievement gaps.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>Faust_denver_0061D_10698.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66583</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Faust, Deborah Isabell</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Research Methods and Statistics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Morgridge College of Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type>thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:format>x, 267 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>case study</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>instructional practices</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>structural equation modeling</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>student achievement</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>teacher attitudes</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dissertations, Academic</dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_66589</identifier>
    <datestamp>2014-03-29T00:43:41Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62799</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Digital media&apos;s transformative role In education: beyond potential to essential</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Chien, Jemmy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Uhrmacher, P.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Michalec, Paul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Fajardo, Rafael</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Jones, Arthur</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2012</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:description>Achieving effective learning via digital media continues to be a major concern in contemporary education. The daily use of all forms of digital media is part of our lives and therefore becomes a key component of education. Educators must consider the process of digital media curriculum as a learning model and form of experience adapted to education. This means the significance is on how to learn as well as what to learn. This study demonstrated how the implementation of digital media curriculum via the Scratch game-making project contributed to middle school students&apos; interaction with the entire educational process. The goal was to rethink the role of digital media in transforming schooling. Based on classroom observation and interviews with the teachers and students from four middle schools in Denver, Colorado, the qualitative method of educational criticism and connoisseurship was employed to examine the use of digital media and the interaction between teaching and learning. Several themes emerged: (a) The production of digital media influenced students&apos; behavior and educators&apos; attitudes towards formal and informal learning; (b) digital citizenship is a substantial lesson in the course of digital learning and an understanding of the digital framework of society; (c) new literacy is critical, because ever-changing equipment supporting the digital experience provides dynamic and contrasting ways of connecting with society; (d) the reward of learning is by doing versus being told, and deeper learning is attained by students&apos; interacting with their own work; and (e) digital media programs, such as making video games for learning, provide students skills in communication, theoretical, aesthetic, creativity, and technical knowledge necessary for becoming successful digital citizens. The research revealed students&apos; enjoyment and effort in this new form of learning experience, which enhanced their critical thinking, problem solving, and creativity under teachers&apos; well-planned guidance. The challenge for educators is to constantly review and design educational approaches supporting students towards using the tools meaningfully and within a defined learning experience, continuing to help students become active participants and authors of their own identity and creativity. Educators need to find the best usage of digital media technology, providing students every advantage towards reaching an informed global perspective.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:identifier>Chien_denver_0061D_10707.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:66589</dc:identifier>
  <dc:creator>Chien, Jemmy</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Morgridge College of Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Curriculum and Instruction</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:format>vii, 392 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:format>born digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>digital citizenship</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>digital media</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>multifaceted thinking</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>new literacy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
 </ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
