<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
 <responseDate>2014-05-05T03:43:15Z</responseDate>
 <request verb= "ListRecords">http://digitaldu.coalliance.org/oai2</request>
 <ListRecords>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55722</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:35:14Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Mobile Home Construction in Colorado as an Example of Applied Climatology</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Guptil, R.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>University of Denver Department of Geography</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:date>1974</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55722</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57648</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:35:04Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Place Names in the Grand Canyon National Park</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Chapparo, Susan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The study of place-names presents a fascinating insight into the hopes, values, and interests of past generations. And perhaps nowhere is this truer than in the United States, where in most cases it is known who first used a name given to a particular feature on the landscape. When the immigrants first came to the eastern shores of North America, they brought with them many treasured memories of their lives in the old world. And the names they placed on the features of this new land were often taken from places they had known before. Then after the American Revolution, great new territories were opened up in the West, and explorers and settlers in these regions often used names reflecting their hopes and dreams. They also met new peoples who had their own names for many natural features, which were then assimilated, often in corrupted forms, into the American language. An example of a name of this kind is Magotsu Creek in Utah, which was taken from the Pah Ute Indian phrase Mahautsu, meaning &quot;long slope&quot;. Many settlements in these newly occupied areas bloomed briefly and as quickly died out, leaving behind only intriguing names and the stories surrounding them. But the names of many of the natural features survived. After much of the West had been at least sparcely settled, its unique and spectacular landforms were located and extensively explored. Many of these areas had been first seen years before by white men, and of course the Indians knew of them, but they were considered either tall tales, or were placed on maps that so poorly showed their true position that no one could find them again. Thus these natural wonders were likely &quot;discovered&quot; many times before being reliably mapped and systematically explored. These areas of natural beauty were later among the first National Parks in the United States. The designation of vast tracts of land in the West as National Parks came about in response to the paintings and writings of many naturalists and explorers, such as John Muir, Thomas Moran and John Wesley Powell, in the late nineteenth century and early twentieth. A need was seen for areas of spectacular natural beauty to be set aside and left in their natural conditions for visitors to marvel at. And marvel they have, even back to the first sightings of one of these places, the Grand Canyon.These early visitors are the ones to whom belongs the credit for the picturesque, often exotic landform names to be found in the Parks. Even the most casual glance at these names shows that most of them fall into one of a number of categories based on their origins, i.e. names from ancient religions or mythologies. This observation led the author to the thought that names in a given category might show a tendency to occur in one area and be sparce or nonexistant in another. The Grand Canyon was chosen for site of this study, for the Park contains a great variety of place names. Originally, I to determine the dates when the names were given, and compare these to the dates of similar names given in other National Parks established at about the same time. However, the material on place names in other Parks is not nearly as extensive as that for the Grand Canyon, and that information rarely indicates when names were given, if it is even known. Therefore, I decided to limit this study to the names in the Grand Canyon, and leave out entirely the question of when features were named.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:date>1987</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:57648</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57648</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_54115</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:37:53Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Developing Remote Sensing Display Modes To Satisfy Urban Planning Data Input Needs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Griffiths, Thomas M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Howard, William A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kracht, James B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver Department of Geography</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1971</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:54115</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:54115</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58123</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:34:31Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Implementation and Application of a 3-D Enterprise GIS at Timpanogos Cave National Monument, Utah</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Geographic Information Systems (GIS) have long been understood to be a very effective management and decision- making tools within the National Park Service, especially for large parks and region wide issues. Recent advances in GIS hardware, software, and data have opened this new technology to many smaller National Park Service units. This research, coordinated with the Intermountain Region GIS support office, provides a case study of GIS implementation and application at one such sm ll National Monument. Timpanogos Cave National Monument {TICA), Utah, requires a GIS to better serve their mission in many different areas of park management. The purpose of this research is to implement a three-dimension (3-D) capable enterprise GIS atTICA. Additionally, this research seeks to prove the capability and functionality of this GIS through a 3-D GIS rockfall hazard assessment and 3-D visualization applications.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002 March</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:58123</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58123</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_54114</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:37:06Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Flagstaff Field Studies: 1970 Part 1-Synoptic Observations And Operations Summaries</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weder, Delores M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peterman, William A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Technical Note No. 2 Contract No. 14-06-D-6646</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver Department of Geography</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1970-12-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:54114</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:54114</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55657</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:36:19Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Development of Computer Programs Applicable to Meaningful Precipitation Management Experiments</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Peterman, William A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description>omputer programs have use in precipitation management experiments. Operational useof computers and computer products has been limited, however, because of several limitation which restricttheir use. Scientists conducting precipitation management operations need user-oriented computer products specifically designed for their needs. Several numerical models and programs have been studied and tested. A philosophy for the field use of computers has been developed. From this has grown a system for transmitting data and computer products to field users. This system has undergone a series of field tests and has been carefully evaluated. This system has been made operational by the Bureau of Reclamation, and its data and computer programs are currently available to all Project Skywater field programs.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:date>1971</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:55657</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55657</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_54113</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:36:43Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Utilization Of The Computer For Operational Weather Modification</dc:title>
  <dc:title>Weather Modification Research Project</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Peterman, William A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Technical Note No. 1 Contract No. 14-06-D-6646</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver Department of Geography</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1970-10-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:54113</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:54113</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55653</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:36:48Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Discriminating Pre-Visual Symptoms of Stress Associated with Dutch Elm Disease Through Color Infrared Photography</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>LaPerriere, Louis R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Howard, William A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Technical Paper No. 71-1</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1971</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55653</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57530</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:36:08Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>AN EVALUATION OF THE THIESSEN POLYGON METHOD FOR ASSESSING AREAL PRECIPITATION DEPTHS: A SIMULATED APPROACH</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Viterito, Arthur</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Data scarcity and non-representativeness is a major problem facing the field of atmospheric science today. For example, Oort (1978) has found the global rawindsonde network to be inadequate for the entire Southern Hemisphere and all ocean areas, and only minimally adequate for large scale circulation studies of the Northern Hemisphere. The situation appears to be just as problematic for more familiar elements, such as precipitation data. Mather (1974) points out that the conterminous United States, 2 although approximating 7.8 million km in area, is gaged by only some 13,000 rain gages. Each of these gages has an average collection area of —7 o 3 x 10 km , giving a total gaged surface area of 1/800 km2. Thus, only 1.6 x 10~8 percent of the total surface area of the conterminous United States has gage coverage. A large scale study by Hudson, Stout and Huff (1952) illustrates the differences in the resultant isohyetal pattern drawn from networks of varying rain gage density for an individual storm in central Illinois (see Figure 1-1). It is readily apparent from the maps that as gage density is decreased, the resultant isohyetal pattern is 12 4 sq mi pe» gag« 4 75 sq mi. pef gog« 9 5&amp;q.n» ptf gog« 19.5 sq m. ptr gog« Figure 1 - 1 . Effect of raingage density on isohyetal pattern (From Hudson, Stout and Huff, 1952) US. Weaifm Buecu Climatofogcol Network, 225 aq mi per gag*. changed markedly. In addition to errors which result from inadequate numbers of measuring sites {rawindsonde stations, rain guages, etc.), errors can be substantial at the measuring site itself. Some of the sources of measurement error include instrument malfunction and poor instrument location. An example of the effect of poor instrument location on observational error is provided by Changnon and Huff (1977). Their analysis of the recent precipitation data for La Porte, Indiana has shown a significant decline in the precipitation amounts for this area and attributes the decline to poor instrument exposure. An example of poor instrument performance is given by Goodison (19 78) for Canadian snow gages. He has shown that for a wind speed of 5 meters/ second, shielded versions of the Fisher and Porter and Universal gages caught only a maximum of 51 percent of true ground precipitation. The unshielded versions of these gages caught only a maximum of 32 percent of true ground precipitation The general relationship established for gage catch and windspeed is that both types of gages have decreasing catches as windspeed increases. Instruments can be improved and their improper siting corrected, but the amount of data available will continue to be less than ideal. The number of data collection points that can be established and maintained has economic limitations, so that we need to expect to continue to work with an unsatisfactory data base. Methods have been devised to provide estimates of average conditions throughout an area from sample point data, and the foregoing comments were presented to emphasize the importance of such methods. This is a study about several of these methods. The climatic element of interest is precipitation, and the methods of data treatment are concerned with providing a representative expression of precipitation occurrence throughout an area rather than at individual points in it. The study has been designed to compare the performance of selected methods for obtaining areal estimates of precipitation. Its purpose is to provide a basis for the statements concerning the appropriateness of these methods under varying circumstances. As will be explained, there is lack of agreement as to which method is most appropriate for a given situation. It is the goal of this study to resolve some of this disagreement.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:date>1980 February</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:57530</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57530</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57895</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:35:09Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Geographic Information System for the Mount Evans Region</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dover, Melissa Ann</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Mount Evans, at an elevation of 4,348 meters (14,264 feet) and located in the Front Range of Colorado, strikes an impressive view looking west from Denver. Originally a portion of an ancestral range of the late Precambrian time, Mount Evans is now only an erosion remnant of a huge granitic batholith (Griffiths and Rubright 1983). Water, ice, wind and gravity have carved this majestic range, and continue to be the dominating natural forces shaping these mountains. The Front Range acts as a watershed for streams and groundwater, a source of valuable minerals, an area for commercial timber activities, a pasture for livestock and perhaps most intensely, as a recreational escape for close-by city dwellers and tourists. According to a Denver Post article dated September 13, 1994, more than 71,000 vehicles drove to the summit of Mount Evans in a three month period during the summer.Mount Evans&apos; close proximity to Denver has enabled the University of Denver to develop a research area for its faculty and students which supports many diverse research topics. The wide range of natural resource topics being researched in the area make the Mount Evans region a prime candidate for a Geographic Information System (GIS). GIS is defined as an information technology which can input, store, manipulate, analyze and display spatial and non-spatial data. A GIS can be the integrating tool that allows disparate information formats such as vector, raster, image or Database Management Systems (DBMS) to be brought together under a common framework for access and analysis (ESRI 1992). &quot;A GIS organizes geographic data using a georelational and topological model which facilitates efficient handling of the two generic classes of spatial data: locational data, graphically describing the location and topology of point, line, and area features; and attribute data, the information describing the characteristics of these features.&quot; (ESRI 1992, p.12) In order to better serve the University of Denver&apos;s Geography department&apos;s research projects, a GIS was designed and implementation begun using Environmental Systems Research Institute&apos;s (ESRI) PC ARC/INFO GIS software, to facilitate efficient and high quality data manipulation and mapping of the Mount Evans region.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:date>1995 August</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:57895</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57895</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_37754</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:37:22Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Comparative Study of Terrain Analysis Techniques</dc:title>
  <dc:title>Publications in Geography</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Griffiths, Thomas M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Technical Paper No. 64-2</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver Department of Geography</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1964</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:37754</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55655</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:37:38Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An Assessment of the Usefulness of Small-Scale Photographic Imagery for Acquiring Land Use Information Necessary to the Urban Planning Function</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Howard, William A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kracht, James B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study concerns the feasibility of remote sensing techniques contributing to the data needs of urban planning. The primary question investigated is whether planning information inputs can be modified to be compatible with current remote sensor output formats and whether these output formats are alterable enough to become compatible with planning input needs. Small scale imagery at 1:50,000 and 1:100,000 in conventional color and color infrared is used to determine the extent to which land use types can be discriminated. The larger scale is most useful and generalized information at a one-digit level can be identified with more detailed information at a two-digit level also possible. The smaller of the scales is only useful for one-digit discrimination and only a very few land use types at a two-digit level of detail. The present formats of remote sensing are suited to the planner’s needs and offer promise as a data source if available on a routine basis and at frequent intervals. However, small-scale imagery must possess high resolution and be of very good quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Technical Paper No. 71-2</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1971</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:55655</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55655</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57882</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:37:58Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Relationship Between Expansive Soils and Housing Turnover</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Graczyk, Richard J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Past studies on residential mobility have examined the relationship between a number of variables and housing turnover. This list of variables includes life cycle stage, housing tenure, racial character of the neighborhood, marital status of household head, income and numerous others. In most cases however physical site factors such as slope stability, drainage characteristics of the residential plot, ability of the soil to sustain an attractive landscape, or shrink-swell characteristics of the soil are seldom mentioned. This paper will explore the latter problem in greater detail.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:date>1980 May</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:57882</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57882</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_54112</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:35:59Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Trincheras And Physical Environment Along The Rio Gavilan Chihuahua, Mexico</dc:title>
  <dc:title>Publications in Geography</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Technical Paper Number 65-1</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver Department of Geography</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1970</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:54112</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:54112</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_37755</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:37:02Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Determination of Vegetation Characteristics And A Discussion of Vegitation Sampling Methods</dc:title>
  <dc:title>Publications in Geography</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ream, Robert R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Technical Paper No. 64-4</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver Department of Geography</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1964</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:37755</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58117</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:34:53Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Developing an Interface Between ArcView GIS and the Industrial Source Complex Model A Case Study in Denver, Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Holtkamp, Christopher Ray</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The interactive tool developed for this project is designed to allow users to access the air pollution modeling capabilities of the Environmental Protection Agency&apos;s Industrial Source Complex (lSC) model then use the capabilities of Arc View GIS, developed by Environmental Systems Research Institute (ESRI), to display and analyze the results. The goal is to allow non-technical users a relatively simple means of modeling the dispersion of air pollution quickly and easily. This report is intended to discuss the process that went into creating the interactive tool and how the final product evolved from the ideas that began this project; it is not intended as a user&apos;s guide for the interactive tool. This report will begin with the background of the project, describing the original idea. It will then discuss problems and decisions that were made during the development process that influenced the final product. It will then discuss the actual development of the interactive tool and the different applications used. This report will end with a discussion of how this tool can be applied and areas of future work that can build on this tool to expand the capabilities.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:date>1999 June</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:58117</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58117</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55729</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:37:45Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The New Pueblo Freeway: A Project Web Site Using ArcIMS Final Report</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Orr, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>MS in GIS Technical Paper</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver Department of Geology</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55729</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55734</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:37:33Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Implementation of a GIS for Regional Management of Leafy Spurge (Euphorbia esula) and Yellow Starthistle (Centaurea solstitialis) in the Western United States</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Thoene, Jason W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>MS in GIS Technical Project</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver Department of Geography</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2002 May</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55734</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55656</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:35:28Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An Evaluation of the Usefulness of Remote Sensing Techniques in Making Environmental Quality Determinations</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Howard, William A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Herold, Laurance C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Driscoll, Linda B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>LaPerriere, Louis R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Timely and authoritative information is essential for determining the conditions and trends in the quality of the environment. Yet a comprehensive monitoring system applicable to all aspects of the environment, either natural or man-made, is far into the future. As a means of advancing the state-of-the-art for conducting environmental quality evaluations, a system is investigated in this report which has as its primary data acquisition method remote sensing techniques. Physical surrogates which represent presumed indicators of social and economic conditions of a population are utilized in the analysis. The physical surrogates employed in this investigation are correlated with social, economic, and demographic indicators identified and used by the City and County of Denver Community Renewal Program. The results are truly promising despite some procedural difficulties that occurred with the imagery interpretation phase of the study. Possibly the most pervasive or important conclusion which emerged from this study is that for remote sensing to play an important part in making environmental quality evaluations the amount and reliability of the information derived from the technique depends greatly on the background of the environment being studied. This fact is borne out in the use of architectural styling as an interpretation key for studying the morphological nature of the City and County of Denver.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Technical Report No. 73-1</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1973</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:55656</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55656</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_37756</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:35:23Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An Effects Linkage Test of Enviromental Characteristics and Military Functions</dc:title>
  <dc:title>Publications in Geography</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Griffiths, Thomas M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Technical Paper Number 64-7</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1964</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:37756</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55732</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:36:24Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Spatial Pattern Analysis of LandSAT ETM+ Satellite Imagery to Determine Logging Extent and Intensity in the Eastern Amazon</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Parks, Susan M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>MS GIS Technical Paper</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver Department of Geography</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2003 August</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55732</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57880</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:35:47Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>THE EFFECT OF URBANIZATION ON SEMI-ARID VERSUS HUMID WATERSHEDS</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Flood increase factors were examined for 21 study basins in semi-arid and humid climate regions to determine whether the effects of urbanization on the magnitude of the mean annual flood varied with precipitation amount. Analysis of variance yielded marginally significant results when comparing flood increase factors for five precipitation groups. However, linear regression analysis indicated only 32 percent of the variation in flood factors could be explained by differences in precipitation. It was concluded that, although marginally significant differences were found between flood factors for the given precipitation groups, the difference was so slight that the results are inconclusive.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:date>1985 July</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:57880</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57880</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_37757</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:36:35Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Geography Symposium Topics-1968</dc:title>
  <dc:title>Publications in Geography</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Technical Paper No. 68-1</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1968</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:37757</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_54111</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:36:39Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Scale Problems In Geographic Research</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Griffiths, Thomas M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Doiron, Claude J. Jr.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Final Technical Report ETL-CR-71-16 Prepared for U.S. Army Engineer Topographic Laboratories Research Institute Fort Belvoir, Virginia 22060 Prepared by University of Denver Department of Geography Denver, Colorado Contract No. DAAK-02-70-C-0334</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver Department of Geography</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1971-07-31</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:54111</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55668</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:34:41Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>University of Denver CAMPMAP GIS Project</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Boesch, William</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This document is presented as a plan for hte implementation of a Geotechnical project that will fulfill the requirements for course credit in GEOG 4960, Project Identification. Course credit in GEOG 4960 is a requirement for completion of a Masters of Arts in Geography at the University of Denver. The Facilities Management Department at the University of Denver has been chosen as the client for whome this plan is written. The actual implementation of the project will fulfill the requirements for GEOG 4993, Technical Project. A committee of individuals representing both the Department of Geography and Facilities Management has been chosen to review this document. Approval of this plan by this committee is required before the implementation phase can proceed. This plan outlines the steps that are to be taken and the resources that are required to complete the project. Background information is also provided.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:date>1999</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55668</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55654</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:34:36Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Weather Modification Research Project</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Peterman, William A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description>From 20 July to 8 August 1970 an experiment in decision making was conducted by the University of Denver with the assistance of scientists from DAWRM and MRI. The results from this experiment are encouraging in that they indicate that (1) decision making can be used to increase the efficiency of precipitation management experiments and (2) the meteorological information network, developed in part by the University of Denver, is a valuable tool for use by decision maker. Largely, as a result of this experiment the decision was made by the DAWRM to initiate the meteorological information network on an operational basis for the 1970-71 wintertime seeding. This was accomplished during November 1971. Thus, beginning at that time, all Project Skywater field programs had available all of the tools and data for decision making available to the scientists at the Flagstaff project. It is felt that the implementation of this network represents a significant step toward the development of a well coordinated precipitation management program. The implementation of the network is only the first step needed to make available decision-making techniques to field users. Many improvements are yet needed. Among these are more efficient processes for collecting, storing, and disseminating data, expanded data bases, and a greater diversity of programs and models. The first step has been taken. Let us hope that the remaining steps will soon follow and that decision making will become truly an integral part of precipitation management research.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Technical Note No. 3</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1970</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:55654</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55654</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55726</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:35:33Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Technical Project Overview: An Introduction into the Worlds of Computer Programming, Custom Application Development and Their Relationships to GIS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Muleh, Alex</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>MS GIS Capstone Project</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver Department of Geology</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55726</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55728</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:35:39Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Growth in Denver: Assessing the Roles of Population and Land Use Decisions in the Denver Metropolitan Area Using Landsat TM and MSS Data with U.S. Census</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Noonan, Jessica C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>MS-GIS Capstone Project</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver Department of Geography</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55728</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55735</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:35:18Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Relationship of Elevation to Birth Weight by Sex and Neonatal Deaths in Colorado Counties</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wagner, Joan A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver Department of Geography</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>No date listed</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:55735</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55735</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55733</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:37:27Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Residential Environmental Quality in Denver Utilizing Remote Sensing Techniques</dc:title>
  <dc:title>Publications in Geography #74-1</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Howard, William A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Herold, Laurance C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Driscoll, Linda B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>LaPerriere, Louis R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Prepared for George C. Marshall Flight Center, Marshall Space Flight Center, Alabama 35812</dc:description>
  <dc:date>1974 May</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>NAS8-28216</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55733</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57511</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:35:52Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>To PUD or Not to PUD: An Inventory of the Extent and Utilization of the PUD Concept in Metropolitan Denver.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Luhrs, Kurt A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Positive results were observed with respect to the hypothesis that perimeter cities and their respective counties will adopt PUD ordinances before inner cities. Analysis of the data showed that perimeter cities and counties did adopt their PUD ordinances before inner cities. This was due in part to the significantly higher rate of growth of perimeter cities. Because PUD was oriented toward large scale development perimeter cities probably adopted this ordinance to better control the increased population growth by offering large scale planned developments.Spatial Group Comparisons.There were many similarities between inner and perimeter cities and unincorporated urban areas when the key ordinance provisions,implementation procedures and development trends were compared. This means that PUD is being used in the same manner throughout the region. Perimeter cities did have a higher percentage of PUD projects for a three year average than did counties. Inner cities seemed to have a limited amount of growth but among these cities there was a growing number of PUD&apos;s. Inner cities appear to be in the process of increasing their use of PUD to guide the development of the limited amount of vacant land available. Use of the PUD Concept Perimeter cities did make the most consistent use of the PUD concept.Thornton and Aurora were the two cities that appeared to make the most consistent use of the concept. Aurora seemed to be using the concept less, in 1978 than during the post adoption period. Thornton is increasing their use of PUD almost to the exclusion of standard zoning and sub¬division regulations. This difference in use of the concept over time is probably due in part to the detailed ordinance used by Aurora and the very general ordinance that Thornton uses.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:date>1980 May</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:57511</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57511</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_37753</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:36:13Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Problems in Expression of Climate</dc:title>
  <dc:title>Publications in Geography</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rudd, Robert D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>Technical Paper No. 64-3</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver Department of Geography</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1964</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:37753</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_60690</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-08-01T15:36:19Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">The Significance and Implementation of Geographic Information Systems for Cities</dc:title>
  <dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Otto-Finnegan, Peggy</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:contributor>
  <dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:contributor>
  <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Text</dc:type>
  <dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema">1988, November</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:publisher>
  <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:type>
  <dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema"></dc:language>
  <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:format>
  <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:format>
  <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:description>
  <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema"></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema"></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:coverage>
  <dc:description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema">In this day and age cities are growing, not only in size, but in complexity which has greatly increased their information needs. The complexity of administrative requirements imposed by new and expanding governmental programs and regulations has created even more data that cities will need to handle. In addition to this growth in the amount of information needed, there is also a need to obtain information in different forms to meet changing legal requirements. At the same time, traditional and routine day-to-day information that is generated and processed must continue to be stored. A city planning department, for example, collects a variety of land related information on a daily basis. Planning and building applications come in with deeds, surveys, and development plans attached. In most cities this information will remain in the case files as a matter of permanent record, creating a vast amount of stored paper. In addition to this, the public is continually requesting information which has to be looked up, either on a map or in one of several record books. They may be asking for information on floodplains or zoning, which must be given in correct precise legal form or the city employee giving the information could be held legally
accountable. Most city departments information which must be are generating useful and necessary stored somehow. All of these
increasing amounts of information are coming at a time when the economic vitality of cities is decreasing, and tax bases are dwindling. In fact, Colorado recently had a proposal where taxation could not be increased without voter approval, with elections allowed only once every two years. While this particular legislative measure did not pass, several other states already have such tax limitation laws and still others can
anticipate taxation laws similar to this. As a result, many cities may have increased needs with no increases in tax based revenue. Budget cuts are already frequent and planning departments along with other city agencies are often targets of personnel reductions. The result is fewer people doing the same work as before plus responding to new needs and requirements. With recent advances in technology, the possibility of
automating land information is a reality for more cities. Just a few years ago data bases for cities were kept on mainframes. Today with the arrival of mini and personal computers, mainframes are not always needed for the same type of storage, analysis, and output. The mini and personal computers are also less expensive than mainframes which may enable more cities to participate in automation, especially smaller ones. The question now becomes whether or not recent advances in geographic information systems (GISs) can provide solutions for
cities to save time and money within a limited resource environment, and if so, how does a community go about selecting and implementing such a system? The research setting for this study will be metropolitan Denver, Colorado. Answers to these research questions have been pursued in two phases. First, selected metropolitan Denver area cities were surveyed as to their experience with automation. These
communities constitute a variety of different sizes, some of which have automated or are considering automation and others which have not automated. Questions related to why they have automated will be addressed. Second, a case study of the City of Wheat Ridge, Colorado which recently became involved with automating their municipal data will be examined. This case study along with the findings from other case studies reported in the literature will be incorporated into guidelines covering the main aspects of setting up a municipal GIS. To date there have been no in depth studies examining the developmental process of automating information systems for cities. This study will assist cities with limited capital in arriving at a decision of whether to automate, and if so to identify issues concerning the subsequent design of their own GIS. The guidelines that will be presented in this study are based on &quot;hands-on&quot; experience and should prove useful in
avoiding the major problems of setting up a municipal GIS.</dc:description>
  <dc:description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema">Research Project</dc:description>
  <dc:description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema"></dc:description>
  <dc:description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema"></dc:description>
  <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema"></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema">Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema">Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema"></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema"></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema"></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema"></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema"></dc:subject>
  <dc:relation xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:relation>
  <dc:relation xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:relation>
  <dc:relation xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:relation>
  <dc:relation xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">codu:60690</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"></dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema">Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:srw_dc="info:srw/schema/1/dc-schema">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:60690</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57892</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:34:47Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development of a Geographic Information System Database for Woodland Park, Colorado a Pilot Project</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rodeck, Paul P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Teller county Planning Offices are currently engaged in the preliminary stages of creating a Geographic Information System (GIS). It is the purpose of this project to facilitate the planning offices in their development of the GIS. The clients of the project are Mr. Larry Larsen, the city Planner of Woodland Park, and Mr. Kip Petersen, the County Planner. The pilot project described in this document provides the procedures of the GIS necessary to make the GIS operational. (Please also note this document assumes user has a working knowledge of AutoCAD and understands basic GIS concepts.) The system is designed to facilitate: 1} organization and maintenance of planning data; 2} the processing of data to provide answers to specific questions; and 3} additional data storage and expansion of the information system. The agreed upon final product of this project, in addition to the development of the GIS system, was a series of land use GIS database files for Woodland Park, Colorado to assist local planners in their GIS development. pilot development of GIS technology is important to the Woodland Park planners because it will provide Woodland Park with a geographic information system which incorporates both graphic and attribute elements in the database. The County Planning Offices are currently in the early stages of initiating a GIS. The first objective was to develop the general design of the GIS and to make it operational. The second was to develop several data files, including a base map which can be used with subsequent map overlays. The City and County planners will be able to maintain, utilize, and update the system by entering new data into the database through a user-interface. This system will allow the planning offices to perform existing tasks in new and more efficient ways when it comes to storing, encoding, and analyzing information that before may have taken several days to complete. Constant updates and production of overlays and hard copy maps may be produced as needed within the planning office itself. Planning offices will be able to use the GIS to assist in the development of a growth management plan, daily activities, and long term planning ideas. Manipulating or combining the data in any way the user desires .may provide new information and assist in meeting future needs. Different alternatives of the planning process can be generated in terms of either graphic display (i.e. maps, diagrams, designs) or data (Hanson, 1987). Finally, the initial systems will allow planners to use Geo/Sql as the foundation on which to build new functions into their GIS and update and expand the database as needed.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:date>1992 August</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57892</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58126</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-03-19T16:37:17Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>COASTAL GEOMORPHOLOGICAL DATA MANAGEMENT, ANALYSIS, AND Visualization: An Assateague Island National Seashore Case Study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ransmeier, Melanie V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The northern end of Assateague Island National Seashore (ASIS) has migrated more than 400 meters toward mainland Maryland since Ocean City Inlet was stabilized by jetties following a major hurricane in 1933. This migration dramatically illustrates the dynamic nature of coastal systems. Geomorphological monitoring is crucial to understanding both the natural fluctuations of barrier islands and anthropogenic influences on coastal change. In order for monitoring data to be effective they must be properly collected, managed, utilized in appropriate analyses, and presented to resource stewards and the public in a meaningful way. This project addresses these needs by instituting a functional data management protocol, illustrating appropriate analytical techniques, and providing a geo-temporal data visualization model for ASIS&apos;s coastal geomorphologic data. The data management protocol documents methods and procedures for collecting, processing, distributing, and storing geomorphologic data. Analytical techniques explored and described include: historic shoreline change analysis, morphologic change surface creation, and comparison of traditional and topographic lidar derived cross-island profiles. The data visualization website provides a three dimensional time sequence animation of changing island morphology. Data management adds increased value to geomorphologic data for monitoring, analysis, and reporting. Illustrating analytical techniques enables natural resource staff and managers to explore the meaning that coastal geomorphologic data can impart by highlighting the potential for displaying and quantifying coastal change. Visualizing coastal change is important for understanding the dynamic nature of coastal environments. Each of these elements, as addressed in this project, enhances the coastal monitoring program in place at ASIS.</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005 June</dc:date>
  <dc:type>text</dc:type>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:58126</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58126</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language></dc:language>
  <dc:rights>Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57358</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:48:36Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Relationship Between Expansive Soils and Housing Turnover</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Graczyk, Richard J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>1980 May</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format></dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Past studies on residential mobility have examined the relationship between a number of variables and housing turnover. This list of variables includes life cycle stage, housing tenure, racial character of the neighborhood, marital status of household head, income and numerous others. In most cases, however, physical site factors such as slope stability, drainage characteristics of the residential plot, ability of the soil to sustain an attractive landscape, or shrink-swell characteristics of the soil are seldom mentioned. This paper will explore the latter problem in greater detail. Each year, natural disasters such as hurricanes, tornadoes, and earthquakes attract widespread television and newspaper coverage. This increases public awareness of these hazards. To be sure, the loss potential of these natural phenomena is enormous as well as highly visible. The damage caused by expansive souls, however, is also quite large but is incurred over a longer period of time rather than in a single large scale dramatic event.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57358</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description>Move to Papers</dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier></dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55684</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:48:36Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_37031</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Using Geographic Information Systems (GIS) to Rank Nantucket Island Shoreline Parcels for Acquisition and Public-Access Preservation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kuster, Andrew Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>May 2002</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>82</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Part I: Relative Research Abstract: This document contains research related to public access, private and public property rights, federal and state law, coastal zone management, management and planning techniques, and coastal Geographic Information Systems (GIS) applications. These topics are presented as an informative background to Parts II and HI of this technical research project. Part II: GIS Application Description Abstract: This document describes a GIS application developed to assist the Town of Nantucket with land parcel acquisition efforts. These efforts are being focused on land parcels adjacent to shoreline, with an underlying goal of protecting public access to beaches. Part III: Preliminary Waterways Access Action Plan Abstract: This document is a guide to the acquisition of shoreline parcels on Nantucket Island. Based on the Nantucket Shoreline Area Parcel Ranking Geographic Information System (GIS) application described in Part II, recommendations for shoreline area parcel acquisition are provided. This document was created for the Nantucket Planning &amp; Economic Development Commission.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55684</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2002_Kuster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
 </ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
