<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
 <responseDate>2014-05-05T05:31:21Z</responseDate>
 <request verb= "ListRecords">http://digitaldu.coalliance.org/oai2</request>
 <ListRecords>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63245</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-10-05T19:52:42Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62796</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Perceptions of Race and Academic Success in an Affluent Suburban Middle School</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63245</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63236</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-11-26T19:36:38Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62797</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Estimating Economic Activity from Space</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ghosh, Tilottama</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2010</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Accurate estimates of the magnitude and spatial distribution of both formal and informal economic activity is necessary to achieve various social and economic goals of societies and countries at different levels of analysis. However, collection of data on economic variables, especially of national and sub-national income levels is problematic due to various shortcomings in the data collection process. Additionally, the informal economy estimates are often excluded from official statistics. Thus, developing alternative methods for estimating these economic activities may prove to be useful and necessary. This research demonstrates the potential of developing spatially explicit estimates of economic activity from nighttime satellite imagery as provided by the Defense Meteorological Satellite Program&apos;s Opertaional Linescan System (DMSP-OLS). The methods presented here are used to estimate formal and informal economic activity of Mexico and India at the sub-national level and to create a disaggregated global map of total economic activity. Regression models were developed between spatial patterns of nighttime imagery and Adjusted Official Gross State Product (AGSP) for the U.S. states. The regression parameters derived from the regression models of the U.S. were blindly applied to Mexico to estimate the Estimated Gross State Income (EGSI) at the sub-national level and the Estimated Gross Domestic Income (EGDI) at the national level. Comparison of the EGDI estimate of Mexico and official Gross National Income (GNI) statistic demonstrated that the informal economy and inflow of remittances for Mexico was about 50 percent larger than what was recorded in the official GNI statistic. However, when the regression parameters were applied to India, Gross State Income (GSI) was underestimated for most of the states and Union Territories (UTs) of India in comparison to their official GSP, although it provided a high correlation (r = 0.93) between them. This was probably because of the lower level of urbanization in India in comparison to the U.S. To adjust for the different levels of urbanization in the U.S. and India, the EGDI was multiplied by the ratio of the percentage of the population in urban areas for the two countries. Comparing the Adjusted Estimated Gross Domestic Income (AEGDI) with the official GNI statistic of India suggested that the magnitude of India&apos;s informal economy and the inflow of remittances may also be 50 percent larger than what was recorded in the official GNI value. Lastly, a global disaggregated map of total (formal plus informal) economic activity was created. This was done by multiplying the sum of light intensity values of the administrative units (states of China, India, Mexico, and the U.S., and other countries of the world) with computed unique coefficients. This provided estimated total economic activity (GSPIi and GDPIi )  for each administrative unit. The total economic activity values were spatially distributed (disaggregated) within each administrative unit using the percentage contribution of agriculture towards GDP for each country, combined with raster representations of the nighttime lights image and the LandScan population grid. This generated a spatially disaggregated 30 arc-second or one km2 map of estimated total economic activity.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Geography--Economics, General--Statistics--Disaggregated map of total economic activity--Informal economy--Nighttime lights satellite imagery</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>163</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63236</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63236</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Sutton, Paul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Rebecca L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Anderson, Sherolyn</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Elvidge, Chris</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63323</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-11-26T19:40:52Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Context of Culture Change: Environment, Population, and Prehistory in Eastern Colorado, 1000 B.C. - A.D. 1540</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gilmore, Kevin Philip</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This dissertation research examines the interplay between prehistoric population dynamics and paleoenvironment, and the extent to which these factors influenced culture change over the last 3000 years on the western High Plains of Colorado.  The population dynamics of prehistoric hunter-gatherers in eastern Colorado were estimated using several proxies, including the summed probability distribution of radiocarbon ages from archaeological sites in eastern Colorado.  Understanding paleoenvironments of the western High Plains is critical to understanding prehistoric human adaptations to past climates and to predicting the magnitude and consequences of current climate change in this semi-arid region.  Analyses of sediment cores from small fens (groundwater fed peatlands) on the High Plains indicate they contain high resolution (sub-decadal) paleoenvironmental records that extend into the middle Holocene (ca. 7800 BP).  These &quot;pocket fens&quot; are small peatlands (25-2500 m2) sustained by springs fed by perched water tables.  Fluctuations in the relative humification and organic content of peat from these features provide proxies for effective moisture and temperature, respectively.  Due to the heterogeneity of the sediments contained within pocket fens, new methods of data analysis and display have been developed to compensate for sediment differences within and between fens.  Data from pocket fens suggest that they contain sensitive records of relatively low magnitude climate fluctuations.Well-dated, high-resolution records of paleoenvironment are important because they allow a more detailed examination of the complex relationship between climate, population and culture change.  Here, these records from pocket fens not only document extended periods of high amplitude deviations in climate (such as drought) that could have influenced cultural adaptations, they also document periods of high temporal variability in proxy temperature and effective moisture that could have disrupted existing cultural systems.  Periods of high temporal variability in climate would result in lower predictability of environment-dependent resources on an annual and decadal temporal scale, which in turn might have exceeded the inherent resiliency of cultural adaptations available within the knowledge base of these systems.  Episodes of drought and high temporal variability in conjunction with periods of increasing population pressure correlate to periods of culture change during the past 3000 years in the archaeological record for eastern Colorado.  This suggests that increased population and climate variability drove prehistoric culture change.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Geography--Anthropology, Archaeology--Paleoenvironment; Prehistory; wetlands;adaptation;</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>331</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63323</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63323</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Sullivan, Donald G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sutton, Paul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Taylor, Matthew</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Bamforth, Doug</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55651</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:34Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Quantitative Evaluation of the Importance of Present Climatic Conditions in the Profile of Slopes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Toy, Terrence J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1973</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>329</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The factors of the environment which control hillslope form include: (1) geology, (2) climate, (3) topography, (4) vegetation, (5) soils, and (6) process. The purpose of this research is to evaluate the importance of the climatic factor. Hillslope measurements and climate data were obtained for twenty-eight sites throughout the conterminous United States. Each hillslope selected has a southern exposure, is underlain by nearly horizontal marine shale, is within five miles of a weather station having a minimum record of twenty-one consecutive years including 1951-1971, and is devoid of man-made changes. The parameters developed from the hillslope surveys are: curvature of the convex segment; slope of the straight segment; slope of a regression line fit through the entire concave-convex hillslope profile; slope-length ratio; and departure from an average curve. The climate variables developed from Weather Bureau records were selected on the basis of their relationship to geomorphic processes. The climate variables utilized are: summer precipitation; fall precipitation; winter precipitation; spring precipitation; rainfall intensity; freeze-thaw cycles; thermal intensity; potential evapotranspiration; and water availability. Correlation coefficients from simple regression were used to determine the relationship between each hillslope parameter and each climate variable. Step-wise multiple regression was sued to measure the combined influence of all the climate variables on slope form. The hillslope parameters were divided into climatic groups and subjected to the analyses of variance to determine the possibility of the regionalization of landforms on the basis of climate. The results of the analyses indicate that climate plays an important role in determining hillslope form. Fifty-nine percent of the variations in the rate of curvature of the convex segments can be explained by the climate variables. Approximately 43 percent of the variation in the slop of the straight segments was accounted on the basis of climate. Slightly over 37 percent of the differences in the slope of the fitted regression line were attributable to differences in climate. Nearly 26 percent of the variation in the values of the slope-length ratio can be explained by the climate variables. Fourteen percent of the departure from the average curve was accounted for on the basis of climate. Two attempts to regionalize landforms on the basis of climate were unsuccessful. The elements of climate most important to hillslope form are: (1) potential evapotranspiration, (2) spring precipitation, and (3) water availability. It can be concluded from these results that hillslopes in arid regions generally have smaller radii of curvature of their convex segments, steeper gradients of their straight segments and smaller slope length ratios than those of humid areas. This suggests that stream patterns in arid areas should exhibit higher densities and frequencies than those in humid regions.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55651</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1973_Toy.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57528</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:34Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Study of the Differences Among Freshmen Persisters, Voluntary Withdrawals, and Academic Dismissals at the University of Denver Based on Enrollment Data</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Landi, Jose Alberto</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>November 1981</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>202</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The problem addressed by this study was as follows: Are University of Denver freshmen persisters, voluntary withdrawals, and academic dismissals different on entrance variables? If they are different, can the differences be explained, and is it possible to predict group membership? Of the freshmen who entered the University of Denver in the fall of 1979, 164 persisters, 140 voluntary withdrawals, and 49 academic dismissals were compared on 14 pre-enrollment variables routinely collected in institutional files. The data were analyzed using stepwise discriminant function analysis in order to test group differences, the contribution of variables to those differences, and the predictive accuracy of a model built on pre-enrollment variables. The analyses performed showed that persisters and voluntary withdrawals were so similar on the variables utilized that a more meaningful analysis of the contribution of variables to group discrimination, and a more powerful prediction model, should use the more homogeneous group definition of the combination of (persisters + voluntary withdrawals) versus academic dismissals. The most important findings of this study were: 1. The similarity of freshmen persisters and voluntary withdrawals on entrance characteristics. 2. The interaction effects of &quot;distance away from home,&quot; and the extremely different profiles of commuter and non-commuter academic dismissals at the University of Denver. 3. The importance of financial aid, student age, and socioeconomic characteristics to separate academic dismissals at the University of Denver from other freshmen, over academic variables expected to hold much stronger discriminating power, such as high school rank and standardized test scores. This finding challenged the criteria for admissions traditionally used by the university. 4. The possibility of building a fairly strong prediction model for academic dismissal at the University of Denver, based only on pre-enrollment data. This study developed a prediction model that, when separating academic dismissals from other freshmen, yielded overall percentages of correct classifications of 82.8% for the sub-sample of commuters, and 76.7% for non-commuters. These results allow the practical use of the model to build a &quot;high-risk&quot; group in order to apply retention, orientation, and counseling strategies on potential academic dismissals.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57528</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1981_Landi.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57891</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:34Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Study of the Rapid Transformation of IBO Heartland Settlements From Rural to Urban Centers: A Post-Nigerian Civil War Phenomenon</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Anene, Lawrence Okezie C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>August 1991</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>309</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The primary concern of this study was to investigate the factors responsible for the rapid emergence and growth of cities in the Ibo Heartland of Nigeria in the years following the end of the civil war in 1970.It was hypothesized that the Ibo Heartland has experienced an unusually rapid rate of urbanization in the post-civil war period. This main hypothesis was tested through the following specific hypotheses: 1. That the rate of urbanization of the Ibo Heartland settlements in the past-civil war period (1970-85) was unique. 2. That Government and private efforts at post-war reconstruction provided impetus for rapid urbanization of Ibo settlements. 3. That intensive community development efforts urbanization of Ibo rural settlements in the post-civil war period stimulated rapid urbanization of Ibo rural settlements. 4. That the return migration of Ibo businesses and persons resulted in the post-war urban phenomenon. 5. That certain Ibo cultural traits aided the urbanization processes. Seven emerging cities within the Ibo Heartland were selected for study. These were compared with fourteen cities of similar status selected from Ibo and Kano regions of Nigeria. Data for the study were collected through primary and secondary sources. Methods of· collecting primary data included use of questionnaires designed for scheduled interviews, oral interviews and field observations. Analyses of these data led to the conclusions that: (1) post-war urbanization in the Ibo Heartland was unique; (2) post-war reconstruction in Nigeria made an indirect contribution to this urbanization; (3) community development efforts provided infrastructures and economic j base for the transformation of Ibo rural settlements into cities; (4) return migration of Ibo businesses and capital propelled their rural settlements to faster growth and urbanization; and (5) Ibo culture was an underlying motivator in the process of transforming Ibo rural settlements into cities. Based on these findings, the researcher recommended among others the: (1) governments should make their impact felt in the development of new cities in Nigeria; (2) viability studies should be carried out before citing high order functions in the rural settlements and; (3) investments in the Ibo Heartland should be more on economic enterprises than mere prestige projects.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57891</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Herold, Laurance C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1991_Anene.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Longbrake, David</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Goetz, Andrew</dc:contributor>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55648</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:34Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Survey of Scale Concepts in Geographic Research</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Doiron Jr. Claude J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>May 1972</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>166</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The great size of the earth and the many geographical elements upon it require that geographic research utilize a reductionism that demands comprehensive considerations of scale. These elements compose a range of geographical focus within the experience of man, and in keeping with the processes of nature. The geographer has no laboratory in the manner of other scientists, but must rely on the map, and more recently upon remote sensors, as a means of making portions of the landscape amenable for study. These also supplement his field work, which is affected by the dimensions of the landscape, and his limited powers of observation. Geography is a science of areal variation which requires extensive study of area. Man’s perception and conceptualization of area have important implications of scale. In field work, the geographer operates at a scale of reality (1:1). The sources with which he supplements field work are at various scales. Perception and conceptualization are processes, of both physiological and mental nature, peculiar to the individual; but the geographer is a trained individual and can give meaning to the areal variations at appropriately selected scales. Geographers have used the term, scale, with several meanings. Map scale is the most common and best understood. However, there are other scales necessary for the measure of areal variation. In this respect, it is frequently necessary for a special scale to be devised for the individual research problem. Geographers have also employed the term, scale, with the connotation of area, and to refer to a point on a scale. The important thing is that the scale measures what it says that it will measure, and that it is not in violation of the isomorphism between the real objects and the number system. It is also important that subsequent mathematical operations performed upon measured quantities, be in accord with the order of the scale (nominal, ordinal, interval, or ratio), with which their measure has been determined. In geography, it is clear that the term scale means measurement, and more specifically, the preciseness of measurement. There is also a need to distinguish between generalization and measurement, as the former belongs to hypothesis and theory, and the latter to empirical observation. The selection of scale for a particular geographic research problem, might be thought of as a position of observation within a cone, inverted over the study area (cone of resolution). The choice of scale available is almost infinite, and the geographer has to rely on intuition and experience for selection. Actually he works at multi-scale considerations, being governed by data sources and the nature of his problem. Examination of current research articles reveals that most geographic research is being conducted at small scales (65 percent) while only 6 percent is at large scale. In aerial photo interpretation scale plays an important part in resolution, detection, and identification, but the mechanical systems and physical conditions involved are the governing factors. Thematic and special purpose mapping have extreme scale considerations center around the expression of areal data as point data. This is basically a matter of the extent to which one wishes to conceptualize or think abstractly, but concept cannot continue to be built upon concept without eventual verification with reality.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55648</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Griffiths, Thomas M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1972_Doiron_Jr.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57890</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:35Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analysis Of Downstream Hydraulic Geometry In The Sangre De Cristo Range, Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wasserman, Adrian A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1990</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>218</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This research examines the influence of geomorphic processes on downstream hydraulic geometry relationships in the northern Sangre de Cristo Range, Colorado. Large calibre bed material delivered to stream channels by mass-wasting, past glacial and past glacio-fluvial processes profoundly affect stream dynamics and, therefore, downstream hydraulic geometry relationships.A total of 96 stations are measured: 32 mass-wasting deposits, 32 on till deposits and 32 on outwash deposits. Field measurements include channel cross-section measurements, slope and bed material size and roundness.Derived data include bankfull width, mean depth, mean velocity and discharge, and sorting. Data from topographic maps include elevation, drainage basin area and stream length. Downstream hydraulic geometry relationships are significantly related to bankfull discharge, but not to stream length. Bankfull mean depth has the highest rate of increase with bankfull discharge while bankfull width has the lowest rate of increase. Analysis of bed material at each station suggests the following characteristics. First, sorting and roundness are significantly related to stream length but not to bankfull discharge. Second, particle size is generally significantly stream length. Finally, the coarsest fraction immobile at bankfull stage. Downstream hydraulic geometry relationships are better explained by the addition of a particle size variable. In general, d gs exerts the greatest influence on these relationships. Bankfull width consistently increases with particle size for all groups examined. Bankfull mean depth increases and bankfull mean velocity decreases with particle size for streams flowing over mass-wasting deposits and till deposits. As particle size increases, so does protrusion with flow. Bed material characteristics are significantly different between material generated by mass-wasting, past glacial and past glacio-fluvial processes. Particle size is largest for mass-wasting generated material and smallest for outwash deposits. Outwash deposits are better sorted and more rounded compared to the other two groups. In conclusion, streams in the study area have only limited influence over their channels. Their effectiveness is governed by their competency to entrain large calibre bed material derived from mass-wasting, and past glacial processes.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57890</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Toy, Terrence J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1990_wasserman_merged.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Hadley, Richard F.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Longbrake, David B.</dc:contributor>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_54109</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:35Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Changing Commercial Patterns In Metropolitan Denver, Colorado 1960-1970</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Peterman, William A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Herold, Laurance C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>December 1971</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>255</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This investigation is designed as a study of the recent changes in the locational patterns of commercial activity in Metropolitan Denver, Colorado. Several commercial functions are chosen as being representative of the various &quot;levels&quot; and types of commercial activity. The time period chosen is between the census years 1960 and 1970. The study is placed in a central place framework and a simple definition of centrality is used. Employing an analogy of physical &quot;sources&quot; and &quot;sinks&quot; a central place is said to be an area in which there is an excess of goods or services available to the population in that area. In a similar manner a non-central place is an area in which there is a deficit of goods or services available. By relating the number of facilities of a function to population through a simple formula, the degree of centrality for the function and area can be determined. Using census tracts as the basic unit area centrality indices are computed for ten different functions for both 1960 and 1970. In addition all of the functions are combined to determine a set of overall centrality indices. By comparing indices by tract for both years the changes in centrality occurring during the ten year period are determined. Maps depicting all of the centrality computations as well as the ten year changes are presented and discussed. A considerable change in the locational pattern of commercial activity has occurred between 1960 and 1970. Along with the increasing importance of major outlying planned shopping centers there has been a decrease in the relative importance of major business arterials. The differences between the geographical patterns for &quot;low&quot; and &quot;high&quot; order functions are becoming fewer. This appears to be the result of an increasing centralization of commercial activity in several nodal areas spread throughout the urban area. Finally the study has allowed the development of a framework for depicting commercial growth and change. This framework, consisting of five stages, relates changing pat¬terns of commercial activity to population trends and is useful in describing the comprehensive patterns of commercial change in any urban area.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:54109</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1971_Peterman.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58115</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:35Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Colorado Migration and &quot;The Mobility Transition,&quot; 1955-1995.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dodge, Richard N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1999</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>335</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The spatial components of Colorado migration and population growth are examined for the 1955-1995 period using data from the Internal Revenue Service, Bureau of Census, and other sources. An analysis is made of relationships between population growth, natural increase, and migration, factors associated with interstate migration to Colorado, internal and external flows within metropolitan hierarchies, and economic and amenity variables. Statistical methods and spatial analysis by mapping are employed. Results are evaluated for conformance with migration theories including Ravenstein&apos;s laws, the gravity model, and especially Zelinsky&apos;s &quot;mobility transition hypothesis. The relationship between migration flows and patterns of urban growth is·discussed. Variations in net migration are found to be more important than variations in natural·increase in explaining variations in population growth. Sources of migrants to Colorado have shifted from the Midwest to the West and South. The gravity model factors, population and distance, are effective in explaining the volume of inmigration. There is a weak relationship between unemployment rates and net migration. Colorado&apos;s metropolitan areas and mountain resort towns serve as the main ports of entry for migrants from other states. Metropolitan size is unimportant in accounting for mig+atioq rate~ except within certain urban hie+archies. There is a slight downward movement within metropolitan hierarchies for external migrants, and a slight upward movement within Colorado. The Boyer and Savageau quality of life index is ineffective as a predictor of net migration direction. The recreational nature of counties and private/public land mix are seen as somewhat important for migrant destinations, but less so for internal migrants. Distance to specific portions of Colorado is the most important factor for migrants from different U.S. Census regions with some noted exceptions. Net flows of internal migrants are primarily directed toward suburban counties and some counties which are contiguous with metropolitan areas. Highest internal migration rates are intrametropolitan followed by intra-nonmetropolitan. The Zelinsky model still has utility, but should be viewed in the light of urban deconcentration.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58115</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Goetz, Andrew R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sullivan, Donald G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1999_Dodge.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Longbrake, David B.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Herold, Laurence</dc:contributor>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57355</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:35Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>County Land Use Planning: An Appraisal, with a Proposed Methodology For Evaluating Its Spatial Component</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Combs, Jr., Herbert Lee</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>September 1979</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>188</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Only in the past two or three decades has there been voiced any real sense of alarm arising from the extraordinary increase in population.In that same time period an increasing awareness of our nation&apos;s finite land space has been penetrating the minds of citizens and government officials. One consequence of this intensifying situation is the emergence of a group of professionals who desire to manage land use decisions in such a way as to present a balance between the numerous and often divergent uses of the finite land surface. These professionals are land use planners. As a result of several factors, state, county, and municipal governments have agencies of one sort or another which are charged with the responsibility for preparing comprehensive land use plans and, in some instances, for overseeing the proper functioning of the plans. These factors are numerous but one may cite federal initiatives in the form of legislation and financial incentives as examples and, at lower levels, the apparent competition for land use in the rural-urban arena. The inexorable growth of population with the expectable intensification of land use has prompted a concurrent—although somewhat tardy—evolution of comprehensive land use plans. The present stage in the evolution reflects a recognition of the scope and seriousness of the need for truly effective land use management. When one considers land use management, the concern is for planning the best use of land area; that is the spatial component.One notable shortcoming persists in the latest comprehensive plans; they include neither a procedure for evaluating the spatial component nor a stated intent to evaluate that critical component—particularly at the county level.If this is so, a methodology for evaluating the spatial component in county land use planning should be proposed.The problem and a purpose for this study emerge. In order to confirm the existence of the problem as initially perceived and to determine the planning milieu in which county governments are working, the planning background at the federal government level was examined as was that at the state level. The latter was accomplished through correspondence with planning agencies in each of the fifty states. In order to narrow the field to a manageable dimension, the planning and support documents of three counties in Colorado&apos;s north central area were carefully examined; i.e., those of Boulder, Larimer, and Weld Counties. Further information was obtained through field observation; visits to and conversations with planners of the three counties plus extensive correspondence. Through the study and investigation involved in this effort, it has been found that most states have provided authority and guidance to their counties to initiate and pursue land use planning. The extent to which counties have undertaken the tasks involved vary widely.This is true even among the three counties making up the study area for this paper. Comprehensive plans reflect to what extent land use pressures are perceived by the residents and officials of a county.They also reveal the degree of control that is to be exercised in managing land use decisions.Not surprisingly, the findings confirm the absence of a procedure to evaluate the spatial component in county land use plans.These findings are significant in that at this late date in the land management affairs of mankind, that management is still quite elemental in relation to the need.With the findings of this study available a methodology was proposed to evaluate the spatial component in county land use plans. The methodology includes a procedure which includes a detailed inventory of present land uses, a cyclic monitoring of the county area, steps which may be taken to rectify misuses, and a suggested means by which the effectiveness of the spatial component in plans may be evaluated. Some important conclusions emerge from this study. Now, late in the nineteenth century, some counties still have inadequate and in¬effective comprehensive plans. Even though some counties may have timely and sophisticated comprehensive plans for land use management, none specifically include a methodology for evaluating the effectiveness of any component of the plan.Finally, it is concluded that a new generation of county comprehensive land use plans is needed.The new plans must have as a specific objective woven into the fabric of the plan, the intention to evaluate the effectiveness of the spatial component of the plan, and a procedure whereby that intention can be effectuated.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57355</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Herold, Laurance C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1979_Combs.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58129</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:35Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Explaining Variability in the Colorado Student Assessment Program Scores: A Geographic Perspective</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Murphy, Lisa M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 2005</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>188</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The Colorado Student Assessment Program, or CSAP, is the Colorado standardized testing program that measures student progress in reading, writing, and mathematics for all public schools in the state of Colorado. The scores vary across the state between districts, neighborhoods, and schools. Is there any pattern to this variation in scores? Is there one primary factor that explains this variation? At which scale are factors most significant? This project uses GIS to map the CSAP results and to correlate CSAP scores with neighborhood demographic variables such as income, race, educational attainment, as well as school related variables such as teacher salary and percent free lunch. The hypothesis that school scores are influenced by the characteristics defining the neighborhoods in which the students live challenges the theory that educational success is independent of these social factors. The most explanatory variable used in the analyses was percent free lunch. The higher the percentage of students that qualify for free lunch in a school, the lower the average CSAP scores for that grade at all scales of analyses. The school scale provided the strongest correlations between the CSAP scores and percent free lunch.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58129</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Sutton, Paul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2005_Murphy.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55709</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:36Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Geographic Research From Earth Orbit with Special Emphasis on Land Use</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paludan, Charles Theodore Naftel</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>August 1975</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>164</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>A thesis is proposed to show that the availability of repetitive observations from satellites yields information of significant benefit to the study of geography. A specific example of land-use survey of a selected test site is used to test the thesis. Data from the satellite LANDSAT-1, from aircraft at very high and medium altitudes, and from ground survey are used in the test experiment. Validation of the thesis statement requires definition of the terms, &quot;benefit&quot; and &quot;significant.&quot; This is accomplished by reference to published information needs of selected geographers. A set of five needs is extracted: (1) develop new approaches and ways of measuring interrelationships, (2) attempt to study all significant phenomena in an area, (3) include temporal data, (4) study human/nature relationships, and (5) determine areal distributions and pattern associations. The thesis is placed in historical perspective by discussion of the importance of reflective observation in past geographical discoveries. It is shown that the rapid traverse studies which began forty years ago are analogous to observations from spacecraft. Design of the test experiment in land-use survey establishes the rationale of the experiment, selects the test site in Madison County, Alabama, establishes objectives and limitations, and out-line tests to determine if objectives are met. Technical details of factors affecting conduct of the experiment are given. These include resolution limits, data gathering, observation modes, and the land-use classification system. Conduct of the experiment is described, and in the analysis of data a number of maps are produced. Using the maps as information products, the test are applied to show that experimental objectives were met. The results are stated in terms of questions raised by the thesis; the five information needs are each examined relative to the experiment findings, for example. The success of the study in confirmation of the thesis is shown. Important findings, unanswered questions, conclusions, and recommendations complete the report.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55709</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1975_Paludan.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57845</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:36Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>High Plains Depressions in Eastern Colorado: Distribution, Classification, and Genesis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Walker, Graham Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1985 </dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>293</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Closed topographic depressions are widespread across the Colorado Plains with maximum densities in areas of fixed Quaternary sand dunes. A purposive sample of 548 depressions selected from maps of the 1° x 2° and 7.5-minute topographic series was described by five variables measuring the bipolar attributes elongate-circular, compact-irregular, shallow-deep, small-large, and simple-complex. Submission of the resulting data matrix to a hierarchical clustering algorithm discriminated the main genetic classes already identified subjectively, although with some misallocation. The analysis gave no new genetic insights and split some natural groupings that span a morphological continuum but share a common genesis. These limitations reflect deficiencies in specifying the morphological diversity of the sample as well as the mechanical nature of numerical classification procedures. Most sample depressions are primary or secondary eolian forms, ranging from small, regular depositional hollows on sand and loess, through deeper, more elongate blowouts, to large and highly irregular features comprising coalescent interdune flats and corridors. The largest features are found across early Pleistocene pediments undergoing dissection by north-bank tributaries of the South Platte and Arkansas Rivers and preserved by beheading of the pediment drainage. They result from solution-subsidence associated with Permian evaporites and from eolian disruption of broad shallow valleys comprising the original pediment drainage. Smaller stellate forms in central Washington County result from disruption of the incised High Plains drainage by loess drifts.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57845</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Griffiths, Thomas M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1985_Walker.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57357</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:37Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Mass Movements Resulting From Intense Rainfall, Douglas County, Colorado: A Morphometric Analysis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kuhaida Jr., Andrew Jerome</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>May 1980</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>216</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>On June 16, 1965, intense rainfall triggered numerous mass movements in Douglas County, Colorado.The purpose of this study was to examine these mass movements and determine the:(1) spatial distribution, (2) specific form and type, (3) contributing environmental factors, and (4) potential hazardous areas.Geometric and environmental field measurements were made on 45 scars.Geometric form measurements were used as the basis for the development of morphometric indices. The indices used were:depth (head)/length, depth (head)/width (source area), width (source area)/ length (source area), depth (head)/depth (side), depth (head)/total length of scar, length (source area)/total length of scar, width of transport zone/width (source area), shape, and volume.Correlation analysis was used to identify relations among the morphometric indices. Cluster analysis was used to identify groups of scars with similar morphometric characteristics. Each group of scars was then examined to identify environmental factors and hazard potential.Results of correlation analysis indicated two statistically significant relationships. Negative correlations exist between: (1) L/Lt and wc/W, and (2) D/Lt and wc/W. Both of these relationships suggest an association between the morphometry of the scars and the flow characteristics of the moving mass. In effect, channelization is related to both the displacement and volume of material from the source area. A long, narrow scar is produced by a moving viscous mass following existing drainageways downslope. With cluster analysis, four groups of scars were obtained that share similar morphometric characteristics. Group 1 was characterized by high L/Lt index values which suggested that sliding was the initial type of movement from the source area.Group 2 contained only one scar and was subsequently excluded from further analysis. Group 3 included scars with low values for the D/Lt index, suggesting that flowage was the operating process as material moved from the source area. Group 4 was comprised of scars exhibiting high values for the D/Ds index.This suggests rotational movement (slumping) of material within the source area. With each group, the material was apparently transformed into a flow as it moved through the transport zone. Environmental factors examined included topography, surface materials, and vegetation. A majority of the 45 scars were located on slopes with a northwest to northeast orientation. The only two associations observed between surface materials and types of movement occurred with groups 1 and 4. The scars in group 1 (slides) had a shear surface of gravelly-sand underlain by a distinct clay layer. Sixty percent of the scars in group 4 (slumps) occurred in surficial material thicker than five feet. No association between vegetation type or ground cover was observed.A hierarchy of hazardous areas for this type of mass movements was recognized.All areas beneath mesas and buttes possess some hazard, including the gently inclined areas at the base of the slopes. The next most hazardous locations include areas adjacent to drainage-ways at the base of slopes.At such locations, the greater the relief between the slope base and upland surfaces, the more extensive is the potentially affected area.The most hazardous situation occurs in those areas near the base of a north-facing slope and adjacent to drainageways.From this study, it can be concluded that a morphometric examination of mass movements has significant potential as a method of analyses for mass movements. Types of movement, factors contributing to movement and potentially affected areas can be suggested. However, more work is needed with various types of movements and in other locations before the full potential can be established.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57357</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Herold, Laurance C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1980_Kuhaida.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58128</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:37Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Measuring the Affordability of Rental Housing in Large Metropolitan Areas of the Western United States</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lopez, Hilary</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 2005</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>220</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The research presented in this paper seeks to further explore the spatial dimensions of affordable rental housing shortages in the western United States by examining the degree to which a shortage of affordable rental housing exists in Los Angeles-Long Beach, California; Phoenix-Mesa, Arizona; Portland-Vancouver, Oregon-Washington; San Diego, California; and San Francisco- Oakland, California. Following Nelson, American Housing Survey metropolitan area micro- data is used to quantify the number of affordable rental housing units relative to the number of renter households within defined income strata to answer the following questions: what is the estimated shortage of affordable rental housing for extremely low income, very low income, and low income households in the study areas; how have the shortages of affordable rental housing changed in these metropolitan areas over time; how do the estimates vary between metropolitan areas; what do these results imply about the housing opportunities facing these populations; and how well do regional estimates•approximate the magnitude of shortages of affordable rental housing for extremely low, very low, and low income renters in the metropolitan areas studied? The results indicate that the affordable rental housing shortage is most severe in the tight southern Californian housing markets due to the acute shortage of units for extremely low income households and very low income renters. The analysis also revealed that shortages of affordable rental housing are worsening in Portland-Vancouver and Phoenix-Mesa. Further, the metro areas displayed different results in terms of whether shortages were more or less severe in their central cities over suburbs and in terms of the lower in some populations impacted. Using logistic regression, it was also shown that in San Diego extremely low income renters have a higher likelihood of occupying affordable rental housing if they receive some form of rental assistance</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58128</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Goetz, Andrew</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2005_Lopez.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57846</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:37Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Scale Problems in Geographic Research</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Doiron, Jr., Claude J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>August 1971</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>192</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The great size of the earth and the many geographical elements upon it require that geographic research utilize a reductionism that demands comprehensive considerations of scale. These elements compose a range of geographical focus within the experience of man, and in keeping with the processes of nature. The geographer has no laboratory in the manner of other scientists, but must rely on the map, and more recently upon remote sensors, as a means of making portions of the landscape amenable for study. These also supplement his field work, which is affected by the dimensions of the landscape, and his limited powers of observation. Geography is a science of areal variation which requires extensive study of area. Man&apos;s perception and conceptualization of area have important implications of scale. In field work, the geographer operates at a scale of reality (1:1). The sources with which he supplements field work are at various scales. Perception and conceptualization are processes, of both physiological and mental nature, peculiar to the individual; but the geographer is a trained individual and can give meaning to the areal variations at appropriately selected scales. Geographers have used the term, scale, with several meanings. Map scale is the most common and best understood. However, there are other scales necessary for the measurement of areal variation. In this respect, it is frequently necessary for a special scale to be devised for the individual research problem. Geographers have also employed the term, scale, with the connotation of area, and to refer to a point on a scale. The important thing is that the scale measures what it says that it will measure, and that it is not in violation of the isomorphism between the real objects and the number system. It is also important that subsequent mathematical operations performed upon measured quantities, be in accord with the order of the scale(nominal, ordinal, interval, or ratio), with which their measure has been determined. In geography, it is clear that the term scale means measurement, and more specifically, the preciseness of measurement. There is also a need to distinguish between generalization and measurement, as the former belongs to hypothesis and theory, and the latter to empirical observation. The selection of scale for a particular geographic research problem, might be thought of as a position of observation within a cone, inverted over the study area (cone of resolution). The choice of scale available is almost infinite, and the geographer has to rely on intuition and experience for selection. Actually he works at multiscale considerations, being governed by data sources and the nature of his problem. Examination of current research articles reveals that most geographic research is being conducted at small scales(63%) while only 8% is at large scale. In aerial photo interpretation scale plays an important part in resolution, detection, and identification, but the mechanical systems and physical conditions involved are the governing factors. Thematic and special purpose mapping have extreme scale considerations centered around the expression of areal data as point data. This is basically a matter of the extent to which one wishes to conceptualize or think abstractly, but concept cannot continue to be built upon concept without eventual verification with reality.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57846</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Griffiths, Thomas M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1971_Doiron.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_54108</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:37Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Settlement Pattern Changes And Self-Organizing Systems In The Central Rio-Grande Watershed Of New Mexico A.D. 1350-1968</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dyreson, Delmar A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>July 1971</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>361</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The distributions of settlements in the Rio Grande Valley of Central New Mexico are studied over the period A.D. 1350 to 1968. The first phase of the investigation is concerned with the historical geography of the settle¬ment changes. Historic records, archaeological evidence, maps and documents are studied to obtain the required information. Settlement maps are then constructed indicating the locations of settlements at various points in time. The quantitative phase of the investigation involves the analysis of the settlement maps. Medvedkov analysis and self-organizing system analysis are employed. Finally the quantitative results and historical geography of the study area are combined for the assessment of settlement pattern changes. While Medvedkov analysis may be useful in some geographic areas, the results of the present study indi¬cate that the method is not universally applicable. To overcome the inadequacies of Medvedkov analysis, the statistical information theory concept of redundancy was tested in the study area and results were compared with samples from outside the area. With empirical modifi¬cation of the Maximum entropy function, the use of redun¬dancy makes possible the measurement of system order in the study area where Medvedkov analysis proved inadequate. It is a natural step to move from the use of redundancy as a static measure of order to the dynamic redundancy rate of change and the associated concept of a self-organizing system. The settlement distributions in this heterogeneous geographical area are characterized by almost continuous change. The fluctuations in the self-organizing system parameter have a sinusoidal character with an average period of approximately 50 years and a non-constant amplitude. There is no indication that a steady or equilibrium condition is attained at any time in the study area. Dacey&apos;s Iowa data was also tested using self-organizing system analysis, and it was found that there were greater settlement distribution fluctuations toward the end of the time sequence than at the beginning. The following factors were noted as being associ¬ated with discernible patterns in the self-organizing system analysis: rapid population increase, steady population loss, spatial expansion and spatial contraction of settlement zone perimeters, out-migration, rural to urban migration, influence of the mission system, and advent of the railroads. Settlement maps and computer program are included in appendixes.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:54108</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1971_Dyreson.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55649</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:37Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Spatial Patterns and Neighborhood Awareness: A Study in Geographic Perception</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Cohen, Steven H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1973</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:format>198</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Cities are presently considered as huge, confusing and impersonal regions by the majority of urban residents in the United States. However, in our society, people have developed a means of spatial ordering centered about themselves that permits orientation and adjustment to urban living. The average person, in discussing his daily movements, generally refers to the urban area in terms of decreasing certainty and increasing suspicion as he mentally moves outward from his home. Of primary importance to geographers has been the research in perception of the urban area by residents and their resultant “mental” images. This study explored a means of measuring and examining the patterns of urban perception. The secondary objective of this investigation was the exploration of utilizing perception measurements in the city-planning process. Four neighborhoods in Denver, Colorado were chosen for use in the study. Each area encompassed differing formal planning and political units and were given special reference titles. They were: 1) Westside-a predominantly Chicano area located near the Central Business District, 2) Bear valley – an entirely White area in southwest Denver, 3) SE Denver – an almost entirely White area in the south-eastern part of the City and 4) Park Hill- an integrated Black-Anglo area in northeast Denver. Residents in the four neighborhoods were randomly selected and interviewed at home. The interviews conducted housing preference, landmark identification, and mobility. During the interviews respondents were requested to rate eighteen examples of housing by comfort. The results were then sorted according to four parameters: 1) Size, 2) Greenery, 3) Density and 4) Styel. Respondents were also requested to identify four landmarks unique to their neighborhood and twelve sites common to all four areas. Last, each person interviewed was requested to complete a trip matrix indication the frequency with which various regional shopping and recreation sites are visited. The analyses of survey data indicated that although all parameters were used to some degree by each neighborhood in stratifying housing by comfort, the greatest stratification between neighborhoods occurred in the use of Size. According to the sample data, there was a direct relationship between the affluence of a neighborhood and the number of residents who stratified housing preference by Size. The study also found that residents used different landmark symbols in site identification. The symbol choice became more regional in scope with increasing distance from the respondent’s home to the site. Also, in moving about their homes, the residents used one localized site for convenience shopping and about two sites, in different directions from the home, outside the immediate neighborhood for specialized shopping.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55649</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1973_Cohen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55707</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:38Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Studies on the Fluvial Environment Arctic Coastal Plain Province, Northern Alaska</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lewellen, Robert Irl</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>August 1974</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>204</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Basic research on the Arctic fluvial environments has been presented. The arctic fluvial, although comparable in form to fluvial environments outside of the Arctic, is characterized by many unique processes. This is principally due to the fact that continuous permafrost underlies the Arctic Coastal Plain Province of Northern Alaska. Direct observations were made on the soils, permafrost, geomorphic processes, and general characteristics of five sites. The first site is an area of polymorphic ground in wet tundra soils and represents the incipient fluvial environment. The second site is a small drainage basin with an open channel and considerable disturbance by man. The third site was a small basin with essentially no disturbance by man. The fourth site is a large drainage basin with a tortuous channel. The channel is representative of the tributaries in the larger basins in the Province. The principal conclusions are numerous but can be summarized as follows. Low centered polygons can act as reservoirs and prevent runoff. Water assists in thawing ice wedges and forming polygon troughs. The troughs overlying the ice wedges can be part of an integrated drainage system. The degree of soil moisture determines if water will flow off of areas of integrated drainage. Large amounts of rainfall can be accepted immediately by the upland soils, and no surface runoff can occur. Runoff occurs only from the saturated soils which are adjacent to the integrated channels. Chemical and sediment loads are low in basins in tundra covered channels. Man&apos;s activity can trigger and accelerate erosion. There is a general sequence of events, repeated annually, between Spring runoff and Fall freeze-up. The evaporation and transpiration appear to be in balance with precipitation. The discharge and sediment load during the Spring runoff are important in forming and maintaining the present geomorphic form. The material presented is significant because this information has not been available before. The information is needed in light of the expanding resource exploitation already underway in northern Alaska.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55707</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1974_Lewellen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57902</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:38Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Synoptic Associations of Exceptional Snowfall Seasons in New England</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hartley, Suzanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1996</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>177</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Seasonal snowfall in New England has exhibited wide variations over the last few decades, the underlying causes of which have not been identified. This research examines how interactions among the large-scale atmospheric circulation and associated sea-level pressure patterns, cyclonic activity and storm track preferences, and North Atlantic sea-surface temperatures contribute to exceptional winter snowfall totals in New England. Unrotated principal components analyses of winter (December-March) precipitation, temperature and snowfall at 27 stations across New England identified regional indices of these variables. Composite anomaly maps of 700-mb heights and sea-level pressure (over North America and adjacent regions of the Pacific and Atlantic Oceans) and western Atlantic sea-surface temperatures were generated for extreme-valued winters on each of the regional climate indices. Possible associations between the regional climatic indices and indices of the Pacific-North American (PNA), North Atlantic Oscillation (NAO) and Southern Oscillation (SOl) atmospheric patterns were explored by correlation and regression analysis. The climatic, atmospheric, and oceanic data fields were analyzed in a multivariate framework to identify dominant modes of joint variability. Finally, comparisons were made of pairs of winters with similar. seasonal temperature and precipitation, but dissimilar snowfall totals. High winter snowfall totals are associated with a meridional circulation regime, as indicated by a negative NAO index and negative 700-mb height anomalies over the eastern United States. Anomalously high surface pressure over northern Canada promotes advection of cold air into the region, and the preferred storm track is along or just to the south of the New England coast. Low winter snowfall totals are associated with no unique set of circumstances, but a positive NAO index and more zonal circulation is indicated, along with weaker high pressure over Canada, and a storm track over interior New England rather than along the coast. There is no direct association with the PNA index and only a weaklag association with the SOl is indicated. In extreme southern New England, high (low) winter snowfall totals are associated with negative (positive)sea-surface temperature anomalies along the Atlantic seaboard.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57902</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Keables, Michael J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1996_Hartley.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58113</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:38Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Synoptic Influences on Seasons of Exceptional Winter Precipitation in the Rocky Mountain Region</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Luchsinger, Deborah Anne</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1998</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>297</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The Rocky Mountain region presents a number of problems for climatologists and meteorologists seeking to analyze weather and climate trends. The complex terrain modifies atmospheric circulation patterns and can both initiate and alter storm systems. Frequency, intensity, and duration of storm events are in tum affected by upper atmospheric circulation patterns. This research examines relations between (1) the PNA teleconnection index, (2) upper atmospheric pressure patterns, (3) storm-track preferences, and (4) frequency of cyclonic activity during seasons of exceptional winter precipitation. Map pattern analysis of standardized winter season precipitation indices calculated for each climate division inthe Rocky Mountain region yield 6 anomalous winter patterns. Composite maps of the 500-mbar surface are classified to determine modes of synoptic feature variability during the winter seasons analyzed. The significance of cyclone frequencies and the PNA index on precipitation anomaly patterns are determined through regression of the cyclone frequency and PNA indices against both divisional and regional precipitation indices. Finally, dominant storm track patterns are analyzed with respect to the anomalous precipitation patterns identified. Above-average winter precipitation patterns in the Northern region are associated with a zonal circulation regime, as indicated by a negative PNA index value and a ridge-trough-ridge configuration in the 500-mbar surface. The anomalous flow regime established by this reverse PNA synoptic pattern increases the frequency of extratropical cyclones breaching the west coast, and shifts the mean storm track such that storms enter the mountainous divisions of Idaho, western Montana, and northwestern Wyoming with little impediment. Anomalous precipitation patterns in the Southern region show no statistical significance to the frequency of cyclonic activity. Meridional circulation, as indicated by a positive PNA index value and a trough-ridge-trough synoptic pattern are strongly associated with above-average precipitation regimes in the Southern region. The increase component of anomalous flow from the subtropical Pacific Ocean and the southward displacement of the mean storm track around the Aleutian low result in an increase in winter storm system dynamics, rather than an increased frequency of storm events.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58113</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Keables, Michael J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1998_Luchsinger.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_54139</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:38Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Morphology Of Slope Profiles: a Statistical Method To Critically Analyze the Slope Hypothesis Of Willeam M. Davis, Walther Penck, And Lester C. King</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Clark, Robert Owen</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1970</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>458</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The classical theory that stages in a fluvially-initiated cycle of erosion are marked by similar and well-defined slope configurations has been postulated by William M. Davis and Walther Penck. Lester C. King has offered a third interpretation of hillslope morphology and changes that occur with time. Although this “uniformitarian” approach to cyclical landform development continues to permeate the literature, its verity has been questioned by some students of hillslope evolution. The need for a definitive statement on the nature of valley-side profiles is therefore of fundamental concern to the science of geomorphology. The classical works of Davis, Penck, and King are reviewed in depth to present an unbiased appraisal of the three geomorphic theories. Recent studies on hillslope development are also presented to clarify the problems related to hillslope evolution. Statistical techniques were employed to test the validity of the classical geomorphic theories and are based on mathematical profile curves and regression models. These procedures were used to evaluate over 1,200 slopes selected at random from large-scale topographic maps of the western United States. Since the geomorphic concepts under investigation are theoretical, slope configurations that depict various stages of these cycles can be expressed as mathematical (or theoretical) curves. If it is assumed that the theories of Davis, Penck, and King are valid indicators of slope form throughout a physiographic region, it is then theoretically possible to predict the configurations of large numbers of slopes within the same region. On this basis slopes selected at random from “Test Areas” in the Pacific Mountains, the Intermontane Plateaus, and the Rocky Mountains were mathematically fitted with theoretical profiles representing the “mature” stages of the classical geomorphic theories. Regression equations for each theorist were computed from comparisons of actual and theoretical curves in the Test Areas and then used to predict profiles of randomly selected slopes in sixteen “Prediction Areas.” By statistically comparing the predicted forms with their actual counterparts, the reliability of each geomorphic theory can be tested. If the variance between these two sets of profiles is significantly large, it would be logical to conclude that such a geomorphic system is neither compatible with nor representative of one or more of the physiographic regions. Statistical analyses of the classical slope theories revealed that uniformitarian development is not an entirely valid concept for the western United States. Although results varied considerably among several theorists, the statistical findings were almost wholly negative. Mean deviation values derived from a comparison of actual and predicted declivities rarely dropped below 4 degrees; more often these values were as high as 6 or 7 degrees and even higher. The percentage variances between actual and predicted slopes were also largely negative for the five profile categories (convex, concave, convexo-concave, concavo-convex, and straight). The concavo-convex form was the only statistically significant and, hence, predictable profile. This profile was accurately predicted by King’s multiple-element model in the Pacific Mountains, Intermontane Plateaus, and Rocky Mountains with percentage variances of 1.8, 7.5, and 4.6, respectively. Although King’s multiple-element model was found to be a valid predictor of concavo-convex slopes, the three major profiles (convex, concave, and convexo-concave) were not representative of the Test and Prediction areas. The logical conclusion is that hillslopes are highly variable and reflect the vagaries of the environment; hence hillslopes cannot be categorized on the basis of rigid slope models.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:54139</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1970_Clark.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58118</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:39Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65308</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Spatial Impacts of Southwest Airlines on Air Traffic Patterns &amp; Pricing in the United States</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vowles, Timothy Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>November 2000</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>260</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The research conducted has three main components. The first component is an updating of the &quot;Southwest Effect&quot; as observed by Air Transport World (1998), Dresner, Lin, and Windle (1996), and Southwest (1999). This updating illustrates that when Southwest enters a market there is a significant increase in pass-engers carried in the majority of the markets and a significant decrease in the average fare paid by travelers in the markets examined. The second goal of this work demonstrates how Southwest Airlines has created a &quot;Wal...;MartEffect&quot; on surrounding airports when entering a market. While this &quot;Wal-Mart Effect&quot; is not a strong as the original &quot;Southwest Effect&quot;, the research shows that the carrier indeed has an effect on enplanements and fares especially in multi-airport regions. The final objective studied in this research is the effect of the airline in changing metropolitan linkages. The increase in passengers attributed to the Southwest Effect lead to movements within the hierarchies of the cities studied. One of the biggest movers was Baltimore, which saw an increase in ranking in almost all of the cases studied. There was a general increase in the rankings of Southwest served cities when compared to non-Southwest served airports. - This research shows that Southwest Airlines does indeed have a profound effect on both the number of passengers traveling between airports and the average fare the passenger pays. It also shows that the carrier has the ability to strengthen the interaction between two airports with the type of service that it provides.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58118</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Goetz, Andrew R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2000_Vowles.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63568</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T16:11:12Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A GLOBAL EDUCATION TRANSITION: COMPUTER SIMULATION OF ALTERNATIVE PATHS TO UNIVERSAL BASIC EDUCATION</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Irfan, Mohammod Taiyeb</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>As an acknowledgment of the critical role of education in realizing other development targets, the Millennium Development Goals (MDG) of the United Nations include education in a framework of development targets. The MDG targets for education include achieving universal primary education and gender parities in all levels of education by 2015.Recent global campaigns have added to the momentum of the rapid progress of educational expansion, which began in roughly the 1960s. Countries with universal or near universal participation and completion in elementary education have started to look beyond primary, towards free and compulsory basic education- education up to lower secondary- for all their citizens.This dissertation will explore the progress towards, and viability of, meeting current and potential global targets at various stages of basic education. It will answer questions such as: What path is the world on in terms of meeting the MDG goal of universal primary education? Which regions and countries are at risk of falling short of that target? How will lower-secondary education unfold in different regions of the world? Will there be any disparity between boys and girls as the countries expand their primary and lower-secondary education? What needs to be done to meet the current MDG for universal primary education and to move the global system towards universal lower secondary at the global, regional, and country level?To find the answers, we developed a long-term educational forecasting model that represents the student and financial flows through the different levels of a formal educational system from primary to tertiary. The model is integrated within the broader International Futures model and represents the economic and demographic forces shaping the supply and demand of education. The broader International Futures system models the impacts of education on societal variables like fertility, productivity, and income, thus creating a feedback loop.According to our analyses, most of the developing countries will continue their educational expansion at a speed faster than the speed that the developed countries showed when they were at a comparable stage of development. However, some of the developing regions will still be far away from universal participation or gender parity in primary and lower secondary, largely due to the low initial condition in these regions. 	Forecasts from the base case of our educational model show the pace of progress will not be sufficient to meet the education MDGs. Two of the world regions, sub-Saharan Africa and South and West Asia, might not be able to enroll all their children in elementary schools by 2015. These two and one other UNESCO region, the Arab States, do not see universal lower secondary education in the horizon even at 2020. In the base case, all UNESCO regions but two will reach or be close to gender parity in primary education by 2015. While the Arab States will be close to parity by 2030, the sub-Saharan African index will not reach parity until mid-century. Latin America and the Caribbean, on the other hand, might experience a reverse gender bias favored towards girls by 2015, but will re-approach parity later.Lowering population growth will lessen the demand pressure in these countries and thus help them achieve better rates of participation in basic education. A better economy will help them spend more on education and thus get better results.Exploration of the recent growth patterns in access to and progress in education convinced us that there is  room for some acceleration of the progress in these areas. We have combined these findings to develop an aggressive but realistic normative scenario, where growth targets in educational flow rates, rather than an absolute coverage, are pursued.Even with the improved results from the normative scenario, the world is unlikely to meet the 2015 MDG targets. However, the sub-Saharan African region, as a whole, would be sufficiently close to the target of universal primary education by 2020. All other regions meet the MDG of universal primary under the normative scenario, with South and West Asia just barely making it. Under the normative scenario, all but one world region, sub-Saharan Africa, reach 95 percent or higher gross participation rate in lower secondary by 2020. It is almost mid-century by the time sub-Saharan Africa reaches close to universal lower secondary.Substantial progress in terms of gender parity will occur under the normative scenario despite the goal being explicitly pursued under the normative scenario. As girls in developing regions catch up with boys these regions reach close to gender parity in primary education around 2015. By 2020, exact parity is obtained in all regions. While the reverse gender parity extant in regions like Latin America and the Caribbean will start to slide back starting in the 2020s, a similar reverse parity starts to show up in sub-Saharan Africa around that time.The transition to universal basic education is important for human development. It will take considerable time and efforts to complete the transition. While it is useful to coordinate the global efforts in making the transition, it is also important to take into account the differences across regions and nations in setting realistic targets and goalposts.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations--Educational Transition--Global Education Forecast--Millennium Development Goal--Universal Basic Education--Universal Lower Secondary Education--Universal Primary Education</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>313</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63568</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63568</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Hughes, Barry B.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hamilton, Sally</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Khan, Haider A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63159</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T16:14:33Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Rhetorical History of Academic Freedom from 1900 to 2006</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Margesson, Robert James</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Human Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This project engages ideographic analysis to trace the rhetorical history of academic freedom. Specifically, this project seeks to uncover how the mainstream press defined and reported on academic freedom over the course of a 100-year period that represents the birth and maturation of American higher education. It is argued throughout this project that mainstream representations of and challenges to academic freedom shape public sympathy toward higher education, the professoriate, and the American student body.Through analysis of controversial professors in the early-1900s, the attempts to purge communists and fellow-travelers from higher education during the red scare, and conservative challenges to the left&apos;s so-called stranglehold on higher education during the latter half of the 20th century, this project uncovers both the political and social implications of control over the meaning of academic freedom and the reasons why such a simple concept can have such important ramifications for higher education, free speech, and democracy. As a result of this analysis, this document argues that academic freedom is a constantly evolving yet important political construct that groups and individuals with, often time, contradictory goals wrestle over in hopes of controlling the hearts and minds of America&apos;s college and university students.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Speech Communication--Academic freedom; ideograph; free speech</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>227</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63159</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63159</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Hicks, Darrin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wood, Roy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Foust, Christina</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Dobyns, Ann</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63297</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T16:17:50Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A PASTORAL THEOLOGICAL APPROACH TO THE IMAGE OF GOD: TOWARD A FRAMEWORK FOR PASTORAL CARE OF BROKEN RELATIONSHIPS AMONG KOREAN AMERICAN CHRISTIANS AND THEIR COMMUNITY</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kim, Gichul</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Religious and Theological Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>In many Korean American ethnic churches, interpersonal conflicts cause suffering and often result in irrevocably broken relationships. Such suffering is exacerbated by pastoral responses that are individualistic and theologically inflexible. This dissertation asserts that interpersonal conflicts are symptomatic of a breakdown of relational systems - communal, societal, cultural and even ancestral - and theologically diagnoses broken relationships as a distorted actualization of the image of God.When the image of God is understood as a symbol rather than a static dogma orsign, it refers to a more relational and dynamic process of imaging God. This dissertation brings theological anthropology based on this interpretation of the image of God intodialogue with a traditional Korean anthropology of human between-ness and a self psychological understanding of human nature (using an object relations theory of personality) in order to construct a pastoral theology of the process of imaging God in theKorean American sociocultural context. Imaging God can be characterized as (1)fulfilling God&apos;s calling as human destiny by practicing the capacity for relationality communally and individually, (2) having relationships with God through genuine andauthentic interpersonal relationships, (3) being connected to ancestry as a way of reconnecting to one&apos;s familial and cultural roots and heritage, (4) building up genuine community through which persons enjoy a sense of security and belonging, (5)experiencing the relational space of human between-ness, and (6) respecting and celebrating the rich diversities in God&apos;s image-bearers and God&apos;s creatures. Pastoral care based on this understanding of the process of imaging God will foster healing and nurturing relationships. Pastoral caregivers can enhance the quality ofcommunal pastoral care by offering a relational atmosphere conducive to mutual sharing and empathy in their faith communities so that pastoral care can be mutually practicedamong the congregants. In a Korean American ecclesial context three major resources for practicing communal care are the class and band meetings, pastoral visitations, and the use of symbolism. These practices are used to illustrate ways in which the church canfind, create, and develop new resources of care that help communities engage in a processof imaging God.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Theology--Psychology, General--Religion, General--Pastoral Care; Pastoral Counseling; Pastoral Theology; Self Psychology; Korean Americans; Image of God</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>267</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63297</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63297</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Doehring, Carrie</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Jones, Arthur</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Graham, Larry K.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63252</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T16:20:45Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Adolescent Girls&apos; Support for Voice in Education</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kastelic, Diana</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Educational Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>ABSTRACT The high school experience plays a major role in the shaping of a confident woman. Because adolescence is a particularly challenging time, often the presentation of the self is not authentic and can be displayed differently depending on the context associated with a given role.  The loss of voice is particularly problematic for female adolescents. Prior to becoming adolescents, girls are able to express themselves with confidence. With the onset of adolescence, it is common for girls to suppress their feelings, cover up what they knew as young children, diminish themselves and suppress their voice. Margaret Mead, in describing what she observed across cultures said that so many gifts are unused and unappreciated for women in western culture. She observed that women&apos;s voices are stilled.This research, examines the support for girls&apos; voices in a high school setting in order to answer five questions: 1. In the school setting, in which area of an adolescent girl&apos;s life is she most likely to feel free to express her true opinions?2. In the school setting, is an adolescent girl&apos;s voice more likely to be stifled in some content areas and subject matter rather than in others? 3. In the school setting, what is the link between teacher&apos;s pedagogy and adolescent girls&apos; voices? 4. In the school setting, what is the link between teacher&apos;s behavior and students&apos; perceptions? 5. In the school setting, what interventions can be utilized by teachers to encourage adolescent girls to confidently express their opinions?This qualitative study employed the method of educational criticism. I viewed the lives of four students for three days each, attending all of their classes and extracurricular activities.  I also interviewed these students prior to the shadowing process and informally during the shadowing process.The study resulted in several important findings. First, the structural dimension of the school is critical to support for voice and student success.  Several aspects of the school&apos;s structure impact students expression of voice including: a healthy culture, strong leadership, an authentic social climate, respect for individuals, an organized, and safe physical environment, effective communication and an organized transition to life after high school. The second emergent theme is that pedagogy plays a major role in the shaping of confident young women. When pedagogy matters there is a strong emphasis on learning, teachers act as guides in the learning process, there is an emphasis on a high standard of excellence, teachers support voice with a safe, yet urgent classroom environment, thus developing confidence and competence in learning. A strong curriculum is the third theme, which includes diverse academic and extra-curricular offerings.  The three themes identified above were integrated into a Radar Chart of the School&apos;s Culture. The fourth theme emphasizes the girls&apos; intentions, i.e. what they expect from their schooling experience.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Administration--Education, Curriculum and Instruction--Education, Secondary--Voice; support for voice; pedagogy; curriculum; ecology of schooling; radar chart</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>251</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63252</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63252</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Uhrmacher, P. Bruce</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Waldbaum, Roberta</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>King, Edith</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Bonaker, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63240</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T16:36:17Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An Ethnographic and Philosophical Investigation into Patrol Officers: Communication Ethics as Critical Work</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ballard, Robert L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Human Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This ethnographic study explores the communication ethics of patrol officers in a large, metropolitan city. The researcher spent over 300 hours riding in a patrol car. The study is inductive, analyzing eighteen case studies on philosophical, interpretive, and critical levels. PART I: CROSSING OVER follows the researcher&apos;s introduction to the world of the police, including their hermeneutic of war and the &quot;Rider&apos;s Curse.&quot; It describes how observations were conducted and analyzes the gendered and linguistic performance of the researcher as ways to gain and maintain access.PART II: ETHICS introduces four &quot;ethical realities&quot; through a welfare check on a mother and her children. These four realities include yelling/verbal force, non-response/tangential response, monologue, and acknowledgment. They are based on the touchstones of safety, authoring/authority, control, and the need for human contact, respectively. These realities are explained and analyzed with philosophical perspectives on what ethics are, notably phenomenological and Levinasian views.PART III: CONTEXT expands this understanding of the interactions to consider how different relationships and voices (Bakhtin&apos;s concept of &quot;polyphony,&quot; 1984) construct and constitute interactions. Lateral relationships are analyzed through a &quot;narrative ethics&quot; (Newton, 1995) of how officers tell stories to each other. Line (top-down) relationships reveal the phenomenological presence of the law and supervisors. The stress and danger of patrol officer interactions are explored. The idea of the &quot;holistic moment&quot; is proposed as a way to describe the multi-layered nature and ethical complexity of an interaction.PART IV: CRITICAL takes a critical turn. Following Althusser&apos;s (1991) &quot;interpellation&quot; of subjects, the study interrogates the researcher, the officers, and society. The researcher&apos;s behavior demonstrates the pervasiveness of the ideology of the police world in regards to race, gender, sexuality, and power and &quot;normalizes&quot; unethical forms of communication. The officers&apos; use of &quot;war&quot; as the dominant way to communicate is interrogated, especially during &quot;social work&quot;-type interactions. Society is interrogated for its complicity in reproducing the &quot;war&quot;-type interactions officers are constructed into. The study concludes by positioning communication ethics as critical work and offers Levinas as a way to simultaneously critique, empower, and emancipate concrete subjects.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Speech Communication--Communication ethics; patrol officers; police; ethnography; critical; Levinas; fitting response</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>411</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63240</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63240</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Wood, Roy V.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lair, Dan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Foust, Christina</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hicks, Darrin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Manning, Susan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63349</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T17:21:53Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>AN EXAMINATION OF STUDENT ACADEMIC REVIEW PLUS (STARplus): A PROGRAM FOR ACADEMIC AND BEHAVIOR REVIEW IN SCHOOLS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bye, Kathleen A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Educational Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This study assessed how leadership, teachers, and students at the building level utilized and experienced the processes of a school-reform model, STARplus, during the first year of implementation. The research also examined the effect of the STARplus processes on student academic performance in reading, mathematics and behavior as measured by district and state assessments, suspension referral data, classroom observation, and student perception.The study was a case study using mixed methodology. A concurrent nested model (Creswell, 2003) was the overarching research design. According to Creswell, this type of model offers the researcher an opportunity to collect both qualitative and quantitative data at the same time while giving emphasis to one type of data.In this study, the qualitative method was dominant, with information specific to perceptions and utilization of practices identified within the STARplus model collected during observations, surveys, and interviews of leadership and teachers in the school setting. The quantitative data was nested or embedded within the qualitative data. The information gathered was specific to gaining an understanding of how school leadership and teachers utilized STARplus through three levels: (a) teacher and leadership experiences during STARplus review sessions; (b) teacher and leadership perceptions of practices; and (c) student perception and performance.Results indicated that school leadership and teacher responses to the practices of STARplus were positive overall. Results of the study were examined by all implementing classrooms (N = 8) along with high (n = 3) and low (n = 5) implementing classrooms. Evidenced through the review meetings, surveys, and focus groups were (1) a focus on student learning; (2) ongoing attention to student behavior; (3) feedback and reflection emerging as crucial to success; and (4) collaborative practices resulting in capacity building. Results of the study suggested that student academic performance in reading and mathematics was significantly higher in all participating classrooms according to results of district assessments. While state assessments in reading and mathematics indicated overall growth when examining student scale scores of matched students, results were not significantly higher. Student suspension referrals did not decrease, but were significantly fewer in the classrooms of high-implementation teachers.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Curriculum and Instruction--Education, Elementary--Education, Administration--School reform; collaborative practices; leadership; behavior; portfolio; implementation</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>224</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63349</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63349</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Katz, Elinor</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Tombari, Martin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Steiner, Ellen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Burke, Ray</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63247</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T17:25:34Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An Examination of the Transformational Leadership Behaviors of Female Head Coaches and Satisfaction with Team Performance in Division I Intercollegiate Women&apos;s Soccer Teams: The Mediating Role of Cohesion</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hall, Misty Dawn</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Counseling Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The current study represents the first attempt to assess the transformational leadership behaviors of female sport coaches and how those behaviors relate to performance and cohesion.  Fifty-one Division I female head soccer coaches at institutions sponsored by the National Collegiate Athletic Association were contacted.  The response rate for the study was 68%, with 15 of the coaches not responding to phone messages about participation in the study.  A total of 30 female head soccer coaches and 451 female soccer student-athletes completed surveys.  Coaches completed a demographic information form and a measure that assessed transformational leadership behaviors.  Student-athletes completed a demographic information form, and three measures that assessed transformational leadership, cohesion, and satisfaction with performance.  Results revealed that transformational leadership positively predicted team cohesion and satisfaction with performance and that cohesion significantly meditated the relationship between transformational leadership and satisfaction with performance.  Also suggested from the results is that as the discrepancy between student-athlete ratings of coach leadership and coach self-ratings of leadership decreased, performance increased.  Lastly, findings from this study show that task cohesion has a stronger relationship with satisfaction with performance than social cohesion.  The results of this study suggest that transformational leadership is likely to help sport coaches to lead in an effective, satisfying way while increasing levels of cohesion and performance within their teams.   The practical implications of these findings are addressed.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Women&apos;s Studies--Transformational Leadership; Leadership in Sport; Cohesion; Performance; Women&apos;s Leadership; Group Dynamics in Sport</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>167</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63247</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63247</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Riva, Maria</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McIntosh, Daniel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Portenga, Steven</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63155</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T17:28:26Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analysis of Stakeholder Perceptions of Education Reform in Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Woempner, Carolyn L</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Educational Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>April 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Author: Carolyn L. Woempner Title: ANALYSIS OF STAKEHOLDER PERCEPTIONS OF EDUCATION REFORM IN COLORADO Advisor: Dr. Ellen Bennett Steiner Degree Date: March 2008  ABSTRACT  The development of successful public policy is dependent on an understanding of public perceptions of existing or anticipated public problems and of acceptable solutions to those problems. This study used the Policy Delphi method to solicit and analyze the perceptions of geographically and demographically diverse stakeholders across the state about education reform in Colorado, focusing on Goals of education, Strategies to achieve goals, and Barriers that stand in the way. Results indicated that stakeholders in Colorado perceive a lack of support for education at the legislative, social, professional, and financial levels. Additionally, respondents were clear that post-high school preparation must emphasize both work-readiness and college-readiness and students must be treated as individuals within the education system. The development of critical thinking and problem solving skills was seen as essential in instructional reform, which may be hindered by the current emphasis on standardized testing. These findings indicate that the development of public policy in education should first focus on building foundational support before specific functional or structural reforms, and illustrate the priorities held by the public in terms of public policy and education reform, i.e. post-secondary preparation in many forms, individual rather than uniform instruction and program design for students, and development of critical thinking and problem solving skills. These findings are useful to clarify policy issues and inform the development of effective and palatable public policy around education reform in Colorado.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Administration--Education policy; policy research; Policy Delphi; Colorado; education policy research</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>154</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63155</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63155</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Bennett Steiner, Ellen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Katz, Elinor</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Seeley, Ken</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63047</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T17:31:01Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analytical Studies of Sorption Phenomena for Nitrogen Heterocycles</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Caulfield, Jeffrey Alan</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Chemistry and Biochemistry</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This work investigated sorption of nitrogen heterocycles with applications relevant to environmental sampling and explosives detection.  Despite having a high water solubility (21 g/L), caffeine adsorption on some clay minerals and sediments was found to be significant.  This was an important observation pertaining to caffeine&apos;s use as an anthropogenic marker.  Caffeine adsorption was measured on natural sediments and a series of homoionic montmorillonites.  Kd values were determined on each of the sorbents in the pH range of 6.7 to 8.7.  The Kd values ranged from &lt; 0.7 to 150 (+/- 8) L/kg for the natural sediments and 290 (+/- 6) to 4.0 x 105 (+/- 1.5 x 105) L/kg for the homoionic montmorillonites.  Infrared methods and molecular modeling were used to demonstrate three different adsorption mechanisms for caffeine binding to the montmorillonites.  The adsorption mechanism and Kd values were highly dependent on the exchangeable cation at the mineral surface.To obtain quality FTIR spectra for the caffeine study, a novel method for the analysis of clay minerals using Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy was developed.  Clay mineral suspensions were dried on a Si wafer substrate for transmission IR analysis.  Four natural source clays, SWy2, SAz1, SHCa1 and KGa1b, as well as the synthetic hectorite, Laponite RD, were analyzed using the described method.  Signal to noise (s/n) ratios in excess of 100,000 for the strongly absorbing Si-O stretching frequency were obtained.  IR spectra were generated and peak locations were compared to previously reported values generated from KBr pellet and ATR methods.Gas chromatography was used to determine the enthalpy of solution, ΔHSol, for a series of nitroaromatic explosives and explosive degradation products.  Five stationary phases of various polarities, ranging from dimethylsiloxane to polyethylene glycol, were evaluated with 13 nitroaromatic compounds.  Isothermal Kováts retention indices are also reported for the nitroaromatics as well as the ΔHSol of several n-alkanes.  A model encompassing the 13 nitroaromatics on 5 stationary phases is presented that predicts ΔHSol for nitroaromatics in polymeric materials when McReynolds constants are available for the polymer.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Chemistry, Analytical</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>308</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63047</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63047</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Miller, Keith E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sullivan, Donald G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kutateladze, Andrei G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Smith, Dwight M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Stedman, Donald H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63182</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T17:33:52Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Beyond Sunday Mornings: The Influence of Church-based Programs on the Everyday Lives of Urban African American Youth</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Groff, Regina C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Curriculum and Instruction</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This study examined the influence of youth-centered church-based programs on the everyday lives of African American urban youth in two African American Colorado churches. The study revealed that the youth who participate in youth-centered church-based programs are influenced positively by them when strong leadership, relevant curriculum, and meaningful relationships are present.This study has been framed by a review of the literature that reveals that youth who are involved in church activities are less likely to become involved in deviant behavior. Furthermore, they have the capacity to overcome stressful situations and to bounce back in the aftermath of adversity. The literature also suggests that churches, parents, and schools who serve African American children can positively influence their behaviors through mentoring, family support, and strong leadership that encourage leadership and spiritual development.Research on this topic is limited, but is gradually increasing. Most research regarding the influence of church-based youth programs on African American children has surfaced in the last 15 years, with the majority being in the last 5-10 years. This increased interest may be attributed to the increased level of suicides, teenage pregnancies, drugs, violence, and other forms of &quot;at risk&quot; behaviors that exist within the African American youth population.This study contributes to the growing body of literature by describing the influence of effective church-based youth programs on today&apos;s urban African American youth. Specifically, the findings provide best practices that have positively influenced the everyday lives of urban African American youth.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Curriculum and Instruction--Black; Church; Youth Ministry;</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>206</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63182</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63182</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Cutforth, Nicholas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Uhrmacher, Bruce</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McCrae, Cyndy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Jones, Arthur</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Fry Brown, Teresa L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63530</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T17:39:03Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Caribbean-China Relations: Foreign Policy and Small State Economic Adjustment</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Morris, Dana Marie</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>In recent years the relationship between Caribbean states and China has intensified. This dissertation argues that the Caribbean&apos;s increased engagement with China is an important component of their economic adjustment strategy that was necessitated after changes in the orientation of the international economic system that they must operate within, particularly in relation to the loss of trade preferences and the sharp decline in official development assistance.Despite the seemingly homogenous nature of these Caribbean states there is in fact significant foreign policy variation seen vis-à-vis engagement with China. Some Caribbean states have consistently recognized China, while others have vacillated between recognition of China and Taiwan. The source of this variation lies in differences in endowment of resources that are of strategic importance to China. The more resource-endowed countries demonstrate more foreign policy consistency while the resource-poor countries have exhibited a less consistent foreign policy towards China.The dissertation also explores the extent to which the relationship with China is beneficial for these states. It will be shown that despite the lack of explicit conditionalities accompanying Chinese aid and loans, there are important implicit conditionalities such as the awarding of contracts to Chinese firms and the importation of Chinese laborers that thwart the potential benefits accruing to Caribbean states from this relationship with China.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations--Caribbean foreign policy--Chinese foreign policy--Small states</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>288</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63530</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63530</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Grabel, Ilene</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Zhao, Suisheng</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Epstein, Rachel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63225</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T18:03:44Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Case study of parents&apos; perceptions of an initial problem solving meeting</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Harrison, Eleanor</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Child, Family &amp; School Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>ABSTRACT The purpose of this study was to describe and interpret the perspectives of parents who were made aware that their child was struggling academically or behaviorally and was being referred to a problem-solving team in a neighborhood public school.  Using a multiple case study design, five parents were observed in an initial school problem-solving meeting and interviewed before and after the meeting to better understand the parents&apos; roles in and perspectives of the process.  The meeting was audiotaped, transcribed, and coded to provide information about the team process and team member roles.Results indicated parents were very satisfied with the meeting itself despite having some confusion about the process and the outcome.  Parents had few expectations upon entering the meeting and were unsure of what roles they would play in the meeting.  Despite their initial apprehension, parents talked openly in the meetings and were active members.  An analysis of the team found that the team had an effective facilitator and members who were very positive, responsive, and friendly to parents and created an atmosphere in which parents felt respected.  Team members also treated parents as experts on their child and actively solicited their input in the meeting.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Educational Psychology</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>152</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63225</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63225</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Hazel, Cynthia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Miler, Gloria</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cutforth, Nick</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salters, Rogers</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62942</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T18:08:10Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Chameleon on the Court: Understanding Factors that Contribute to Visibility/Invisibility for Division I Intercollegiate Gay Athletes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tontz, Paul Andrew</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Higher Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Although gay athletes are definitely a part of the current composition of Division I athletics teams, few studies address this particular population.  Further no study has reported the factors that support visibility/invisibility for this population of students.  This qualitative phenomenological study explored the question: What factors contribute to the visibility/invisibility of Division I gay male collegiate athletes? The purpose of this study was to disclose those internal and external factors that may contribute to whether a gay athlete passes as heterosexual or conceals his identity?  Further, this study also sought to understand the outcomes of visibility and the ways higher educational institutions can make gay athletes feel more included.I conducted a series of three interviews with each of the eight participants.  I focused on their life histories surrounding sport and self-identification as gay, their current experience being visible/invisible to their team and coaches, and their reflection on the meaning of being both gay and an athlete within Division I athletics.  Using the most compelling quotes from interviews I then constructed unique profiles reflecting their background.I used Colaizzi&apos;s (1978) approach for analyzing data.  The analysis included the extraction of significant meanings related to the phenomena, clustering the data into themes, an exhaustive description of the phenomenon, and finally an unequivocal statement expressing the essence of the phenomenon.  Data was collapsed into four themes: internal factors of invisibility/visibility, external factors of invisibility/visibility, the gay athlete acceptance continuum, and the costs and benefits of invisibility/visibility.  Factors reflect an updated model of Clair, Beatty, and Maclean&apos;s (2005) conceptual model of the decision to pass or reveal one&apos;s identity.Most importantly this research makes suggestions for the higher educational community, including faculty, staff, coaches, athletics administration and the NCAA on ways to make the experience of Division I gay athletes more positive.  This research confirms the ways in which athletics culture silences gay male identity particularly for those athletes from high profile team sports.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Higher--Psychology, Social--Gay--Athlete--Factors--Visibility--Invisibility--Division I</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>228</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62942</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62942</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Tuitt, Frank</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Stevens, Richard</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Beaudoin, Luc</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Katz, Elinor</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63416</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T18:11:24Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Characterization of the Molecular Mechanisms Regulating Hypercorticism in Spawning Pacific Salmon</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Westring, Christian Gustav</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Biological Sciences</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Pacific salmon are semelparous fish that undergo accelerated senescence and death after a single reproductive event.  Sustained hypercorticism has been implicated in the systematic physiological degeneration of post-spawning Pacific salmon.  However, the molecular mechanisms responsible for cortisol overproduction in spawning Pacific salmon have yet to be fully elucidated. The hypothalamus-pituitary-interrenal (HPI) axis is the neuroendocrine network responsible for modulating a broad range of physiological functions from reproductive activity to chronic stress response. Fluctuations in the production and/or regulation of cortisol by this axis can have serious consequences with respect to the survival of an organism.  In particular, sustained increases in plasma cortisol levels are directly correlated with metabolic disorders characterized by muscle atrophy, immune deficiency, adrenal hyperplasia, kidney dysfunction and systemic tissue degeneration.During the spawning migration, semelparous Pacific salmon undergo extensive tissue and organ degeneration. While it had previously been thought that the stress of marine to freshwater migration was responsible for the post-spawning demise of these fish, numerous studies have implicated the sustained overproduction of cortisol during sexual maturation and spawning as the event which ultimately leads to the demise of spawning Pacific salmon. Conversely, salmonids such as iteroparous steelhead trout also experience sharply elevated cortisol levels during spawning.  In these animals, however, cortisol levels return to normal after spawning, suggesting hypersecretion of cortisol in spawning salmonids in not necessarily irreversible.The current study uses a combination of molecular and proteomic strategies to compare the differences in hypothalamus-pituitary-interrenal activity and its potential impact on cortisol release in semelparous salmon and iteroparous steelhead rainbow trout.  This comparative approach provides further insight into the physiological differences between these two distinct reproductive strategies and underlying molecular mechanisms regulating hypercorticism in spawning Pacific salmon.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Biology, Molecular--Biology, Molecular--Endocrinology--Salmon--HPI Axis</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>283</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63416</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63416</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Danielson, Phillip B.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Stedman, Donald H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Coughlan, Christina</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Angleson, Joseph</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Monahan, Michael</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63354</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T18:14:09Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Children Bullied by their Peers: Why Some Do Well and Some Do Not</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bennett, Laurie</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Curriculum and Instruction</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This dissertation examines what might be going on in and around schools that helps some students to overcome the stigma and suffering of being bullied, and what might be going on that gets in their way.  What do schools do to increase the likelihood of these students&apos; surviving bullying intact and thriving thereafter?  What do schools do to diminish that likelihood?To answer this question, a retrospective, qualitative study was performed with two populations, using an extreme sampling approach: a group of high achieving, suburban high school students enrolled in advanced placement courses, and a group of incarcerated young men.  Each group was given a retrospective survey to determine if they had been bullied when they were in grade school, and those from each group with the highest cumulative scores on the survey were selected to be interviewed.From the interviews, the following findings emerged.  What schools did that most helped to bullied children survive their bullying was (a) engage them in challenging work, and (b) support them through caring adults.  What happened in schools that most hurt bullied children or got in the way of coping with their bullying was (a) changes in school structure (accompanying the shift from elementary to middle school), (b) adult non-intervention in bullying when it happened, and (c) isolation of victimized children from their school community.  Three fundamental needs of bullied students, which could potentially be fulfilled by the school, also emerged from analysis of the interviews: (a) the need for a place of refuge and safety, (b) the need for caring adults, and (c) the need for a sense of a positive future awaiting them if they only stay in school.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Curriculum and Instruction--Education, Technology--Bullying; peer victimization; educational criticism and connoisseurship; truancy; at-risk youth; qualitative research</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>217</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63354</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63354</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Uhrmacher, Bruce</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Reshotko, Naomi</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Tombari, Martin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cutforth, Nicholas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63134</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T18:16:59Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Children of the Borderlands: Young Soldiers and the Reproduction of War</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hynes, Bridget Ann</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Conflict Resolution Institute</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Locality intersects with international security through the lens of one of the larger manpower drivers of recent African wars ---child soldiers. This study compares the border regions of the Namibian Kavango with the Mano River and Kailahun regions of Sierra Leone, as war and children crossed over from Angola and Liberia, respectively.  Local norms and networks in child soldiering illuminate two aspects of international security ---the problem of war contagion and the challenges of international regime efficacy.First, is the relationship between local capabilities and the expansion of war. The fieldwork shows war&apos;s spread and child soldiering are intertwined, through local vulnerabilities, and local capabilities. It dissects local configurations and shows that border localities are not endemically dangerous. Though the role of locality can serve as a stimulus and momentum for expanding war, expected and unexpected pathways of local action can make a difference in both in the degree of war&apos;s spread and the extent of children&apos;s participation.Second, what could be called a global anti-child soldiering regime, an international configuration strongly linked to the protection-based theoretic in human security, emerged and flourished over the past 15 years. Programmatic actions against child soldiering, accompanied by international legal norms shunning child soldiering, have escalated dramatically. Yet, international estimates of child soldiers active in combat did not diminish. On the contrary, child soldiering grew from 250,000 children a year in 1998, to more than 300,000 in 2005. Why haven&apos;t these actions halted child soldiering growth?In detailing local involvement and resistance to cross-border child soldiering, distinct gaps between the conceptual and substantive factors of import in prevention locally, and those stressed by anti-child soldier networks globally, come to light. The findings in provide needed political specificity for the human security literature and the global anti-child soldiering regime. The concrete conditions and localized ideas where efforts to thwart child soldiering have had some success (Namibia) and where they have not (Sierra Leone) demonstrate capabilities that aid children and civilians in conflict zones. Flowing from the study&apos;s finding, are a risk continuum and analytic tools for targeting support for local capabilities, local capabilities that push away from regional violent involvement on the whole, and from children&apos;s involvement specifically.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations--Anthropology, Cultural--Women&apos;s Studies--Child soldiers; capabilities; human security; war borders; conflict; children and war</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>327</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63134</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63134</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Sisk, Timothy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gilbert, Alan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McCamant, John</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62901</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T18:26:53Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Closing the Achievement Gap: Effective Teachers in High Poverty, High Minority Elementary Schools</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eddy, Lara E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Educational Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Across the nation, an achievement gap exists between high poverty and minority students and their higher SES, white peers. While research indicates that the gap can be decreased and even eliminated with highly effective teachers, very few studies provide the field of education with a set of discrete actions that teachers must do in order to successfully close the achievement gap. As America&apos;s population of children becomes increasingly diverse, teachers need to know how to be highly effective in reaching diverse populations.This study used a mixed methodological approach to create a theoretical explanation for the phenomenon of elementary teachers closing the achievement gap with high poverty and minority students. Quantitative and qualitative data were gathered, analyzed, and synthesized to develop a substantive theory. Through this process, the Reciprocal Learning Theory was developed. This theory explains the actions and behaviors of highly effective elementary teachers with high poverty and minority students.This study contributed to the field by providing an explanation, grounded in quantitative and qualitative data, on what highly effective teachers do to close the achievement gap with high poverty and monitory students.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Curriculum and Instruction--Achievement gap--Effective teachers--Elementary--Grounded theory--Mixed methodology</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>197</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62901</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62901</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Bennett Steiner, Ellen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Katz, Elinor</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salters, Roger</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Seeley, Ken</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63580</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T18:32:12Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Competency-based Curriculum for a Master&apos;s Program in Service Science, Management and Engineering (SSME): An Online Delphi Study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Choudaha, Rahul</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Higher Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The overarching purpose of this research was to provide theoretical and conceptual foundations for developing a competency-based curriculum for an interdisciplinary master&apos;s program in Service Science, Management and Engineering (SSME). Specifically, the objective was to ascertain the competencies and courses that are relevant for developing a competency model for a service scientist and a curriculum blueprint for SSME. The study employed three rounds of the online Delphi survey to achieve the research objectives. The three rounds were used to identify, prioritize, and define competencies and courses. A panel of industry professionals and university faculty were invited to participate as experts. A total of 51, 40, and 39 respondents participated in Round 1, Round 2 and Round 3 survey respectively.Overall, a high degree of consensus was observed among the participants for the importance of competencies and courses, however, there were some differences noted by the disciplinary expertise and professional background of the respondents. Based on the consensus of the study participants, a final list of 10 competencies and 14 courses was generated. These competencies were used to develop a competency model and the courses were used to create a curriculum blueprint.The final 14 courses were categorized into four modules, Module 1: Contextual Foundation (Information &amp; Service Economy, Consumer Behavior, Leadership &amp; Organizational Behavior, Project Management); Module 2: Service Core (Service Innovation, Service Design, Service Operations and Supply Chain); Module 3(a): Engineering Concentration (Business Process Modeling, Service Engineering, Quality Management); Module 3(b): Management Concentration, Strategic Management, Service Marketing, Enterprise Systems) and; Module 4: Integrative Capstone (Business and Technology Integration).The final 10 competencies were categorized into three clusters; Cluster 1: Service Mindset (Needs assessment, Conceptualize service system, Problem-solving, Contextualize service science); Cluster 2: Integrative Competence (Business and technology integration, Interdisciplinary collaboration, Diversity orientation) and; Cluster 3: Meta-competence (Adaptability, Interpersonal communication, and Critical thinking).The results of this study may serve as a common language among stakeholders to prepare future service scientists or &quot;T-shaped&quot; professionals for the service economy. This study also contributed to the body of literature of competency-based curriculum development in higher education.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Higher--Business Administration, Management--Engineering, System Science--Curriculum--Delphi--Engineering--Management--Service Science--SSME</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>190</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63580</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63580</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Tuitt, Frank</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Grealy, Deborah S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Seidel, Kent</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63263</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T18:34:22Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comprehension Monitoring, Cognitive Resources, and Reading Disability</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Roth, Laura</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>People with reading disability (RD) exhibit deficits in comprehension monitoring, or the ability to assess understanding during reading. One reason monitoring problems may arise is because individuals with RD struggle so much with word identification that there are insufficient resources left for comprehension processes like monitoring. A second possibility is that individuals with RD may have a primary deficit in monitoring that is independent of their word identification difficulties.We performed two experiments to address whether comprehension monitoring constitutes a primary or secondary deficit in RD. Monitoring was evaluated using garden path sentences, each containing an ambiguous homograph, such as bow, that was incorrectly primed. Homograph corrections were the dependent variable assessing monitoring. In the first experiment, we evaluated whether monitoring difficulties can result from a typical reader spreading limited cognitive resources in a dual task paradigm where readers not only had to read and understand, but also had to keep track of the background color of the text. We also varied the decoding difficulty of the text to compare monitoring on texts that were virtually identical in meaning but varied in ease of decoding. Both manipulations resulted in decreased monitoring performance for typical readers, suggesting that indeed resource limitations may lead to difficulties in comprehension monitoring.In the second experiment we evaluated specifically whether decoding problems in RD affect monitoring performance. Again, we manipulated the decoding difficulty of the text. Individuals with RD monitored significantly more on simple than difficult texts. When decoding was covaried, we found no significant difference in monitoring between individuals with RD and age-matched controls. This suggests that when decoding problems are removed, individuals with RD are able to monitor their understanding as well as typical readers.In sum, the combined results of these two experiments offer strong support for resource limitations as an explanation for comprehension monitoring problems, suggesting that monitoring problems in RD are a secondary deficit that results from their decoding problems.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Psychology, Cognitive</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>93</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63263</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63263</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Keenan, Janice M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Reed, Catherine L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pennington, Bruce F.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Miller, Gloria</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63198</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T18:37:13Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Crossing Borders: Bringing Students and Professors to the Same Side of the River</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stone Norton, Amanda E</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Higher Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Currently, Latina/os have one of the highest rates of attrition in higher education (León, 2003; National Center for Educational Statistics, 2005b; US Census Bureau, 2000). In 2001, the percentage of first-time post-secondary Latina/o undergraduate completion rates (for students starting in 1995) were 5.5 % for students beginning their college education at two-year institutions and 11.4% for those beginning at four-year institutions (National Center for Educational Statistics, 2005b) as compared to white students with 11.4% and 61.9% respectively (National Center for Educational Statistics, 2005b).  Numerous studies have sought to understand the reasons for the high rates of Latina/o student attrition; however little research has been conducted on the impact of pedagogical techniques on Latina/o undergraduate student persistence. This research answered the question how do faculty members create inclusive pedagogies for undergraduate Latina/o students at a predominantly white, private institution.This research utilized Critical Race Theory (CRT), Alejandra Elenes&apos; (2006) theory of Border/Transformative Pedagogies, and inclusive pedagogy models as its guiding theoretical frameworks. More specifically, CRT guided all of the data collection and analysis procedures; whereas, Elenes&apos; (2006) research and the inclusive pedagogy models provided the foundation for the emanation of story telling. Using the qualitative methods of focus groups, interviews, document reviews, questionnaires, correspondence, and journaling, this research engaged Latina/o undergraduate students and recent graduates and faculty members in a dialogue about inclusive pedagogical techniques at a private predominantly white institution in western United States.The findings of this research fell into three categories: values, knowledge, and actions. The faculty and student participants stated that inclusive faculty members demonstrate the values of care, respect, life-long learning, and authenticity.  Inclusive faculty also exhibited basic knowledge of Latina/o cultures, the power of socio-economic status and race at predominantly white affluent institutions, and conflict management skills. Behaviorally, inclusive faculty members utilized a variety of techniques that a) included Latina/o cultures in assignments and classroom activities, b) encouraged Latina/o students to academically and socially engage in classroom learning, c) respected the multiple responsibilities of Latina/o students, d) created equitable learning environments, and e) engaged students outside of the classroom.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Higher--Education, Teacher Training--Hispanic American Studies--Teaching;Latino;Pedagogy;Inclusive;College;Hispanic</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>310</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63198</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63198</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Tuitt, Frank</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Chevillot, Frederique</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Vaccaro, Annemarie</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Trevio, Jesus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62933</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T18:41:34Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Deliver Us From Evil: Christian Freedom and Sexual Regulation in the Trafficking Victims Protection Act</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zimmerman, Yvonne C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Religious and Theological Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This dissertation uses a Foucaultian genealogy to examine the intersection of the U.S.&apos;s federal campaign to eliminate human trafficking with American Protestant Christianity.  I argue that the understanding of human trafficking and the imagination of freedom codified in &lt;em&gt;The Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000&lt;em&gt; (TVPA) and enacted in federal anti-trafficking initiatives are constituted through this set of religious sensibilities.  Not only do these religious sensibilities shape the U.S.&apos;s anti-trafficking laws, under the presidential administration of George W. Bush they have become a prominent part of the U.S.&apos;s anti-trafficking project.In its legislative moment, or the processes through which the TVPA was created, I show that while the TVPA is not a piece of &quot;religious&quot; legislation, it is situated within a discourse of religious freedom rooted in Protestant Christianity.  Hence Protestant conceptions of what freedom entails condition the legislation&apos;s vision of  freedom from trafficking.  In its executive moment, or how the anti-trafficking legislation has been enacted, I show how the Bush administration has installed as the lynchpin of the U.S.&apos;s anti-trafficking stance a set of  religious claims that are particular to American Protestantism.  In both moments, conceptions of gender and sexuality crucially construct the emergent conception of freedom from trafficking.  Insofar as the U.S.&apos;s anti-trafficking stance employs sensibilities rooted in American Protestantism, the freedom that this project endorses corresponds to conventionally Protestant norms of sex and gender.  Especially as applied to women, the U.S.&apos;s anti-trafficking project functions as a Protestant disciplining of &quot;appropriate&quot; gender and sexuality.The Protestant norms that undergird the U.S.&apos;s foreign policies on human trafficking are not constitutive of freedom in any universal sense, yet these norms are imposed all around the world.  Because in a democratic, pluralistic society the state must not be permitted to compel ascription to any particular religious perspective, I conclude that the religious overtones and undertones of the U.S.&apos;s anti-trafficking stance are problematic.  The elimination of trafficking requires an approach that does not rely on sexual regulation as the primary ethical imperative of opposition to trafficking but, instead, one that protects and promotes practices of freedom.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Religion, General--Women&apos;s Studies--Human trafficking--Religious freedom--Sexual regulation--American Protestant Christianity--Genealogy--Freedom--Bush administration</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>293</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62933</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62933</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Alumkal, Antony</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wilbanks, Dana</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>d&apos;Estree, Claude</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Henking, Susan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Seeburger, Frank</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63222</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T18:46:29Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development and Validation of the Professional Support Inventory for Mental Health Professionals</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bahraini, Nazanin</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Counseling Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Researchers and practitioners in the field of traumatology have emphasized the importance of a supportive work environment in helping trauma therapists cope with the demands of their work. The therapist&apos;s professional peer group can provide different types of support that may prevent or reduce the impact of compassion fatigue and burnout. Despite these discussions, there are no studies to date that have examined this relationship using well-defined and psychometrically sound measures of professional social support. The purpose of this study was to construct and provide validation for a measure of professional social support for mental health professionals who work with trauma clients. The measure was entitled The Professional Support Inventory for Mental Health Professionals (PSIMHP).The process of instrument development occurred in four phases. The literature review provided a conceptualization of professional social support for mental health professionals, which was used to create an item pool. A panel of experts evaluated the item pool, rating the items for relevancy, specificity, clarity, and usefulness. Quantitative evaluation was conducted in two phases, the pilot and the field study. A sample of 47 mental health professionals was included in the pilot study. Reliability was assessed using SPSS, which resulted in the deletion of one item from the pilot test. The measure was then re-administered to a second sample of 173 mental health professionals in the field study. Psychometric properties and evidence for the instrument&apos;s validity were examined using both classical test theory and Rasch Model analyses.Psychometric properties of the final revised version of the instrument (PSIMHP-R) revealed that the items demonstrated good fit, invariance across subgroups of mental health professionals, and offered greater support for a unidimensional measure. In addition, the distribution of person agreeability and item difficulty estimates obtained for the revised measure showed good coverage along the continuum, and items showed better differentiation among individuals with varying levels of professional support. Cronbach&apos;s alpha for the original and revised version of the measure were .95 and .92, respectively. The findings from this study also provided preliminary evidence for different types of validity. Study implications, limitations, and future directions were also discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Psychology, Psychometrics</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>182</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63222</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63222</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Sherry, Patrick</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Craine, Michael</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salters, Roger</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62958</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T19:04:20Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Discussing the Dead: Patterns of Family Interaction Regarding Lost Family Members</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hosmer, Rebecca</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Human Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The current study focused on the variations of family patterns and the overall environment of family communication regarding a lost family member as reflected in the communication of the family system.  Participants were recruited in undergraduate communication courses at a Midwestern university, as well as via snowballing techniques in the same Midwestern city.  A total of 74 surveys were submitted that fulfilled the participation criteria of having lost an immediate family member at least two years ago.  Surveys were largely qualitative in nature and were available online at the Survey Monkey website.  Surveys were processed using thematic analysis and two separate, independent reviewers.The current study found a variety of ways that families pattern their communication in the process of re-establishing identity after a family member dies.  Two major distinctions stood out: the different patterns of interaction for within-family conversations versus those for conversations with people outside the family, and the patterns of interaction for families who did versus did not engage in interaction regarding their lost family member.  The study also found that emotional qualities related strongly to within-family interaction regarding lost family members, while taking the perspective of the &quot;other&quot; related strongly to non-family interaction regarding lost family members.    Finally, an initial Theory of Family Interaction Regarding Lost Family Members was proposed and discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Speech Communication--Sociology, Individual and Family Studies--Family communication; grief and loss; family systems; patterns of communication; interaction and loss; death and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>164</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62958</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:62958</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Dickson, Fran</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Morr Serewicz, Mary Claire</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Suter, Elizabeth</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Chevillot, Frederique</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63576</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T19:07:44Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>DRIVING WHILE BLACK: STORIES THROUGH THE DRIVER&apos;S CAR WINDOW A COMMUNICATIVE ANALYSIS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Keesee, Tracie Lynn</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Human Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This study explores the communicative dynamic that occurs between Denver police officers, and citizens of the African-American community, during traffic stops characterized as &quot;Driving While Black.&quot; Thirty four interviews were conducted regarding this study. Derived from the interviews were transcribed narratives, which were examined through the use of narrative analysis and various theoretical frameworks. The narrative analysis and theoretical frameworks provided a new lens for exploring the police/citizen communicative dynamic, and a foundation for additional communication research between police officers and the African-American community.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Speech Communication--Sociology, Criminology and Penology--Communication--Driving While Black--DWB--Police--Race--Racial Profiling</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>173</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63576</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63576</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Wood, Roy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Foust, Christina</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lair, Dan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Manning, Susan S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63561</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T19:10:31Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of Contextual and Individual Difference Factors on Perceptions of Victims</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Combs, Melody Dawn</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Victim blame can have detrimental effects on victims&apos; coping with traumatic events. The current study examined contextual (i.e., victim-observer ingroup membership and safety of the environment) and individual difference (i.e., world beliefs, trauma exposure, and cognitive semantic associations) factors in relation to victim blame. Ingroup membership predicted greater character praise in females, while outgroup membership predicted greater praise in males. Victim praise was also greater when the environment was safe versus dangerous. Stronger beliefs about the manageability of the world marginally predicted greater victim blame, while stronger benevolent world beliefs predicted less victim blame and less character derogation. Further, the number of traumatic event types reported by participants was positively related to character praise and negatively related to derogation. Histories of exposure to traumas high in betrayal predicted greater character derogation. Using an implicit semantic priming task to examine the automatic semantic associations between victim and derogation concepts, victim-to-derogation priming was related to less victim blame.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Psychology, Experimental--Psychology, Social--Psychology, Cognitive--Just world beliefs--Trauma--Victim blame--Victim perceptions</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>54</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63561</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63561</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>DePrince, Anne P</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Riva, Maria T.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McIntosh, Daniel N.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Potts, George R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Shirk, Stephen R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63186</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T19:13:58Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of Developing Mathematical Ideas on Teacher Practice in the Elementary Mathematics Classroom</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pace, Heidi V</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Educational Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Author:  Heidi V. PaceTitle:  EFFECTS OF DEVELOPING MATHEMATICAL IDEAS ON TEACHER PRACTICE IN THE ELEMENTARY MATHEMATICS CLASSROOMAdvisor:  Dr. Ellen SteinerDegree Date:  August 2008ABSTRACTInternational measures of student achievement in mathematics over the past decade indicate that United States&apos; students do not perform as well as their counterparts in other countries.  Reform initiatives to address this deficit have included new curriculum, revised mathematics standards, alterations in school structures, and implementing new teaching strategies with minimal results.  The missing component in these initiatives has been a focus on the classroom teacher&apos;s own knowledge of and facility with mathematics and the impact this has on developing students&apos; understanding of math.This study explored whether elementary teachers who participated in the professional development program Developing Mathematical Ideas (DMI) implemented research-based mathematics practices more frequently than teachers who did not receive the training.  The study also reviewed student achievement in classes taught by DMI-trained teachers and those teachers not trained in DMI.  Instruments included a survey, interviews with 5 teachers and the state achievement results of third, fourth, and fifth grade students.The survey results showed no differences in the frequency of implementation of research-based practices for DMI and non-DMI-trained teachers with one exception.  DMI-trained teachers reported modifying the math curriculum and evaluating students&apos; learning gaps at a higher frequency than non-DMI-trained teachers.  The interviews pointed to a possible relationship between coaching following DMI training and higher teacher confidence levels in teaching math.  More coaching sessions may also improve teachers&apos; facility with mathematics.  Achievement results showed no mean difference in scale scores between third and fourth grade students taught by DMI-trained or non-DMI-trained teachers.  Fifth grade students taught by non-DMI-trained teachers had significantly higher mean scale scores than those taught by DMI-trained teachers.The findings from this study point to DMI not having a robust impact on teacher practice and having no positive impact on student achievement.  Survey design, sample size, program implementation, and other school district initiatives may explain some of these findings.  These findings may be limited to this study and may not generalize to another setting.  The implication that follow-up coaching may enhance the results of DMI training should receive further attention.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Curriculum and Instruction</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>128</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63186</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63186</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Steiner, Ellen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lopez, Maggie</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salters, Roger</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Katz, Elinore</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63575</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T19:16:06Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EFFECTS OF PLAIN LANGUAGE REVISION</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Baker, Holly Elizabeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Educational Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Colorado assesses approximately 98% of students enrolled in grades 3&amp;ndash10 in the area of mathematics. In 2005, 69,872 English Language Learners (ELLs) in grades 3&amp;ndash10 participated in the state content area assessments. In 2007, 88,060 ELLs participated in the state content area assessments. With this dramatic growth in the ELL population in the state of Colorado and elsewhere in the nation, ensuring that ELLs have access to comprehensible materials on state assessments is of paramount importance. Accommodations provide access for students based on their individual needs. Likewise, assessment items designed and or revised using the principles of plain language and universal design increase access to the content area information in assessments. Colorado&apos;s work in plain language revision of Colorado Student Assessment Program (CSAP) items has been extensive.Using statewide CSAP data for 2005 and 2007, this study examined how mathematics assessment items, once revised for plain language, performed compared to the original, unrevised version of the item. Access for English Language Learners was a focal point for this study. Plain language revision was evaluated for its effects on item difficulty, item discrimination, DIF and DOK.DOK ratings from 2005 and 2007 were compared using Chi&amp;ndashsqaure. One sample t&amp;ndashtests were used to examine the differences in DIF and item difficulty (p&amp;ndashvalue), as well as item discrimination for ELLs and Non&amp;ndashELLs comparing the 2005 non&amp;ndashrevised items with the 2007 revised items. Unrevised items were used as controls. Revised items were classified by type of linguistic change. Each type of change was examined using ANOVA to determine if a specific type of change effected differences in DIF and item difficulty.While results indicate little if any difference in item performance at individual grade levels, overall LEP performance on revised items was higher than on non&amp;ndashrevised items, a change in performance not present for non-ELLs. This may indicate that plain language revision continues to hold promise as a best practice for item development. As an accommodation, however, it appears that plain language revision alone may not be sufficient to ensure access to assessment items for ELLs.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Tests and Measurements--English Language Learners--Plain Language--Universal Design</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>163</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63575</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63575</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Steiner, Ellen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lefly, Dianne</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Katz, Ellie</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salters, Roger</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63567</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T19:21:37Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EXAMINING THE EFFECTS OF LINGUISTIC ACCOMMODATIONS ON THE COLORADO STUDENT ASSESSMENT PROGRAM--MATHEMATICS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Enriquez, Marisol</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Educational Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The No Child Left Behind (NCLB) Act changed assessment for English Language Learners (ELLs). Under the law, states must validly assess ELLs&apos; English Language Proficiency (ELP) and content knowledge. The law shed light on the achievement of ELLs while also creating challenges for states in validating state assessment and accountability systems. Test accommodations are used for ELLs to reduce threats to test score validity and measure academic achievement as accurately and fairly as possible. Since ELLs are working towards proficiency in English, they face linguistic and socio-cultural barriers under the confines of large scale assessment. A limited body of research regarding accommodations for ELLs exists, but has inconclusive findings that do not factor in student background variables. This study examined to what extent linguistic accommodation led to improvement in test performance of ELLs using ELP scores from the Colorado English Language Acquisition Assessment (CELApro) and Mathematics scores from the Colorado Student Assessment Program (CSAP) along with student background variables. The results of this study suggest that Translated Oral Scripts seemed to make the biggest difference for all grade levels in terms of association with higher CSAP performance. Students using Word-to-Word Dictionaries also showed increased performance for grades eight and ten. Grades three through seven were not included for this accommodation because of small sample sizes. Oral Scripts and Teacher Read Directions were associated with positive score increases for some grades and negative score drops for others. Students with lower levels of English proficiency tended to benefit more from receiving accommodations than students with higher proficiency. Analyzing the accommodations by grade also revealed differential accommodation effects. Third grade students receiving Translated Oral Scripts had higher CSAP scores than their non-accommodated peers, those using regular Oral Scripts benefitted slightly, while the effects of Teacher Read directions and Extended Timing appear to be worse than receiving No Accommodation for this sample. In grade ten, it did not matter what accommodations students received--none seemed to be associated with student performance.While the analyses showed that for the most part Teacher Read Directions, Extended Timing, and Oral Scripts were not significantly associated with Fluent-English Proficient (FEP) performance, it is unfortunate that the student samples receiving Translated Oral Scripts and Word-to-Word Dictionaries were insufficient in size to allow their inclusion. The FEP results may be due to the fact that FEPs no longer benefit from accommodations since they have a high level of ELP. Considering the significant role that assessment results have in guiding decisions about individuals and organizations, it is crucial to continue examining how to fairly assess ELLs while using systematic research-based practices.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Tests and Measurements--Education, General--Education, Administration--Accommodation--Assessment--English--Language--Learner</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>154</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63567</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63567</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salters, Roger</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lefly, Dianne</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Katz, Elinor</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63018</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T20:48:16Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Examining the Impact of Changes in Data-Driven Teaching and Leading on Collective Efficacy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Filbin, Janet Eileen</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Educational Administration and Policy Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The sanctions are mounting for those schools who are failing to meet federal, state, and local accountability requirements.  States and districts continue to spotlight schools that are considered underperforming for scrutiny.  As a result, staff within these schools often struggle with feelings of hopelessness and dissatisfaction.  Collective efficacy, the belief that an individual has about their own and their colleague&apos;s competencies to take on difficult tasks, has been found to be a significant predictor of student achievement.  Prior student achievement has also been shown to be highly correlated with the individual and collective efficacy of a school staff.  However, enhancing or sustaining the efficacy of educators in schools targeted for improvement year to year is challenging.  Research in this field is emerging and little is known about the factors that directly influence the collective efficacy of a school staff.This research examines the relationships that teacher pedagogical precision, the use and application of data to inform teaching for learning, and the principal&apos;s use of data with staff has on collective efficacy.  The mediating effects of changes in student achievement on the relationship between teacher and principal pedagogical precision and collective efficacy were also investigated.   Educators from 50 elementary, middle, and high schools in a large urban/suburban district participated in this cross-year study.  Survey and achievement results were collected three times throughout the school year and analyzed using structural equation modeling.The findings of this study indicate that there is a direct and significant impact on collective efficacy when teachers report higher uses of data to change instruction with an effect size of .908 (p&lt;.01) by spring.  Teachers&apos; perception of principals&apos; use of data had a positive effect size ranging from .795 in fall (p&lt;.001) to .409 in spring (p&lt;.001).   Results show that, as a school risk factor, socio-economic status had a significant, negative impact on individual teacher&apos;s perception of collective efficacy throughout the year (p&lt;001) but a small, significant, and positive impact on achievement in winter and spring (p&lt;.001).</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Administration--Instructional leadership; collective efficacy; data-driven; school improvement</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>228</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63018</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63018</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Katz, Elinor</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salters, Roger</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Tombari, Martin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McNulty, Brian</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Korach, Susan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63071</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T20:50:21Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Explicit Finite Element Modeling of Joint Mechanics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pal, Saikat</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Computational models of biomechanical systems can provide valuable insight into joint functionality and implant performance under conditions that are difficult to test in vivo or using in vitro experimental setups.  The main objective of this research was to develop and demonstrate the feasibility of explicit finite element (FE) based models to address current concerns in biomechanics.  Specifically, efficient probabilistic methods were applied to evaluate the effects of inherent system uncertainties on output measures, and custom user subroutines and optimization algorithms were incorporated within the FE framework to develop muscle-actuated dynamic models.  
	
A probabilistic FE model of the Stanmore knee simulator was developed.  Inputs to the model included International Organization for Standardization (ISO) force-controlled gait loading conditions, along with normal distributions of component alignment, loading and environmental parameters representing uncertainty associated with the experimental setup.  The model predicted distributions of output measures, including 1 and 99 percentile bounds of joint kinematics, range of motion, peak contact pressure, and linear and gravimetric wear.  Sensitivity of the performance metrics to input parameters were reported to identify the important input parameters.
	 
Three-dimensional musculoskeletal models of the lower extremity were developed.  A probabilistic model was used to evaluate the effects of muscle attachment location uncertainty and joint kinematic variability on moment arm predictions from different estimating techniques.  Muscle-actuated dynamic FE models were created to simulate activities driven by direct forces or forces calculated from muscle parameters and activations data.  Inputs to the FE models included patient anthropometry data, muscle and soft-tissue properties, contact definitions, and muscle parameters based on a Hill-type model.  The models were optimized for muscle forces or activations to reproduce kinematic signatures representing knee flexion and chair rise activities.  Outputs of the models included joint reaction forces, ligament loads, and tibiofemoral and patellofemoral kinematics and contact pressures.  The computational framework developed represents a novel methodology to perform comparative studies of joint behavior and implant designs.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Engineering, Biomedical--Engineering, Mechanical--Explicit finite element methods; knee simulator modeling; musculoskeletal modeling; probabilistic methods; moment arm; numerical wear</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>255</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63071</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63071</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Rullkoetter, Paul J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Shelburne, Kevin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Laz, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kumosa, Maciej</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63345</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T20:55:03Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Financial Aid Type and Student Need Level as Predictors of Undergraduate Persistence at the University of Denver</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kruse-Crocker, Michelle Marie</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Higher Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This dissertation examines the capacity of financial aid type and student need level to predict undergraduate student persistence at the University of Denver. Studies that have measured the influence of financial aid on persistence have had varying results. This may be a function of the institution under investigation, the population investigated, or the combination of the various types of aid. Focusing on one institution, the University of Denver, provides administrators with specific information about the practice of leveraging aid dollars to promote undergraduate student persistence. This study used a quantitative research design. Measures of central tendency were conducted to determine the characteristics of the student population. Logistic regression analysis was used to determine if undergraduate student persistence could be predicted based on what type of financial aid a student receives and what level of need the student had upon entering the University. Findings indicate that type of financial aid does not predict persistence at year one or year four. Student need level only marginally predicts persistence at year one and when type of aid and need level are considered together only work-study is a predictor of persistence for year one. Models for year two, three, and graduation did not produce a goodness of fit for the logistic regression models, therefore the findings remain inconclusive. The outcome of this investigation provides the University of Denver administration with data for basing their decisions about the use of financial aid to address student financial need in order to promote persistence.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Higher--Education, Finance--Financial Aid; Student Need; Persistence</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>293</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63345</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63345</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Summers Thompson, Sheila</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Tuitt, Frank</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DeLyser, Ron</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Davis, James R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63194</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T20:58:24Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Finding My Way: Increasing Self-Awareness and Self-Goal Setting Among African American Youth</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pleasant-Immanuel, Nicole Danielle</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Psychology</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Author: Nicole Pleasant-ImmanuelTitle:  Finding My Way: Increasing Self-Awareness and Self-Goal Setting Among African American YouthAdvisors: Howard J. Markman and Scott M. StanleyDegree Date: August 2008ABSTRACTMarriage has been found to be beneficial to men, women and children of all races, but many African Americans do not experience these benefits as 70% of African American children are born to an unwed mother.  While there is a general trend among all ethnic groups to have more accepting attitudes toward nonmarital childbearing and high expectations for marriage in the 20th century, these attitudes have had a greater impact on the childbearing behavior of African Americans largely due to the strong association between neighborhood economic disadvantage and nonmarital childbearing.  African-Americans are more likely to come from an impoverished neighborhood than other ethnic groups and attitudes have been found to be a mediator between neighborhood economic disadvantage and nonmarital births.  In addition, there are very few programs available to African-American youth that teaches skills and principles associated with and increases confidence in creating a healthy, happy long-term relationship.The major aims of the present study were to introduce an intervention to an adolescent population in order to increase relationship skill development and influence attitudes regarding marriage and childbearing.  Ideally, participating African American youth would demonstrate increased communication skills, increased confidence in having a healthy long-term relationship and endorse attitudes more accepting of childbearing in the context of marriage and economic stability.Fifty-seven African American high school students were the participants in this feasibility study aimed to assess the effectiveness of a new intervention, Finding My Way.  This preventative intervention was designed to increase self-awareness and self-goal setting; positive relationship characteristics (constructive communication, relationship confidence, and relationship satisfaction); the endorsement for childbearing within the context of marriage and/or economic stability; and the use of contraception during sexual intercourse.   The study used a quasi-experimental design with a treatment as usual control group.The results of this study showed that Finding My Way was effective at modifying the childbearing attitudes of older youth such that participants endorsed a greater acceptance for childbearing within the context of marriage and/or economic stability and reported greater use of protection during sexual intercourse as compared to the treatment as usual group.   There was a trend for those in the Finding My Way group to show greater self-awareness and self-goal setting when thinking of a romantic partner but no other significant effects of the intervention were found.  This lack of other significant effects of the intervention may have been due to many factors including challenges delivering the intervention within a community-based context, a strong treatment as usual comparison condition, and relatively small sample sizes.While many of the proposed effects of Finding My Way were not found, the results indicate that this intervention can be successfully delivered within a community-based context and impact the attitudes and behavior of African-American youth.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Psychology, Clinical--Self-Awareness and self-goal setting; African American youth--Neighborhood economic disadvantage; nonmarital childbearing; healthy relationships; protected sexual intercourse</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>193</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63194</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63194</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Stanley, Scott M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Markman, Howard J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Williams, James H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Jones, Arthur C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Shirk, Stephen R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63177</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T21:02:32Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Fire Changes Biogeochemistry of Wildland Soils</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wojcik, Nathan Joseph</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Biological Sciences</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Fire is a critical process in altering belowground resources in terrestrial ecosystems.  It has been found that soil nutrients increase, decrease, or remain the same following fire. Thus, in an attempt to elucidate the ambiguity surrounding this paradox, meta-analysis was used to comprehensively and quantitatively review empirical studies to detect overall patterns of soil nutrient response after fire in varying biotic and abiotic conditions. The results suggested that fire increases available soil N, plant-available P, extractable P and pH.  In contrast, total soil nutrient pools had mixed responses with no change in total N, reductions in total carbon (C), and significant increases in total P, which ultimately influence the overall sustainability of soil resources.  In addition, the results of the meta-analysis indicated that significant fire-induced responses vary with one or several different biotic and abiotic conditions.  Hence fire-induced soil nutrient responses varied by vegetation type, fire category, ignition seasonality, time since fire, soil texture, and soil depth.Cheatgrass invasion in Great Basin sagebrush-grassland communities has rapidly increased and brought fire with it.  Therefore, I examined the role fire has on influencing the spatial patterning of soil nutrients in cheatgrass invaded sagebrush soils.  The results indicated that available N and P, total N, total C, and pH increased after prescribed burning in sagebrush habitat containing invasive cheatgrass.  In addition, the lack of spatial differentiation in surface and mineral soil temperature regimes indicated that a ubiquitous cover of cheatgrass may have reduced the spatial heterogeneity of this sagebrush habitat, and as a result, soil nutrients responded similarly to fire under shrub canopy, under shrub dripline, and at shrub interspace.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Biogeochemistry--Biology, Ecology--Biology, Biostatistics--Fire; soil carbon; soil nitrogen; soil phosphorus; meta-analysis; sagebrush steppe</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>185</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63177</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63177</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Sanford, Robert L, Jr.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hill, Roscoe</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sher, Anna</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Oyler-McCance, Sara</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>McIsaac, Hugh</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Christophel, David</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63342</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T21:06:47Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Hypervelocity Impact Damage Response and Characterization of Thin Plate Targets at Elevated Temperatures</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Corbett, Brooke</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Materials Science</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The performance of a typical International Space Station (ISS) shield against the meteoroid and orbital debris (M/OD) impact threat is generally modeled by damage equations for the outer shield and the rear pressure wall. In their current forms, these damage equations neglect the on-orbit temperature extremes witnessed by the ISS.  To address IF and HOW temperature extremes affect the performance of the ISS&apos; typical M/OD shield, a comprehensive study was undertaken that investigated hole diameters in .063&quot; thick 6061-T6 aluminum targets impacted at velocities from ~2-7 km/s at 20ºC, 110ºC, and 210ºC.Robust graphical and analytical analyses confirmed the existence of a statistically significant temperature effect, i.e., hole diameters in heated targets were larger than those in room temperature targets. A new temperature-dependent model was found via multivariable regression analysis that incorporates a linear velocity term and a temperature term based on a form of the cumulative distribution function.Numerical modeling of hypervelocity impacts (HVI) into elevated temperature targets was also performed to determine whether or not currently available material and failure models can adequately simulate the differences observed between room and elevated temperature target hole diameters. Statistical analyses showed that AUTODYN simulated the heated data almost as well as the room temperature data.  However, the slightly worse Goodness of Fit (GOF) values between the heated empirical vs. simulated comparisons suggest that the simulations do not completely account for the observed temperature effect.A series of materials tests and observations were carried out on the post-impacted target plates to help explain the empirical data results with respect to material variability and deformation features.  Rockwell B and K macro-hardness tests revealed that the hardness values for the targets impacted at 110°C were statistically significantly higher compared to those targets impacted at 20°C and 210°C.  Since hole diameters are expected to increase with target temperature, this observation suggests that a less ductile failure mode was involved for the 110°C holes compared to the room temperature and 210°C holes.  Polished micrographs of select 110°C impact hole cross-sections support the idea that these targets failed in spall in a less ductile manner compared to the 20°C and 210°C targets.Current orbital debris (OD) environment predictions are based, in large part, on in-situ damage of spacecraft surfaces, but do not relate observed surface damage to their temperature at the time of the impact.  A first-order prediction was calculated to quantify how much elevated temperature bumpers could potentially affect ORDEM2000 flux predictions, and ultimately the risk of impact.  By failing to take into account that larger hole diameters are created in heated targets, ORDEM2000 potentially overestimates the risk of impact by particles in the 3mm range of the environment by at least 68%.  These calculations show that, in this range, a small error in predicted particle diameter can result in a significant difference in the predicted orbital debris particle flux and risk of impact.  To the extent that these effects are true for other spacecraft surfaces, spacecraft designs may be over-conservative due to an overprediction of large particles in the OD environment.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Engineering, Materials Science</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>204</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63342</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63342</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Amme, Robert C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kumosa, Maciej</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Laz, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Williamsen, Joel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Schonberg, William</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63095</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T21:10:01Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>&quot;I Will Be King Over You&quot;: The Rhetoric of Divine Kingship in the Book of Ezekiel</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Clark, Terry Ray</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Religious and Theological Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This dissertation provides a rhetorical analysis of the motif of Yahweh&apos;s kingship in the Book of Ezekiel.  Drawing upon Aristotle&apos;s The Art of Rhetoric and more recent adaptations and elaborations of classical rhetorical theory, the focus is placed upon the role of Yahweh&apos;s kingship in the argumentative strategies and argumentative purposes of the Ezekiel corpus.The dissertation performs the following tasks: Chapter 1 explains the classical rhetorical method to be employed throughout the project; Chapter 2 provides a basic survey of the rhetorical arrangement, genre, and purpose of Ezekiel; Chapter 3 explores the rhetorical situation or crisis for which Ezekiel serves as a rhetorical response; Chapter 4 examines the role of divine kingship in the visions of Ezek 1-3, 8-11, and 40-48, and discusses its relationship to the motif of divine abandonment and return; Chapters 5-7 examine the motif of Yahweh&apos;s kingship in Ezek 20, in the oracles against the nations (specifically Ezek 28:11-19 and Ezek 31), and in Ezek 34, respectively, and explain the relationship of these units to the transitional material in Ezek 33; Chapter 8 is a summary and conclusion.The dissertation argues that a major concern of the Book of Ezekiel is rebuilding the ethos of Yahweh among the Israelite exilic community in Babylon.  This is especially evident in those sections that implicitly and explicitly employ the motif of Yahweh&apos;s kingship. Ezekiel argues that Yahweh is the Great King (a central tenet of the Zion tradition) by emphasizing Yahweh&apos;s universal sovereignty and his universal exercise of justice.  The text also encourages covenant faithfulness among the exiles in an effort to preserve their unique identity as Yahweh&apos;s patrons.  The rhetorical foundation for accomplishing this is the clarification of Yahweh&apos;s character, which seeks to build the deity&apos;s reputation as honorable and trustworthy, in spite of the disasters of the Babylonian exile and the destruction of Jerusalem.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Religion, Biblical Studies</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>356</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63095</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63095</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>George, Mark K.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Howard, Scott</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Tucker, Gene</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63094</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-25T21:14:13Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Idealism is Not Enough:  The Role of Resources in the Autonomy and Capability of Terrorist Groups</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vittori, Jodi</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Economics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>May 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Terrorism scholars have posited that 90 percent of terrorist groups survive less than a year, and half of those which remain will not live to see the ten year-mark. This dissertation addresses the variety of means through which terrorist groups seek to acquire, move and store money, tangible and intangible resources, and how these strategies shape their autonomy in conducting operations and theoretical capabilities to engage in violent actions. The combination of a terrorist group&apos;s capability and autonomy leads to the identification of seven different categories: state-sponsored terrorist groups, franchises, popularly-supported groups, lone wolves, state-sponsoring groups, shell states and transnational corporation-like groups (TNCs). Within these groups, those with medium to high levels of both autonomy and capability are proven to have the highest average lifespan.Utilizing the Terrorism Knowledge Base database, 100 terrorist groups out of a total of 897 were examined. Each was coded according to its level of autonomy (measured as low, medium or high) and capability (measured as very low, low, medium or high) with respect to the conduct of terrorist actions; the longevity of each group was determined from the time of its first terrorist attack until the most recent one. Statistical analysis utilizing a Weibull distribution verifies that those groups with medium to high capability and autonomy do indeed achieve a longer lifespan than those with only low capabilities and/or low autonomy. Moreover, the sample indicates that the average lifespan for all terrorist groups may be much longer than what terrorism scholars have anticipated.This dissertation addresses four significant gaps in the literature on terrorism. First, it provides a typology for examining the resourcing of terrorism, as none currently exists. Second, it analyzes how the institution of terrorism resourcing has evolved over time and how new institutional variations influence groups&apos; autonomy and capability. Third, as the above criteria correlate to the lifespan of individual terrorist groups, this dissertation explains why some outfits are more likely to survive and flourish while others are short-lived.  Finally, this study develops objective criteria for measuring the capability and autonomy of terrorist organizations.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Political Science, General--Economics, General--Terrorism; financing; autonomy; capability; longevity; institutions</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>485</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63094</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63094</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Adelman, Jonathan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sacko, David</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Szyliowicz, Joseph</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63191</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T17:41:15Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Impact of Pluralistic Mentoring at the United States Air Force Academy (USAFA)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wilks, Jackie</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Higher Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Academic research demonstrates the importance of implementing measures to enhance human diversity and to ensure campus environments are truly inclusive. Literature on mentoring consistently demonstrates its importance in facilitating the opportunities for students to achieve greater levels of academic success, fulfillment, and human development. However, literature merging principles of human diversity with principles of mentoring is somewhat scarce. The direction of this dissertation was an attempt to develop a pluralistic mentoring program at the United States Air Force Academy (USAFA), which would bridge diversity initiatives with good mentoring practices. More importantly, research was conducted to assess the impact of pluralistic mentoring at the USAFA. Jim Cummins&apos;s (2001), Empowering Minority Students: Framework for Intervention enabled the researcher to develop a program that could be incorporated into the Officer Development System (ODS) at USAFA and within the Dean of Faculty advising and mentoring program.The research demonstrated both a qualitative emphasis with historical analysis conducted before and during the development and training of pluralistic mentors, and a quantitative emphasis that explored the impact of pluralistic mentoring upon the cadets&apos; attitudes toward diversity and pluralism. Additionally, the historical research phase enabled the researcher to contemplate the etic issues (presuppositions and philosophical positions gleaned from theory and literature) and to consider the emic issues (the discovery from acquaintance with the case) before accomplishing the quantitative research.  The researcher explored a bounded situation at the USAFA: the new Officer Development System, which was unveiled in January 2004 to change the culture and the mechanisms for developing future officers. Thus, the Academy&apos;s leadership, culture, and socialization processes were examined and juxtaposed with the relevant literature regarding human diversity and mentoring principles. Although the new program did not achieve the desired level of impact, improvement of implementation and execution strategies should allow pluralistic mentoring to complement existing programs that professionally develop cadets at the USAFA. Moreover, pluralistic mentoring, when fully embraced, will enable the Academy to produce culturally competent and socially conscious officers who will become Air Force leaders of the twenty-first century.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Higher</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>404</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63191</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63191</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Tuitt, Frank</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salters, Roger</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Summers-Thompson, Sheila</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63330</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T17:43:04Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>INSTITUTIONAL, FINANCIAL, AND STUDENT CHARACTERISTICS AFFECTING PERSISTENCE OF SCHOLARSHIP RECIPIENTS:  A CASE STUDY OF FIRST, SECOND, AND THIRD YEAR STUDENT RETENTION FOR DANIELS FUND SCHOLARS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bean, Beth</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Higher Education</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The purpose of this study was to determine if the academic, financial, or institutional variables successfully predicted undergraduate persistence in first year, second year, and third year private scholarship recipients. This study also explored if student retention was predicted uniquely for members of different races/ethnicities and/or genders. Three-way interactions between persistence, the independent variables, and the moderator variables were examined. Ideally, this study aimed to advance the limited research regarding scholarship persistence and provide some information to increase retention of this unique and growing population.A series of logistic regression analyses were utilized to explore the main research questions. The following variables were statistically significant in predicting the persistence of scholarship recipients: high school GPA, college GPA, Daniels Fund Scholarship award, EFC, Federal Pell grant, other scholarship awards, work study, institutional control, cost of attendance, institutional size, institutional diversity, and geographical location. However, the statistically significant variables predicting student retention varied by year in college, gender, and race/ethnicity. Academic variables showed relevance earlier in a scholar&apos;s college career, while financial variables were more relevant in later years. Institutional variables showed a mild direct influence on persistence particularly for female students.  The independent variables that created a statistically significant interaction with gender and race/ethnicity included: high school GPA, aptitude test scores, Daniels Fund Scholarship award, work study, institutional type, institutional diversity, institutional type, institutional control, institutional size, institutional quality, and cost of attendance.Several recommendations for future research were drawn from the literature and the study findings including 1) segregating the population into subgroups for analysis, 2) examining possible two-way and three-way interaction effects between the independent variables, moderator variables, and persistence, 3) analyzing persistence by academic year, and 4) exploring how different types and combinations of financial aid variables influence the persistence of scholarship recipients. Additionally, three recommendations were offered for private scholarship providers including 1) all scholarship recipients are created equal, but they are not equal, 2) know not only your scholars but the institutions they are attending, and 3) customize scholarships based upon the students&apos; total financial aid package and individual scholar information.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Education, Higher--Persistence--Retention--Scholarship recipients--Finanical characteristics</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>336</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63330</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63330</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Lovell, Cheryl D.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Green, Kathy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Vaccaro, Annemarie</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Bacon, Don</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63149</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T17:50:20Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Instructions on the Removal of Birds from the Head</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Howard, Gregory Edwin</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>English</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Instructions on the Removal of Birds from the Head is a work of fiction composed of fragments, anecdotes, self-contained stories, unfinished stories, lists, and vignettes--all of which  relate to an unknown disease that surfaces among the populace in an unknown country.  The book  details the disease&apos;s many and seemingly unrelated symptoms, the stories of patients and presumed patients&apos; experience with the disease, the attempt by four doctors to understand and diagnose it, and the world that created it.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Literature, American</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>96</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63149</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63149</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hunt, Laird</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sheinbaum, Jack</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ramke, Bin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kiteley, Brian</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63579</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T17:52:28Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Japan&apos;s Missile Defense</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Namatame, Norifumi</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>For some years, Japan has pursued its own missile defense system in cooperation with the United States. The Japanese government claims that the missile defense (JMD) program is purely defensive and will not pose a threat to other countries. JMD may seem justified by North Korea&apos;s development of ballistic missiles and nuclear weapons. However, neighboring states regarded it as a sign of military ambition and revival of Japan&apos;s prewar militarism. The development and deployment of JMD could have grave implications for regional and global security. This dissertation focuses on these implications, domestic and international political considerations and the future direction of Japan&apos;s defense and security policy.After the Cold War, when the superpowers maintained strategic stability with massive offensive nuclear arsenals (mutual assured destruction--MAD), new threats from rogue states and terrorists have forced us to rethink the credibility of MAD. But attempts to build shields against nuclear ballistic missiles could trigger a new phase of the arms race pitting offensive vs. defensive capabilities. The author argues that defense must be emphasized in order to achieve stability and security (mutual defense emphasis--MDE). Characterization of JMD as truly defensive or not depends on theoretical and strategic viewpoints. The key is the distinction between defense and offense, and whether Japan will emphasize defense, and convince other states that its strategic intentions are really defensive.For the Japanese, with their dual realist and pacifist identities, JMD can be a tool of either realist military strategy or pacifist arms control. Japan should choose defensive realism, including MDE arms control, as a middle way that may eventually open a pacifist route to disarmament. With the world&apos;s most sophisticated technology and a tradition of pacifism, Japan is in a unique and advantageous position to promote arms control.In pursuit of JMD, the Japanese government should not only promote arms control and MDE--building missile shields against rogue and terrorist missile attacks or accidental or unauthorized launches, but also advance offensive arms reduction among major states. Japan can and must become a leader in such a shift toward a less dangerous world.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>246</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63579</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63579</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Goldfischer, David</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Van Ness, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Viotti, Paul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63578</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T17:54:13Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Japanese Worldviews, Ideologies, and Foreign Aid Policy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Shannon, Richard Warren</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Josef Korbel School of International Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This project studies the ideational factors influencing Japanese foreign aid policy. It builds on previous research in political science on perception and foreign policy decision-making, Japanese political economy, economic and technological development, foreign aid, and in anthropology on perception, worldview, and international development.The main goal of the research is to answer the question of how Japan&apos;s historical experiences with technology, development, and foreign relations (and key leaders&apos; views of those areas) from 1850 to 1945 have influenced current aid policies. Second, the project aims to answer whether the Japanese development concepts of &quot;modernization,&quot; internationalization and translative adaptation accurately reflect Japan&apos;s own experience. Third, the project asks how spirituality and religion may be influencing current aid policies.In the research, I review key contexts of Japan&apos;s historical experience from 1850 to 1945 in several important areas. I also study the beliefs and worldviews (cognitive frameworks) of seven key Japanese leaders for the same period: Fukuzawa Yukichi, Mori Arinori, Ito Hirobumi, Yamagata Aritomo, Kato Hiroyuki, Yanagita Kunio, and Emperor Hirohito. I analyze these historical experiences and leaders&apos; views through analytical concepts and lenses from political science, anthropology, and economics, in three main areas: development, technology, and cognition.Among my key findings are that there is much continuity between Japan&apos;s prewar culture of politics and the postwar system, including examples and ideas, which shape the policy environment in which Japan&apos;s aid operates. Many of these are negative in nature, and some are ideas based on Japan&apos;s own development experience. Several key lessons emerge, including the importance of: 1) a strong civil society to prevent abusive politics for the achievement of Japan&apos;s national interests, whether in its prewar politics or the current aid system; 2) a strong, effective state for encouraging successful development; 3) Japan&apos;s development experience for other regions (if carefully applied); and 4) the concept of translative adaptation, the idea that each nation&apos;s development must be customized for its own conditions and experiences. I conclude that Japan needs better consideration of ground level factors in its assessments of ODA policy and international affairs.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Ph.D.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations--Anthropology, Cultural--Religion, General--Foreign aid--Ideology--Japan--Policy--Religion--Worldview</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>912</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63578</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63578</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Szyliowicz, Joseph S</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Van Arsdale, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Khan, Haider</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hamilton, Sarah</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63150</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T17:55:52Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>JUSTIFYING AN ATTACK ON CIVIL LIBERTIES: THE 2006 USA PATRIOT ACT REAUTHORIZATION SENATE DEBATES</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bordogna-Weeks, Melissa Anne</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Human Communications</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The current research examines the U.S. Senate transcripts of the 2006 USA PATRIOT Act Reauthorization debates.  In particular, the study identifies how objections to reauthorization were raised and advance by opponents as well as the subsequent responses by advocates of the legislation.  The arguments were analyzed from a pragmatic justificatory perspective which was augmented with three additional theories--collective imagining, strategic maneuvering and political reasonableness.  Three primary arguments emerged within the discourse of the opposition.  The first concerned particular legal flaws within the Act and proposed amendments, the second involved the ideal of liberty, and the third dealt with the manipulation of Senate processes and procedures.  It was discovered that both opponents and advocates drew upon notions of the reasonable when arguing their positions and maneuvered strategically to in order advance their agendas.  The arguments which were deemed strongest, most closely adhered to the six principles of pragmatic justification.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Speech Communication--Language, Rhetoric and Composition--Political Science, General--Argumentation; U.S. Senate; debates; rhetoric; justification; senate debates</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>171</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63150</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63150</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Hicks, Darrin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Dobyns, Ann</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wood, Roy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Foust, Christina</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63070</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T17:57:56Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62795</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Managing Uncertainty in Spatiotemporal Databases</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alkobaisi, Shayma</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Computer Science</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Applications that deal with large sets of Moving Objects (MOs) continue to
grow, and so does the demand for an efficient data management and query processing systems supporting MOs. Application examples include location-based services, transportation management and mobile networks, which require an efficient database management system that is able to store, update, and query a large
number of continuously changing MOs. Major challenges for developing such
systems are due to the fact that the actual data object reports its state, which is associated with one or more properties (e.g., geographic location and velocity), that can continuously change over time, however, it is only possible to discretely record the object&apos;s states. All the missing or non-recorded states collectively form
the uncertainty of the object&apos;s history.This dissertation reviews existing uncertainty models and proposes a more efficient model called the Tornado model that reduces the size of uncertainty regions resulting in less false hits, thus improving the efficiency of the database management
system. The Tornado model resulted in an average reduction of 94% in the uncertainty volume over the Cone model - one of the most common uncertainty models in spatiotemporal databases.To be practically viable, each uncertainty model must be paired with appropriate approximations of uncertainty regions that can be used for indexing. This is due to the two-phase query processing system consisting of the refinement phase
and the filtering phase. In this dissertation, we propose Minimum Bounding Rectangle (MBR) approximations for three uncertainty models including the Tornado
model; we also propose an estimated MBR for the Tornado model that achieves a good balance between accuracy and computation efficiency. The estimated MBR of the Tornado model reduced the number of false hits by 29% on average over the Cone model.Finally, this dissertation presents the Truncated Tornado model - an uncertainty model as a significant advance in minimizing uncertainty regions associated with MOs. This model achieves the reduction in uncertainty regions by removing
sub-areas that are unreachable considering the maximum velocity and acceleration of the MOs. We combine the Truncated Tornado model with an approximation technique called Tilted Minimum Bounding Box (TMBB) to make the indexing of the uncertainty regions more efficient. Experimental results showed that the Truncated
Tornado in TMBB resulted in an average volume reduction of 96% over the
axis-parallel MBB of the Cone model.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>PhD</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Computer Science--Uncertainty; spatiotemporal databases</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>112</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63070</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63070</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Kim, Seon Ho</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Leutenegger, Scott T.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cohen, Joel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Vojtechovsky, Petr</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>doctoral</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>  
<dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
 </ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
