<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
 <responseDate>2014-05-05T05:32:47Z</responseDate>
 <request verb= "ListRecords">http://digitaldu.coalliance.org/oai2</request>
 <ListRecords>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62736</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-10-05T19:56:36Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62280</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62283</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62278</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62286</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62285</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62281</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62279</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of Institutional Factors on the Retention of Graduate Students of Color in Schools of Library and Information Science</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62736</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63086</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-10-05T19:52:25Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62285</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Women&apos;s Participation in Transitional Justice Mechanisms: Comparing Transitional Processes in Timor Leste and Sierra Leone</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63086</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62566</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-10-05T19:51:37Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62279</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62278</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62285</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Scripting the Docufiction: Combining the Narrative and Documentary Modes in a Social Issue Film</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62566</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62597</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-10-05T19:51:40Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62286</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62283</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62287</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62279</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62281</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Rewriting the Future: The Construction of Masculine Subjectivity within Articulations of Russia&apos;s Post-Soviet National Idea</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62597</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62684</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-10-05T19:51:46Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62286</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62278</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62280</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An Exploration of Identification of Leadership for Gifted Students</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62684</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_62627</identifier>
    <datestamp>2012-10-05T19:51:41Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62283</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62286</setSpec>
    <setSpec>codu_62279</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Revictimization: A Multi-method Approach to Understanding Risk Detection</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>codu:62627</dc:identifier>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55678</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:44Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A 10,000 Year Record of Pre-Columbian Environmental Change From Highland Guatemala</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Caffrey, Maria A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 2007</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>139</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The Huehuetenango region of the Guatemalan Sierra de Los Cuchumantanes is a landscape characterized by extensive human modification surrounded by mountainous terrain that has been significantly deforested in recent centuries for agriculture. The paleoclimatic history of the Guatemalan lowlands has been extensively studied along with the impacts that the Maya had on their environment. This research looks at the impact of climatic change on the highlands environment and how naturally occurring changes agree or differ from lowland records that include potential influences humans. A partial sediment core was taken from a high elevation site in the Huehuetenango region. Radiocarbon dates show that the record extends for most of the Holocene period from 10,240 14C BP until 2850 14C BP. Pollen and macroscopic charcoal analyses in addition to standard geochemical analyses were carried out at close intervals throughout the core in order to determine how vegetation and fire frequencies within the region have changed over time. Data shows that the area underwent a number of periods alternating between warm, dry and cold, wet conditions through the early Holocene until the Middle Preclassic. The outcomes of this research are a record of the impacts of climate change on a landscape that was unmodified by humans that can be used to distinguish between natural and human signals in the lowland data.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55678</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Taylor, Matthew</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2007_Caffrey.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_37750</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:45Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Comparative Analysis of Boundary Locations Established By Climatic Classifications</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bock, Willian Texas</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>August 1964</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>100</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Effort directed toward classification of the world&apos;s climates has produced quite a number of systems in the past three-quarters of a century. A number of the more recently developed ones, similarly based on climate-vegetation relationships, appear to have a high degree of climate boundary locational agreement despite differences la boundary criteria and classification organisation. It is the purpose of this study to ex¬amine a cross-section of relatively current climatic classifications (1) to determine the amount of agreement and disagreement among specific boundary locations, especially where extremes occur, and (2) if boundary patterns exist, to consider their significance. The classifications selected for boundary comparisons are those of W. Koppen, C. W. Thorathwaite, A. A. Miller, M. Vahl, and N. N. Ivanov. These classifications were chosen because they represent an international cross-section of classification thinking; they are relatively current classifications; they vary in complexity, and each is somewhat unique; but all have a common basis and purpose. For treatment in this study, like subdivisions of these classifications are organised into five major climate groups, each including groups and subgroups of the selected classifications. The group boundaries are compared on a world basis and the subgroup boundaries are compared only in selected areas. This procedure reveals some interesting conclusions. Even though boundaries generally shew locational disagreement, there is a fundamental similarity of pattern. Terrain appears to be of even greater importance as a climatic classification control than popularly believed. It appears that the climatologists relied heavily upon vegetation boundaries in areas of extreme climate where less climatic data is available. There is, however, essentially no difference in the amount of agreement and disagreement between boundary locations in areas where climatic data are scarce, and where data are plentiful.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:37750</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Rudd, Robert D.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1964_Bock.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57896</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:46Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Regional Analysis of Eastern Colorado Streams and a Paleoflood Analysis of First Creek, Rocky Mountain Arsenal, Commerce City, Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Capesius, Joseph Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>November 1996</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>188</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This research examines the applicability of regional flood equations to streams in eastern Colorado. This research also attempts to explain why these equations fail to estimate the 100-year flood magnitude based on systematic and paleoflood data for First Creek, an intermittent stream that flows through the Rocky Mountain Arsenal, a National Wildlife Refuge. Paleoflood reconstruction uses woody debris, cottonwood tree age, and historic accounts as indicators of past floods. From these paleostage indicators, three paleofloods are determined to have occurred. These paleofloods have magnitudes of 3500 fe Is, 2000 fe Is, and tOOOfe Is. The tOO-year discharge determined from -II years of systematic streamflow data and the three paleofloods that occurred during a 30-year historic period is 4430 fe Is. This is substantially smaller than the tOO-year discharge as determined from regional flood equations of Jarrett and McCain (1976) and Livingston and Minges (1987). Three hypotheses are proposed to explain the failure of the regional flood equations to estimate the tOO-year discharge for First Creek. The first hypothesis examines basin lithology and unit discharge. This analysis shows basins developed in consolidated sediment have produced many large unit discharges (e.g., &gt;500 fe Is/mi2)in eastern Colorado while basins developed in unconsolidated sediment have produced few large unit discharge. The second hypothesis shows that, when variations in surficial geology are controlled, maximum observed unit discharges are twice as large for stream basins located in high-relief areas (i.e., above 5000 ft elevation)as for basins located in low-relief areas (i.e., below 4000 ft elevation) in eastern Colorado. The analysis of the third hypothesis shows more extreme precipitation (&gt;6 inches in 24 hours) events have occurred at sites less than 30 miles from large scale topographic rises than at sites beyond 30 miles from large scale topographic rises in eastern Colorado. These are areas with the greatest relief in eastern Colorado. The analysis of the regional flood equations shows that eastern Colorado may not be hydroc1imatically homogenous as previously assumed. This analysis further shows that high-relief areas may be more susceptible to extreme precipitation and flooding than areas with lower relief. Some researchers suggest greater precipitation and flooding occur near abrupt topographic rises in the western United States because of a combination of mechanical or orographic and convective uplift Future research in this area will undoubtedly improve the understanding of catastrophic flooding in eastern Colorado and other Rocky Mountain states.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57896</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Gonzalez, Mark A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1996_Capesius.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57354</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:46Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Spatial Analysis of Selected Private Practice Physicians in Metropolitan Denver, Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bryan, Barbara Maness</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>December 1975</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>175</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This thesis examined the distribution and utilization of physicians within the Denver metropolitan area in 1975 in terms of the central place concepts of threshold and range. Based on the results of previous research it was hypothesized that(1)the offices of physicians providing general medical care are more dispersed throughout metropolitan Denver than the offices of physicians providing specialized care; (2)physicians providing general care serve smaller areas than specialized physicians; and (3) generalists and specialists are influenced by different factors in their choices of office location within metropolitan Denver. A comparison of the office distributions of eight physician specialties by utilization of the nearest neigh-born index failed to support the hypothesis of a greater dispersion of generalists&apos; offices; however, problems associated with the characteristics and calculation of the index may have significantly influenced the results. The greater concentration of generalists&apos; offices in suburban areas and findings in other sections of the study both suggested generalists&apos; offices were more widely dispersed throughout the metropolitan area than were specialists&apos; offices. When the service areas of the physicians were contrasted by comparing the distances traveled by patients to the physician offices, highly significant differences between the specialty groups were indicated by analysis of variance. Denver area residents traveled the shortest distances for general care and the longest distances for specialty care.An analysis of the locational factors and practice characteristics influencing the physician&apos;s choice of office site within metropolitan Denver revealed a very complex interaction of forces.Differences between the practice characteristics and preferences of physicians engaged in various specialties were apparent, and many of the findings suggested that the offices of generalists were likely to be more dispersed than those of specialists.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57354</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Herold, Laurance C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1975_Bryan.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57360</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:46Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Statistical Analysis of Several Factors Influencing Per Capita Consumption of Municipal Water</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hoadley, Jeanne Lynn</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>November 1981</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>88</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The purpose of this study was to identify quantitative relationships Between per capita consumption of water in municipalities of the United States and several factors of climate, standard of living and pricing. Forty cities with 1970 populations ranging from 50,000 to 250,000 were studied.Annual water use for each city was compared with influencing factors using a simple correlation analysis. Seasonal water use representing six month periods was also correlated with climatic factors. Significant relationships were found between water use and precipitation and rainfall minus potential evapotranspiration. Weak relationships were identified with potential evapotranspiration, education level and metering. No relationship was found between water use and temperature, price, or with most socio-economic factors. When water use was broken down into seasonal components very strong relations were found between precipitation and precipitation minus potential evapotranspiration and water use from April to September. No relationship at all was seen between these same factors and water use from October to March.It was concluded that socio-economic factors were overshadowed by the importance of climatic factors but would have shown a stronger relationship in a smaller scale study. The most valuable factors for prediction of water use on a national scale appear to be precipitation and precipitation minus potential evapotranspiration.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57360</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Herold, Laurance C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1981_Hoadley.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57850</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:46Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Synoptic Analysis of Winter Precipitation in California During ENSO Events from 1950 to 1984</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Van Hyning, Conrad</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>1990 August</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>252</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The El Nino/Southern Oscillation (ENSO) phenomenon has very recently been recognized as the dominant global climate signal on time scales of a few months to a few years. It is associated with major dislocations of the rainfall regime in the tropics, and has begun to be associated with unusual winter conditions in mid-latitude regions (Rasmusson, 1984). Interest in the ENSO phenomenon began as recently as the mid- 1960s, when its significance to global climate was first realized. Much of the current understanding of ENSO is the result of the occurrence of nine events since 1950, providing the opportunity for comprehensive research of the phenomenon with modern climate data. The purpose of this research is to analyze relationships between regional mid-tropospheric (500 mb) circulation and precipitation in California during winter, especially with respect to winters associated with ENSO events. Appropriate analytical and descriptive methodologies of synoptic climatology will be used. Synoptic climatology is the study of the dominant circulation patterns of the mid-troposphere which create and influence surface weather (Barry and Perry, 1973). ENSO-related atmospheric research has traditionally made use of synoptic techniques, but to date has focused more upon responses of the global atmospheric circulation to ENSO than upon relationships between ENSO circulation and regional climate. This is especially true with respect to relationships between ENSO circulation and seasonal precipitation in the United States. Thus this research will help to address climatological effects of the ENSO phenomenon currently not well understood. The remainder of this chapter briefly describes the importance of synoptic studies to the understanding of California precipitation, the importance of precipitation to California&apos;s agricultural economy, and the apparent importance of ENSO to both mid-tropospheric circulation and California precipitation. The problem statement, subproblems and hypotheses addressing relationships between 500 mb circulation, ENSO and California precipitation are also enumerated.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57850</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Keables, Michael J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1990_Hyning.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_38532</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:47Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Theoretical Study Of Geographic Reality And Human Concepts</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stevens, Charles Rolfe</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>February 1968</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>121</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>An understanding of human behavior within the man-environment system requires both analysis of the physical influences of the environment and recognition of the purposes, prejudices, and capacities of man. Exclusive application of one of two parallel theories, environmental determinism or cultural determinism, generally results in incomplete explanation. It is suggested that the problem may be resolved through analysis of human attitudes, concepts, and images that relate to the environment. Human concepts of geographic reality are derived from those elements of reality which man&apos;s perceptual systems are able to detect, and from the full spectrum of man&apos;s culture, experience, personality, and motivation. These concepts become the operational basis for adaptation to and manipulation of the geographic environment. Thus the meaning of a given environment to a particular society or individual relates to a specific context of time, place, and culture. If geographical significance is dependent on both external reality and internal human qualities, &quot;raw&quot; data are in-sufficient for most human needs. The subjective factor in environmental observation and evaluation thus becomes not only inevitable but also necessary. Subjective and contextual factors are present in the writings of explorers and geographers. Explorers tend to be mission oriented or programmed in terms of a particular society and a particular goal. Geographers as scientists tend to operate within a context which relates to culture and personality, and attempts to achieve &quot;pure&quot; objectivity in a field which is essentially human oriented may not be appropriate.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:38532</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Crain, Clark N.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1968_Stevens.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55711</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:47Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Agriculturally Critical Area Information as a Planning Tool in Rappahannock County -- Baseline 1977</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Cheeseman, Valerie C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>December 1979</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>122</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Important farmlands as defined by the U.S. Soil Conservation Service (SCS) are disappearing the fastest in the Southeast Region of the U.S. Permanent loss of important farmlands to urban and built-up uses depletes the nation&apos;s renewable resource base. Prime farmlands, a sub-category of important farmlands. need to be identifies and mapped for conservation purposes in the face of future physical development. Primary and secondary data sources can be combined to provide information useful to land use planners. The purpose of the research was to supply statistical and geographic data on prime farmlands in an area experiencing physical development pressures. Rappahannock county, Virginia, in the Southeast Region, fit this purpose, for it is experiencing changes in land use, but still maintains rural characteristics. The objectives were to measure haw much prime farmland existed in the County. how much land has been brought into crop use, how much farmland has been lost to urban and built-up uses, where the losses of prime farmland are the heaviest and where future losses may occur. It was through a combination of primary and secondary data sources that the objectives were met. The procedure devised to meet the objectives was twofold. NASA Black and White medium scale photography was manually classified into 18 prime farmlands related land use and land cover categories of two levels--Level II (U.S. Geological Survey, Anderson and others, 1976) and Level III (USGS modified--user created). Farm plans provided information on cropland to complete the land use and land cover data base. SCS soil survey information was manually transferred and combined with the land use and land cover data to complete the prime farmland soils data base. The research provided a geographic baseline (1977) distribution and measurement of land use and land cover and prime farmland soils. Results were two thematic maps showing the location of 18 land use and land cover categories and of prime farmland soil series, and area measurements for each category. Measurements of prime farmland areas occupied by urban and built-up uses (lost prime farmlands) were very small--165.9 acres. Trends of losses can be used in formulation measures to preserve the majority of prime farmland (11,877.1 acres). For rural counties with limited planning capabilities, this technique required minimal equipment and training and could provide needed information on farmland resources.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55711</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Longbrake, David B.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1979_Cheeseman.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58131</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:47Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An Analysis of Bat Activity Patterns Along a Prairie Riparian Corridor in Eastern Montana at Multiple Spatial Scales</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stewart, Joanne E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>November 2007</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>147</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Few studies have been devoted to the ecology of bats inhabiting prairie landscapes. Existing studies have indicated the importance of riparian corridors as foraging habitat for prairie bats, but resource partitioning and the landscape factors influencing patterns of riparian habitat use are relatively unknown. This research investigates the relationship between bat spatial activity patterns along the Missouri River in eastern Montana and landscape characteristics using cover type classification and remote sensing analysis at three spatial scales: local (50 m), regional (2 Ian), and landscape (15 Ian). Twelve bat species were detected in the study&apos; area, including a considerable expansion of the known range for the spotted bat (Euderma maculatum). Riparian forest edge habitat accounted for the highest bat activity. However, the EPFU/LANO/LACI phonic group exhibited a strong bias towards all riparian forest habitats. Remote sensing analysis revealed that landscape characteristics at the 2 Ian spatial scale were the strongest predictors of bat activity. A heterogeneous landscape was the best predictor of bat activity for the 40 kHz phonic group. However, a consistent positive correlation was found between activity for the EPFU/LANO/LACI phonic group and percent of forested land cover. This research suggests that riparian cottonwood forest, especially the ecotone between riparian forest and open vegetation, provides important habitat for bats in eastern Montana and might be a limiting factor to bat distributions and abundance on prairie landscapes. Furthermore, the surrounding landscape matrix should be a consideration when managing prairie riparian zones for bat communities and prioritizing areas for conservation.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58131</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Sullivan, Donald G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2007_Stewart.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57510</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:47Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An Analysis of Gully and Drainage Basin Relationships in East-Central Wyoming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Berry, David A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>March 1987</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>213</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This research attempts to identify significant statistical relationships between drainage basin characteristics and gully morphology.The drainage basin variables of area, aspect, relief ratio, average slope, elongation ratio, percent bare soil, percent silt and clay content of soil; and the gully variables of length, slope, average width, average depth, averaged width to depth ratio, average cross-section area and volume are measured for 29 first and second order gully and drainage basin net¬works in east-central Wyoming. The basins are located on unmined land adjacent to the Glenrock Coal Company, Dave Johnston Mine. The local climate is semiarid. The gullies have developed in alluvial material that is deposited over the Wasatch and Fort Union Formations, and they are tributary to the Dry Fork Cheyenne River and to the North Platte River. Local vegetation consists of short grasses and sagebrush common to the Northern Great Plains. Data are derived through a combination of field measurement, map analysis and laboratory procedures. Bivariate and multivariate correlation and regression techniques are used to identify significant statistical relationships between basin and gully characteristics. The drainage basin area variable is significantly and positively related to the first and second order gully variables of length, average width, average depth, average cross-section area and volume. Basin area is significantly and negatively related to first and second order gully floor slope. Average basin slope exhibits a significant, positive relationship with first and second order gully length and first order gully volume, and a significant, negative relationship with gully floor slope. Percent bare soil is significantly and positively related to the first order gully variables of length, average width and volume, and is significantly and negatively related to the first order gully slope variable. No other reliable significant relationships are identified. The research findings suggest that gully morphometry results not only from fluvial scour processes, but also from gully wall mass-movement processes. The results also indicate that many of the documented relationships between basin characteristics and hydrologic and erosional processes, for large scale drainage systems may not apply to small scale gully systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57510</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Toy, Terrence J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1987_Berry.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_38530</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:47Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An Analysis Of The Hammond Landform Classification System For Use At Large Scales</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hallett, Richard A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>August 1967</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>203</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Edwin. K. Haamond developed In 1954 and refined in 1964, a landform classification system which he applied to small scale maps. In this thesis large scale (1:24,000) U.S.G.S. topographic maps were tested using Hammond&apos;s classification criteria. Only four of twenty-eight test areas received the sans landform classification as on the Hammond landform map of the United states. By making minor modifications in the classification criteria, twenty-five of the test areas matched the Hammond classification. The modified Hammond system therefore, can be usable for large scale landform analysis. To aid in illustrating the Hammond classification system, forty-three block diagrams of the landform types that occur in the United States are included in the study.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:38530</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1967_Hallett.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57359</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:47Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An Analysis of the Hillslope-Floodplain Boundary</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rudd, Lawrence P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>December 1980 </dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>203</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The basal hillslope endpoint is studied on concave-convex hillslopes bordering floodplains. The purpose of this study is to establish a definition of the hillslope-floodplain boundary according to formative process. The physical characteristics of the sediments deposited on each landform are believed to reflect the distinctive processes involved in the formation of each landform. The study area is located in the drainage basin of Fountain Creek, about two miles northeast of Pinon, Colorado. This area has a mid-latitude steppe, a semiarid climate and is underlain by nearly flat lying Pierre Shale of upper Cretaceous age. All of the hillslopes used in this study are located in third order drainage basins. Analysis of the particle size distributions of hillslope and floodplain sediments revealed that the hillslope-floodplain boundary takes the form of a broad transition zone in the study area and cannot be located within the 1.5 foot soil sampling interval used in the study. Neither the verbal description of the sorting of each soil sample nor a comparison of soil organic content to distance downslope could be used to distinguish between hillslope and floodplain sediments. Three size parameters (median, mean, and sorting) of the soil samples taken furthest on the floodplain side of all the sampling areas studied were found to be significantly different, at the 5%level, from soil samples taken furthest on the hillslope side of all the sampling areas indicating that the hillslope-floodplain boundary occurs within this transition zone. The hillslope-floodplain transition zone could not be narrowed to one sampling interval when the individual soil samples were compared using bivariate scattergrams,correlation and regression analysis, and a second paired t-test. On none of the hillslopes studied could the hillslopefloodplain boundary be located using three hillslope endpoint definitions proposed in the literature, consequently, no comparison was made between the different definitions of the basal hillslope endpoint. In conclusion it is suggested that the shale lithology and small drainage basin order in the study area had the greatest influence on the inability of this study to locate the hillslope floodplain boundary.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57359</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Toy, Terrence J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1967_Hallett.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_38531</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:48Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An Energy Balance Index Of Potential Evapotranspiration With Application To An Irrigated Arid Region</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Walker, Wayland Joseph</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>January 1967</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>145</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The fundamental problem underlying this study is a threatening world food crisis that may accompany the population explosion of the twentieth century. Temperate and tropical regions have historically been able to supply adequate food, fiber and forage supplies to meet demand. Arid regions by necessity are now being developed at a quickening rate. With increased technology these dry regions not only have the potential to meet the challenge but could eventually surpass the agricultural yields of temperate and tropical zones. A multitude of interdisciplinary soil, plant, water, and social studies are required to bring arid zone technology to the point of fruition. These studies run the gamut from theoretical through basic and applied research. The diversity of information and new knowledge needed is manifold. This thesis is primarily concerned with one important aspect of the expansive problem, namely, the loss of water to the atmosphere. The limiting combined loss of water to the atmosphere by evaporation plus transpiration was termed, by C.W. Thornthwaite, potential evapotranspiration. Numerous scientists, it is shown, have contributed to the study of this phenomenon. They have, by and large, concluded that only four climatological factors influence the global rate and quantity of water loss to the atmosphere. These four factors are solar radiation, temperature, humidity, and wind. For arid regions, solar radiation and temperature are deemed adequate indices of potential evapotranspiration. An energy-balance index of potential evapotranspiration is set forth using solar radiation and temperature as basic ingredients. The empirical formula proposed appears consistent with theoretical energy balance foundations. A procedure for bridging the gap between potential evapotranspiration and crop consumptive use is presented. The methodology used leans heavily upon the work of Blaney, Criddle, and Fireman, noted workers in this field of study. Indigenous characteristics which should be considered in applying the proposed index and methodology to an arid region are stated to be; (1) Cropping Intensity (2) Cropping Pattern (3) Cropping Period (4) Culturable Area A simple case study of the Northern Zone of West Pakistan shows how the foregoing information can be put together to predict future Irrigation water requirement and thereby open the door to intelligent planning in arid irrigation economies.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:38531</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1967_W_Walker.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55688</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:48Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An Evaluation of Spatial Forecasting Techniques Used in Tactical Crime Analysis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Van Auken, John B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 2005</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>204</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Spatial forecasting is used in tactical crime analysis to &quot;predict&quot; the area of a future event in a crime series. This allows law enforcement to take a proactive approach to criminal activity instead of a reactive approach. The concept has received recent publicity and scrutiny as a valuable new option in law enforcement due to various successes across the country. A survey of the crime analysis community on the use of spatial forecasting techniques was conducted to determine the most popular techniques in use today. The Minimum Convex Polygon, 68% and 95% Standard Deviation Rectangles, 50% and 90% Jennrich-Turner Ellipses, and Kernel Smoothing based on Spider Distance Analysis were determined to be the more prevalent techniques. These methods were looked at in depth for their ability to &quot;forecast&quot; the area within which the next event in a crime series will occur by evaluating them on thirty-one solved crime series. The series were collected from various analysts across the country, have a varying number of events and geographic distribution, and are of different crime types. The techniques were evaluated on the number of correct predictions and size of forecasted areas. The history and evolution of these techniques towards use in crime analysis is discussed, along with the possibilities for future research.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55688</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Sutton, Paul C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>Van_Auken_Spatial_Forecasting.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57844</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:48Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analysis of Warm-Season Precipitation Around the Palmer Divide, East-Central Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schaer, Barry C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1984</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>213</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>A southwest to northeast increase in the warm-season rainfall distribution was shown by trend surface analysis. Residuals from the analysis identified a zone of greater precipitation, coincident with the previously-mentioned exception. Seasonal rainfall varied on the temporal level.Two precipitation maxima occur during the warm season: one in the 2nd week (approximately June 7-14), and one in the 8th week (Approximately July 20-26). These peak periods vary in magnitude spatially north versus south of the Palmer Divide.The influence of the Palmer Divide during the warm season is less significant and more spatially limited than previously thought.Its significance and areal limitations may differ when considered on an annual basis.The author suggests these topics, as well as additional research on the temporal aspects of precipitation in semi-arid areas, as directions for further research.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57844</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Herold, Laurance C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1984_Schaer.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58121</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:48Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Anomalous Water Balances and Mid-Tropospheric Circulation in the Contiguous United States From 1946 to 1994</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wedgeworth, Connie S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date></dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>213</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The purpose of this study was to identify abnormally dry and wet events and describe their associated 500-millibar circulation patterns. The abnormally dry and wet events were defined using the Palmer Drought Severity Index (PDSI). Most events had qualifying PDSI divisions that occurred west ofthe - Mississippi River. The anomalously wet and dry episodes mainly occurred in summer and fall and lasted from four to 19 months. The associated 500-millibar patterns frequently indicated dry air mass flow into an area for dry events. During wet events, the 500-millibar patterns sometimes indicated enhanced moisture flow into the areas experiencing wet events. The position of the positive height anomaly or negative height anomaly was important in influencing the surface conditions. The position of these positive height anomalies and negative height anomalies can enhance or suppress moisture advection and heat advection into the continent. Moisture and heat (evapotranspiration) are the two main influences of the watebalance of an area. Wet events were more difficult to associate with 500-millibar patterns since they events are not always synoptic in nature, especially during summer when convection plays a large role in precipitation throughout the contiguous United States.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58121</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Keables, Michael J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2001_Wedgeworth.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57647</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:48Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Approximating IN-SITU Hydrologic Properties of Soils From Measurements of Mass Per Unit Volume of Saturated Soil Samples</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Keffelew, Berhanamaskal</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>April 1986</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>73</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The relationship between water in soil and associated vegetation,has long been of great concern. Much has been done to define methods to determine factors influencing permeability and the proportion of water in the soil that is actually available for plant growth. Permeability is influenced by factors that affect porosity;while available moisture is characteristically determined from the difference in quantities of water retained between field capacity and the wilting point of vegetation. Techniques have been developed to measure porosity, the ability of soils to retain water against the force of gravity at field capacity, and the ability of plants to extract water from the soil to the wilting point. The major problem with most of these techniques is that the required equipment and laboratory facilities are too expensive to be used extensively in developing nations of the Third World, like Ethopia. The objective of this research project is to evaluate a simple method that could be used extensively to define factors that control soil permeability and availability of water from soils. Applicable methods were described by Wilcox (1951) and Richards and others (1954). Wilcox (1951) defined a technique for determining the water content of soils at saturation from measurements of the mass per unit volume of saturated soil samples. Richards and others (1954), working at the U.S. Salinity Laboratory, observed that there were relationships between water content of soil at saturation and the water content at either field capacity or the wilting point. Use of similar but more refined, relationships defined by Miller and Branson(in review), permits approximation of water content at various levels of retention froce for soils with similar saturation capacities.It will also facilitate computation of void space available for drainage. Since the dry weight of the soil sample that has been saturated can also be approximated, it is possible to compute insitu water content and volume weight. Volume weight, in turn, can be used to determine the capacity of voids for water. To accomplish this, soil samples must be obtained in a manner that permits measurement of differences in volume weight with increasing depth.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57647</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1986_Keffelew.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57848</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:48Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Center-Pivot Irrigated Land and the Effects of the Ogallala Aquifer Depetion, Kit Carson County, Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Giannetti, Claudia Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>November 1992</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>136</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Irrigated agriculture is one of the major economic activities in Kit Carson County, Colorado. Irrigation is dependent solely on water from the Ogallala Aquifer. Irrigated agriculture has developed extensively over the past three decades because of plentiful amounts of groundwater and the introduction of center-pivot irrigation systems. However, reported water level declines have caused concerns about the future of irrigation in the area. This research evaluates whether depletion of the Ogallala Aquifer in Kit Carson County, Colorado between 1976 and 1988: (1) caused a decrease in center-pivot irrigation; (2) caused a change in the types of crops (from high water-demanding to less water-demanding crops) grown on center-pivot irrigated plots; and (3) resulted in a greater change in the number of acres irrigated by center-pivot in the western or eastern sections of the county. Air photographs, statistical analysis and sampling methods were used to evaluate these changes. A survey was conducted to obtain subjective information from farmers who were irrigating with center-pivot sprinklers since 1976. The results of simple correlation, used to measure the strength of the relationship between water level decline and center-pivot irrigated acres, indicated little or no association between the Ogallala Aquifer depletion and center-pivot irrigated acres. The Chi square test, used to determine if the magnitude of change in the acreage planted with high water-demanding and less water-demanding crop categories was significant, indicated that there was an increase in the acreage of less water-demanding crops. Finally, the Chi-square test also indicated that there has been a greater decrease in the number of center-pivot irrigated acres in the western half of the county than in the eastern half of the county. The findings suggest that adjustments in irrigated agricultural practices have been initiated in order to adapt to the Ogallala Aquifer&apos;s water level declines.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57848</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Herold, Laurance C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1992_Gianetti.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_38545</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:49Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Characteristics and Rates of Thermal Erosin Barrow, Alaska</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lewellen, Robert I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Griffiths, Thomas M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>December 1965</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>226</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>In the vicinity of Barrow, Alaska, the tundra-covered mainland of the Arctic Coastal Plain is eroding thermally. The upper several meters of perennially frozen ground consists of fine-grained, ice-cemented sediment, large quantities of buried peat, and massive ice wedges. The seasonally thawed soil is approximately 40 cm deep. The mechanisms of erosion include: undercutting, the formation of thermo-erosional niches and collapse, slumping and saturated flow of thawed soil and exposed sediment, and ice-wedge depletion. Rates of erosion have been determined for a tundra stream, along 75 km of the Elson Lagoon coastline, and along selected lake shorelines. The measurements were made from aerial photography compiled over the past 16 years. Locally, the shorelines are retreating differentially as a function of cliff exposure, sediment composition, currents, depth of offshore water, and wind generated waves. Erosion along selected portions of the Elson Lagoon shoreline ranges from amounts too small to be measured effectively, along sheltered areas, to 10.4 meters per year by Olkralik Point where the shore is exposed to the Beaufort Sea. Rate of shoreline retreat for selected points on the oriented lakes ranged from less than 0.3 to 3.6 meters per year. Many of the lakes are being revegetated. The Footprint Creek area was studied for changes caused by an increase in watershed area and precipitation. A nick point retreat rate of 3 meters per year was measured between 1952 and 1962. A rate of 28 meters per year for 1962 and 1963 was measured after heavy precipitation.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:38545</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1966_Lewellen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57847</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:49Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Colorado Atlas Project</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wright, Patrick J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1991</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>194</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The Colorado Atlas Project was developed to establish the foundation for an electronic atlas of the state of Colorado by the University of Denver Geography Department. The Geography Department intends to produce such an atlas using a geographic information system (GIS). The data base created in the Colorado Atlas Project will have the potential for use as an electronic as well as text atlas. The goals for the Colorado Atlas Project are to establish standards for and to determine the feasibility of creating an electronic atlas. This manuscript outlines research designed to identify and evaluate the initial groundwork in producing an electronic atlas as well as a GIS of the State of Colorado. Chapter II, &quot;Basic Map Theory&quot;, reviews the fundamental map theory that is the framework of all superior cartographic achievement. Chapter II, will discuss the fundamental principals of map scale, map accuracy, map projection and the application of text or annotation. Chapter II will also discuss the graphic design principals of lines, linesymbols, and symbology. Chapter III, Atlas Review&quot;, is a comprehensive review of five atlases selected to discuss the theory behind the design principals and cartographic techniques used in atlases. Chapter III presents the cartographic techniques and theory used in the creation of published atlases. By applying the knowledge acquired in chapter II, the atlas review identifies the positive and negative aspects of the subjects portrayed, the cartographic techniques employed, and formats used in the creation of the reviewed atlases. Chapter IV, &quot;Software&quot;, presents a brief overview of the capabilities of the GIS software used to complete the project. Chapter IV will explain the benefits of using a GIS in the creation of an atlas. Chapter IV will also review the capabilities of the computerized drafting software, (Informap) and the GIS software, (EMIS) of the Synercom package. Chapter V, &quot;Colorado Atlas Project&quot;, is a description of the design decisions and methodology used to create the required maps for the Colorado Atlas Project. Chapter V explains the design decisions made and methodology used in the creation of the base map and six thematic maps for the Colorado Atlas Project. Each overlay within the base map and each thematic map created is discussed in detail emphasizing cartographic design, source, classification scheme and methodology used in the creation of each.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57847</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Keables, Michael J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1991_Wright.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57353</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:50Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Critical Area Analysis: A Geographic Perspective of Interchange Area Development</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Turk, David J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>August 1973</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>181</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Freeway interchanges have become the hew foci of this nation&apos;s urban access systems. As such they have become critical areas in terms of planning. Interchanges may be areas of great development opportunity, However, they may also become areas of potential congestion and nuisance as well. There is a gap in highway impact knowledge in the understanding of the dynamic aspects of urban interchange development. Experimental work has not been done with areas prone to overdevelopment, and studies of land use control, conducted in critical areas, have not differentiated specific interchange development problems. There is a need for research in urban interchange areas to: (1) provide a basis for future experimental work, and (2) provide a methodology for analyzing specific critical area problems so that land use controls may be appropriately matched to the difficulties at hand. In this research, the following steps were carried out to pursue.the above goals. (1) Interchanges were selected and study areas delineated. (2) Land use maps of the study zones around the interchanges were made. (3) Assessments were made of the land use changes occurring after interchange completion. (4) Congestion at the interchanges was assessed. (5) Zoning histories were noted for each of the areas. (6) With this data bank, the nature and origins of congestion at each of the sites was analyzed. The interchanges selected for study illustrate a great variety in development and congestion, constituting an adequate test of the methodology&apos;s ability to analyze interchange area development. The first site, while apparently overdeveloped, has had few congestion problems. It combines commercial strip, multi-family housing, and office development. The second location, although moderately developed, cannot handle the traffic needs•demanded of it. It has undergone commercial strip, highway related, and extensive residential development. The final site, is operating quite well at the present, but has experienced rapidly increasing traffic volumes. It has been developed with industrial and office park*, warehouse, and shopping center uses. It was found that congestion at the interchanges studied was not only due to the amount and intensity of development, but to the following factors as well. (1) The balance of in and out flows during peak traffic periods. (2) The degree of trip dispersal throughout the day on the interchange ramps. (3) The proportions of trips generated by the land uses of the study zones using the freeway. (4) The relative proportions of remotely generated traffic using the interchange facility.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57353</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1973_Turk.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_37745</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:50Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Decline Of Great Britain&apos;s Prestige Resulting From The Suez Issue of 1956</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>McDonald, Gordon C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>August 1957</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>142</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Despite a constant reduction in her strength since the early years of the century, Great Britain had until 1956 retained a prestige which had given her great influence in international affairs. During 1956, however, Premier Nasser of Egypt flaunted Britain by nationalising the Suez Canal, which, although located within Egypt and owned by a nominally private company, was considered to be one of Britain&apos;s vital interests, Britain demanded as a minimum basis of agreement that the Canal be placed under international control. The United Nations did not support Britain&apos;s stand. After four months of fruitless negotiation, Britain and France attacked Egypt a few days after Israel launched an attack upon Egypt&apos;s forces in the Sinai Peninsula, The United States, Russia and an overwhelming majority of the United Nations then brought their collective power to bear upon Britain and France forcing them to halt their forces before achieving control of the Suez Canal. Having attacked despite almost universal opposition, and then succumbed to pressure without achieving her objective, Britain suffered a serious loss of prestige, America, Russia, the Arab nations, and many other nations joined in censure of Britain, The miscalculations of Britain&apos;s government, led by Mr. Anthony Eden, resulted in serious economic as well as political losses.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:37745</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1957_McDonald.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57893</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:51Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of Selected Roadcut Reclamation Practices and Environmental Factors on Shrubs Planted in the Lake Tahoe Basin</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Watson, Linda K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1992</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>296</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>In the fall of 1972 and 1973, several California Department of Transportation roadcuts in the Lake Tahoe basin were stabilized as part of a highway reclamation project. Dr. Andrew T. Leiser, professor of environmental horticulture at the University of California, Davis, directed the project with the objectives of stabilizing slopes and experimenting with various reclamation techniques. Shrub species were selected for revegetation, and planted following interim stabilization measures. The present research project is a follow-up study of long-term revegetation success on the roadcuts reclaimed by Dr. Leiser in 1972 and 1973. In August, 1988, field work for this research project was undertaken to analyze the effect of some of the reclamation methods on the longterm survival of selected shrub species. Results of the research suggest that certain species may benefit from spring planting. Generally, however, certain reclamation techniques such as fertilization, the use of rock breast walls for purposes other than slope stabilization and differences in such environmental factors as amounts of solar radiation and slope length, within certain ranges, may not affect long-term survival of shrubs at this location.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57893</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Toy, Terrence J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1992_Watson.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_37740</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:51Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Enviromental Adaptations In The Western Sheep Industry</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Griffiths, Thomas M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>December 1948</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>183</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The study examines the environment in which the sheep industry of the western United States has operated from the time of the industry&apos;s introduction by the Spanish culture in the 16th century to the present day. The main emphasis is placed upon two aspects of environmental adaptations first, the changes brought about in the industry by environmental pressures, and second, the modifications which have been made upon the environment by the industry. The specific environmental factors examined include the physical habitat, historical development of the industry, the operational pattern, the public domain, the land use pattern, the political effects of tariffs and subsidies, spatial and locational effects on the economy and marketing process, and modifications in the environment brought on by the pattern and pressure of use. Three primary conclusions are reached: first, the sheep industry has proved to be more adaptable to environ¬mental pressures than the other branches of the western livestock industry; second, where the sheep industry has applied pressure to the carrying capacity of the environment, extensive and injurious modifications have resulted;third, as the industry reaches a locational and spatial maturity, it must decrease its pressure upon the environment, make adjustments to competing uses for the environment, and modify its own operational methods in order to keep the environment on a renewable basis.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:37740</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1948_Griffiths.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55683</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:51Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Establishing a Method for Locating Buried Oxbow Lake Deposits Using Electrical Conductivity, Sacramento Valley, California</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ernenwein, Eileen Gloria</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 2002</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>145</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This study develops a method where electrical conductivity mapping can be used to locate relict oxbow lake sediments, which often have no surface expression. Electrical conductivity mapping was successfully employed to discover six buried oxbow lake deposits, whose presence was confirmed by auger tests. In a meandering river environment, three general types of depositional units are expected: point bars, oxbow lakes, and a number of floodplain depositional facies. Since these three basic depositional units are characterized by distinctly different particle size ranges, they are discernable with geophysical tools that measure the chemical and physical properties of the buried units. To test the ability of EM induction tools to map the location of buried oxbow lake deposits in the middle reach of the Sacramento River Valley, five distinctly different areas were chosen for study. Electrical conductivity maps created with the EM31 device show the bulk conductivity from 1 to 6 meters below the ground. These maps may reveal the location of buried oxbow lake sediments and other associated facies based on the geometry of the conductivity patterns. To evaluate and calibrate these maps, subsurface tests were used to reveal the true nature of the buried sediments. Thus, with only a few carefully placed auger test holes for calibration and a knowledge of the general depositional environments expected in a meandering stream environment, the conductivity maps were used to accurately map the near-surface three-dimensional stratigraphy. In the future studies of this sort can be used as a guide to take intact cores from the buried oxbow lake deposits that have been mapped. If enough are found and numerous cores are taken, dated and analyzed for flood deposits, a flood record could conceivable be constructed going back thousands of years.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55683</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Sullivan, Donald G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2002_Ernenwein.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57894</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:51Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Factors Affecting the Distribution of Lightning-Started Forest Fires in Pike National Forest, Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Torikai, Lori A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>November 1994</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>121</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Lighting is a rare and random occurrence. It follows that lightning started forest fires, a result of lightning, should also be randomly distributed. This is not the case in Pike National Forest, Colorado. The distribution of lightning-started forest fires is clustered in the eastern portion of the forest during the summer months between 1986-1992. Based on 213 lightning caused fire, the factors of elevation, topography, geology, precipitation, temperature, vegetation, and the local meteorology are studied to determine the extent of their relationship with the distribution of lightning-started forest fires. Elevation and topography are presented with the lightning forest fires in the form of map overlays; The average elevation of the fires is approximately 2,400 meters with over 88 percent of the fires below 2,743 meters. The topography of the forest best describes the distribution of fires; the fires predominantly follow the drainage basin of the forest. Lightning-started forest fires are related to geologic type. The fires are superimposed on the bedrock geology and a chi-squared test proves that the distribution is not random. The observed fire frequencies are not what would be expected if the distribution were random between geologic types. Monthly mean precipitation and monthly mean temperature are correlated with the number of fires for each month during the study period. Monthly mean temperature is not related to the number of fires while monthly mean precipitation is inversely related to the number of fires for climate stations in and around the forest. Lighting fires are also related to the vegetation zone. Most fires are within the montane zone and a chi-squared test proves that the distribution is not random within the forest vegetation zones. The local circulation, namely the Denver Convergence Vorticity Zone (DCVZ), is quantified by measuring vorticity between various points. The vorticity points are mapped and classified to describe the nature of the DCVZ circulation at the time of the lightning fire occurrence. With the exception of mean monthly precipitation, lightning-started. forest fires are related to all the aforementioned factors. However, many of the factors studied are inter-related and this is never addressed within the confines of this research.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57894</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1994_Torikai.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58125</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:52Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Fire-Related Sedimentation and the Evolution and Chronology of Alluvial Fans: Spring Creek, Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hunt, Emily P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 2003</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>81</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>A 1996 forest fire in the Buffalo Creek and Spring Creek Watersheds followed by a 100-year precipitation event produced natural exposures to both new and older alluvial-fan stratigraphy. These recent and Holocene alluvial-fan deposits in the Spring Creek watershed were analyzed to interpret the response of alluvial fans to forest fire and other conditions of disequilibrium. In addition, a chronology of basin-wide alluvial fan-building episodes was developed based on the alluvial-fan stratigraphy and relative age-dating techniques. Four generations of alluvial fans were identified, three of which are likely fire-induced depositional events. The size, sedimentology, and stratigraphy of each depositional episode were distinctively varied. While the forest fues likely catalyzed similar geomorphic processes, including increased overland flow and sediment transport, the resulting deposition on alluvial fans was dramatically different. This indicates that throughout the stratigraphic record, the alluvial fans - and the watershed as a whole- have had distinctively different responses to forest fires and the increased sediment availability that typically follows. These differences are likely a result of factors including changes in the climatic regime, precipitation intensity and timing following the fire, burn intensity, and intrinsic sub-basin characteristics.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58125</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Luchsinger, Deborah</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2003_Hunt.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57849</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:52Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Gully Erosion in Northwestern Colorado: A Case Study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Doerner, James Patrick</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>August 1988</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>117</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Gullies are common landforms throughout the arid and semiarid regions of the world. These steep-walled channels range in depth from less than ten feet to more than a hundred feet (Bryan, 1925). The term &apos;gully&apos; may be applied to any channel that is so deep that it cannot be crossed by a wheeled vehicle or eliminated by plowing (Peterson, 1950). The terminology applied to gullies varies with geographic location. In North Africa and in the Near East it is called a wadi. In India it is known as a nullah. In the southwestern United States it is sometimes referred to as an arroyo. Significance of Gullies Erosion of gullies is responsible for widespread destruction of valuable lands in the western United States. Gullies represent an unstable landform; one that is dynamic, and one that is a part of a transforming drainage network (Schumm, et. al., 1984). Field studies by Heede (1982) showed that gully erosion may cause rejuvenation of tributaries and an increase in sediment yield from a drainage network. The production of large volumes of sediment can adversely affect water quality and reservoir capacity (Patton and Schumm, 1975). Bryan (1925) and Heede (1979) report changes in flow regimes from perennial to ephemeral due to the lowering of the local water table following gully incision. The water table may be lowered to an elevation that it will no longer support subirrigated vegetation, thus increasing the erodibility of the valley floor by reducing the protective vegetation cover.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57849</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Toy, Terrence J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1988_Doerner.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_38547</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:52Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Irrigated Agriculture-The Grand Valley Project, Mesa County Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Walker, Paul David</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>December 1967</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>162</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The early history of settlement and agriculture of Grand Valley in Mesa County, Colorado, began following the removal of the Utes from Western Colorado and their relocation on reservations in Eastern Utah in the latter part of 1881. The Grand Valley was, however, visited from time to time by fur trappers and explorers prior to this date. In 1776, an expedition led by Fathers Dominguez and Escalante passed northward across Grand Mesa just to the east of the Grand Junction area.1 A trading post was built by Joseph Roubideau about 1838 just east of the present site of Grand Junction. In 1853, Captain John W. Cunnison, seeking a route for a transcontinental railroad led an exploring party down the Gunnison River Valley past the confluence of the Gunnison and Colorado Rivers and on down the Colorado River Valley.2 Members of the Hayden Survey found only the Ute Indians in the area in 1875 and 1876 and cut short their field season because of skirmishes with the Utes. Following the exit of the Utes in 1881, the Grand Valley was opened for settlement. Immediately following the opening, George A. Crawford founded Grand Junction and fromed the Grand Junction Town Company. The most urgent problem of these early settlers was that of the irrigation of lands so that production of crops for food and the raising of livestock could be realized. The agricultural possibilities of the Grand Valley were considered negligible by members of the early exploration and survey parties. In 1853, E. G. Beckwith described the Grand Valley thus: “ The Valley 20 miles in diameter inclosed by these mountains is quite level and very barren except scattered fields of the greasewood and sage varieties of artemisia—the margins of the Grand (Colorado) and Blue (Gunnison) Rivers affording but a meager supply of grass, cottonwood, and willow.”3 In discussing the agricultural possibilities of a larger part of Western Colorado in 1875, A.C. Peale completely ignored the dry Grand and Lower Gunnison Valleys. “A comparatively small proportion of the country is fitted for agricultural purposes, farming land being confined to the portions of the valleys of the Uncompahgre and Gunnison Rivers and to some small valleys on the upper part of the Dolores and a few of the streams draining the La Sal Mountains.”4 After the Grand Valley was opened to settlement in 1881, it was soon realized that the climate was too arid to grow crops and successfully without irrigation. The solution to this problem began when the first ditch company was organized in 1882 to supply irrigation water from the Colorado River. In March of 1882, work was started on the Pioneer Canal, the forerunner of a number of canals which would be utilized in watering the lands of the Grand Valley. The first large project was the Grand Valley Canal, a privately owned system, constructed in 1883. Ditches were constructed by a number of other companies including the Grand River Ditch Company, the Mesa County Ditch Company, and the Independent Ranchmen’s Association. All of these companies were taken over by the original Grand Valley Irrigation Company. Other irrigation districts in the Grand Valley included the Palisade, Redlands, and Orchard Mesa Irrigation and/or Water Districts. Assistance from the United States Reclamation Service was requested as early as 1902 by local interest. Subsequently, investigations were made by the Reclamation Service. 5 The project was spurred on by the Grand Valley Water Users Association, now the operating organization of the project. This Association was organized and incorporated on February 7, 1905.6 On February 27, 1908, the Grand Valley Project was awarded 732 feet of water to be obtained from the Colorado River.7 Purpose of the Thesis This Grand Valley Project, the largest irrigation project in the Grand Valley, has given the people of the Grand Valley the irrigation potential needed to make this valley a prime agricultural area. Just exactly what the project has accomplished will be discussed in the remainder of the thesis. Along with the added advantages of having water for irrigation are the problems which must be solved. The thesis through statistical material gained from United States Bureau of Reclamation Project Histories will discuss the agricultural advantages brought about by this particular irrigation project. It will also discuss some of the inherent problems brought about by the irrigation of lands throughout the Grand Valley. Without irrigation in the Grand Valley area, it would revert to its nonproductive state as described in some early chronicles already cited. Organization of Remainder of the Thesis The thesis will be organized into seven chapters. The first and second chapters will present the purpose of the thesis and the review of literature pertaining to the subject. Chapter III will consist of general subsections dealing with location, size, land forms, soils, and natural vegetation of the Grand Valley as well as the part transportation facilities play in the present economy of the area. Chapter IV will deal with the early irrigation systems in the Grand Valley and will be a brief resume of those systems constructed so that products of crops and food and the raising of livestock could be realized. Chapter V will deal with the Grand Valley Project in particular and will be a discussion of the United States Bureau of Reclamation’s Project and will include information pertaining to farm incomes, land use, farms, and water flows and use. This chapter will also include methods of irrigation utilized under the Grand Valley Project and some of the problems inherent with these types of irrigation. Chapter VI will discuss the position of agriculture within the economy of the Grand Valley and Mesa County. 1 Baker, James H. (ed.) and Hafen, LeRoy R., History of Colorado, Volume I (Denver: Linderman CO., Inc.), 1927., p. 277. 2 Lohman, S. W., “Geology and Artesian WSater Supply Grand Junction Area Colorado”, Geological Survey Professional Paper 45 (Washington: Government Printing Office, 1965), p. 13. 3 Ibid., p.14 4 Peal, A. C., “Geological Report on the Grand River District,” United States Geological Survey Territory Annual Report 9 (Washington: Government Printing Office, 1877), p. 33. 5 Bacon, Herbert Lee, “The Peach Industry of the Grand Valley of Colorado,” (unpublished Master’s thesis, The University of Colorado, Boulder, Colorado, 1953), p. 18. 6 Ibid., p. 19. 7 Ibid., p. 20.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:38547</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1967_P_Walker.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57899</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:52Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Mandatory School Desegregation and Its Impact on Urban Demographics: A Case Study of Denver, Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dwyer, Catherine F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>March 1993</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>173</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The purpose of this study is to determine what impact, if any, a 16-year-old school desegregation program has had on reshaping the demographic character of the City and County of Denver, Colorado. This study examines changes in Denver, since 1970, in such population characteristics as total number of residents, number of residents under 18 years of age, percent minority residents, and public school enrollment. To analyze these data, a variety of methods are employed, including tabulations of CMSA population trends, choropleth maps to identify population dynamics within the central city, cohort analysis of DPS grade enrollment, regression analysis, and matched pair t tests of popUlation data from a sample of similar city and suburban census tracts. The cohort analysis indicates that retention rates (births/enrollment) in the city&apos;s public schools declined more than 15% in the first years after busing was implemented in the city; and that, throughout the 1980s, these rates remained substantially lower than in pre-busing years. This analysis also suggests: 1. that DPS enrollment decline is solely a function of decline in the number of anglo students; and, 2. that 70% of the anglo children born in the city since 1972 left the school system, and presumably the city, before or during their school age years. Regression analysis of declining anglo enrollment estimates that, during the 1970s, more than 30,000 anglo residents migrated from the city to its suburbs in direct response to the implementation of court-ordered busing. In addition, tabled and mapped population data demonstrate that since 1970, and during an era when population in the rest of the CMSA nearly doubled, the central city has been unable to attract, or even retain, anglo residents. T tests conducted on a sample of similar city and suburban census tracts also indicate that statistically significant differences in anglo population patterns now exist in those city tracts where busing was the differentiating variable. In short, this study indicates that school desegregation accelerated white flight from the city during the 1970s and early 1980s. In the long term, a lack of school desegregation in the suburbs appears to have acted as a &quot;pull factor&quot; in attracting the great bulk of anglo families with children who have settled in the Denver metropolitan region since 1980. These trends, in turn, have produced ever increasing proportions of minority residents in the central city.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57899</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Goetz, Andrew R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1993_Dwyer.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57878</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:53Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Microclimatic Determinants in Tree Species Distribution</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Newman, Albert H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>November 1974</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>28</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Examination of 20 selected hillside plots at approximately 7500 feet indicated differences in populations by species. Species populations and diameters compared to various environmental criteria. Simple correlation analysis found to be most valuable tool linking insolation and Douglas fir population.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57878</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Toy, Terrence J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1974_Newman.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_37747</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:53Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Pediments of the Colorado Piedmont A Geomorphic Study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Howard, William Arby</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1960</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>51</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This study was concerned with the identification and origin of certain planata rock surfaces found at varying elevations along the foothills zone of the Colorado front Range. The surfaces are unusual in appearance when compared with the more angular features of the foothills and seemingly are not related to the present cycle of erosion. The postulate was proposed by this author that the surfaces were features which had originated during a previous geomorphic cycle. Comparing the essential characteristics of the planate surfaces to the characteristics of quite similar features described in other localities it was adjudged that the surfaces along tho Front Range conform to the necessary requirements to be identified as pediments. Pediments are landforms which are common in arid and semi-arid climatic regions. As examination of the physiographic development of the Front Range revealed that there have been periods in the past when the foothills streams were concentrating their efforts toward the lateral reduction of the mountain mass. For this to have occurred the streams of the area would have to have undergone a Strange metamorphosis. The condition necessary for a stream to cease cutting downward and to concentrate its efforts toward the lateral corrosion of its channel is known as the attainment of a profile of equilibrium or grade. Within the walls of the more active streams in the foothills rock-cut benches, which are quite noticeable, testify to past periods in which the streams were engaged in lateral cutting of the mountains. A comparison of the relative elevations of these remnants and the pediment surfaces indicates a definite relationship in their genetic origin. Thus the conclusion was reached that the pediments, as well as the rock-cut benches, along the foothills are the result of graded streams which were concentrating what tooling actions they possessed toward the lateral reduction of the mountain front.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:37747</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1960_Howard.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57361</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:53Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Regional Comparison of Drainage Basin Morphometry; Eastern Powder River Basin, Wyoming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Knutson, Kent</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>March 1983</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>61</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>First order drainage basin parameters (area, basin length, basin relief, percent slope, drainage density, and ruggedness number) were examined in nineteen fourth order basins within the eastern Powder River Basin. The fourth order drainage networks were selected from six geomorphic regions within three major river systems, crossing two prominent geologic formations. Parameters of basins located on the Fort Union formation are characteristic of a more rugged topography than those basins measured on the Wasatch formation. The mean values of basin parameters (for the two formations) are significantly different. The structural geology which dictates the general form of the basin may be responsible for these differences. Furthermore, individual T-tests were made in order to compare variation across the geologic contact between river basins. Basin characteristics varied significantly from what might be expected on the Little Powder River and the Cheyenne River. On the Belle Fourche drainage system, results were found to be consistent with what might be expected based on the hypothesis.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57361</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Toy, Terrence J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1983_Knutson.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55705</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:53Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Relationship of Flooding Recurrence Intervals to Alluvial Soils in a Semi-Arid Environment</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stephens, Terry M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>March 1975</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>37</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Results of research involving flood frequencies and alluvial in humid and semi-humid regions of the United States suggests a frequent recurrence interval will inundate most alluvial soils. This study examines the recurrence interval relationship to alluvial soils in a semi-arid environment. The 7-15 year range of flooding recurrence intervals indicated for this area of the High Plains adds data from a semi-arid environment that seems to be agreement with conclusions from more humid locations. Soil surveys that map alluvial soils are a low cost, practical method for delineating flood plains in a rural environment.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55705</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1975_Stephens.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57901</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:54Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Relative Impact of Off-Road Bicycle and Hiker Traffic on Trail Soils: An Experimental Study, Boulder, Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Carter, Anna Ruth</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1994</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>126</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This research examines the effects on trails of off-road bicyclists as compared with hikers. The research also attempts to assess the degree to which the environmental damage caused by these two recreational user types is affected by trail gradient. Experimental lanes are constructed on a flat plot and a plot having a 10% gradient. Each plot contains a hiking lane, bicycling lane, and a control lane. Treatment consists of 1500 passes over the treatment lanes. Parameters measured include soil compaction and trail microrelief. Matched pairs t-tests are conducted to determine if compaction is affected by trail use. Difference of means tests are used to compare bicycle lanes to hiker lanes and sloped lanes to flat lanes. Compaction is assessed by penetration-resistance and bulk density measurements. Conclusions regarding compaction are hampered by a number of factors. Experimental error is suspected in the data collection. Also, natural variability and small sample size may have prevented establishment of statistical significance. Furthermore, the soil remained dry and relatively resistant to compaction throughout the majority of the experiment due to the scarcity of precipitation. In addition, too few passes may have been applied to allow the soil on the lanes to reach a steady state. Suggestions for modifications to the study design that may overcome these difficulties are included. Off-road bicycling is found to cause greater changes than hiking in trail microrelief; bicyclists have the greatest impact on slopes, while hiker impacts are similar on flat and sloped lanes. Based on these results, land managers might consider restrictions of bicyclists on steeply sloping terrain. Alternatively, these users should be kept in mind when designing and constructing new trails or updating old trails.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57901</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Gonzalez, Mark A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1994_Carter.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57512</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:54Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Rill Erosion and the Geomorphic Environment of Reclaimed Surface-Mined Hillslopes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Soulliere, Jr., Edward J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1983</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>153</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>From a geomorphologic standpoint, surface-mining drastically disturbs the existing balance between the landforms and the processes which have shaped them. Surface and sub-surface hydrology are altered, and erosion is temporarily accelerated substantially above the geologic norm. The control of said erosion through reclamation must be considered a primary objective in order to reinstate this balance.The purpose of this research was directed toward developing useful equations to predict the magnitude and frequency of rill erosion on reclaimed hillslopes. They study site was the Dave Johnston Coal Company located in the southeastern Powder River Basin of Wyoming. The dependent variables in this study are the rill parameters of width, depth, length, frequency (rills per meter), and width times depth. The independent variables are the environmental variables of percent slope, slope aspect, soil pH, percent bare soil, soil compressive strength, soil shear strength, soil bulk density, clay ratio, slope age, slope length, percent silt, and the cross-product variable bulk density times slope. Five equations were developed to predict responses in the five dependent variables. Rill width is best predicted by the independent variables of bulk density, slope age, and slope length with a standard error of .004. The optimum equation for rill depth includes the variables soil shear strength and slope length with the standard error again at .004. The regression, equation which best predicts rill length contains only one variable, that of slope length, with a standard error of .147. The variables which best predict rill frequency are soil bulk density, the clay ratio, soil compaction, soil pH, and slope with a standard error of .021. The final regression equation for the cross-product term rill width times depth includes the variables of soil shear strength and slope length with a standard error of .007.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57512</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Toy, Terrence J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1983_Soulliere.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58130</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:54Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Rural vs. Rural: Characterizing the Variable Access to Primary Care in Non-Metropolitan Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alonzo, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 2007</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>162</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>There is significant research focusing on variation in access to primary care between urban and rural areas. There is little work however, focusing on the disparities among types of rural communities. This thesis regionally evaluates the variability of care supply and demand in non-metropolitan Colorado. A mixed methods approach is used to determine which areas of the state have better or worse access to primary care as measured by doctor to population ratios and the presence of federal designations of under service. Provider survey responses give further insight into who is serving the state&apos;s disparate regions and which factors of place are important in their locational decision making. The Great Plains and southern Colorado are faring worst in terms of access to primary care. The areas that are underserved throughout the state tend to be non-mountainous, poorer, ethnically Hispanic, and comprised of older residents. Younger and women practitioners are more likely to be practicing in these areas as are members of the National Health Services Corps. However, low levels of satisfaction among practitioners in underserved areas lead to unlikely retention. Respondents statewide highly ranked place factors associated with achieving a work-life balance, professional collaboration, and the natural environment surrounding their community. Nevertheless, there are differences in the demographics and values of providers practicing in Colorado&apos;s mountains and those in the plains. It is important for health care policy makers to consider the variation in community types even within a state in order to appropriately match each with physicians intent on staying.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58130</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Goetz, Andrew</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2007_Alonzo.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58132</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:54Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sedimentological Evidence of Late Quaternary Environmental Change Preserved in a Grand Mesa, Colorado Peat Deposit</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Williams, Tennille J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 2005</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>159</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Kannah Creek Fen (elevation 3200 m) occupies a glaciated stream channel atop Grand Mesa, a basalt-capped plateau in western Colorado. Several cores (&gt;7.5 m length) provide evidence of environmental change over the last 20,000 years. The upper 4.8 m of the cores are composed of peat; the lower 3 m are made up of silty lake mud and fine grained glacial outwash. A bulk sample radiocarbon date of 18,890 +/- 70 14C yr BP was obtained just above the bottom of the sediment core; peat began accumulating 10,040 +/- 4014 C yr·BP. Close interval sampling of sediment properties and fossil pollen were used to reconstruct a high resolution record of paleoenvironmental change. High bulk density values at the base of the core reflect the presence and eventual disappearance of the Grand Mesa ice cap near the end of the Pleistocene. Organic content of the peat can be used as a proxy of relative paleotemperature, and organic content curves from the fen cores approximate other paleotemperature proxy records from the region. Changes in the degree of humification of the peat, measured as percent light transmittance, provide a proxy for effective moisture. The humification data from periods during the Holocene that were warmer than today indicate that peat was more humified, suggesting that increased temperatures either did not strengthen the summer monsoon in the region, or that any increase in precipitation was offset by increased evapotransporation. The conclusions from this research provide a record of paleomoisture conditions and suggest a means of validating global climate models used to predict future climate.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58132</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Sullivan, Donald G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2007_Williams.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58124</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:54Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Short-Term Rill Evolution Following the Buffalo Creek Fire, Buffalo Creek, Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pine, Elizabeth J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 2002</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>184</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The Buffalo Creek Fire burned 11,900 acres near Buffalo Creek, Colorado on May 18-20, 1996. The fire burned 6,660 acres of the Buffalo Creek watershed and 5,250 acres of the Spring Creek watershed. The study area concentrated on Spring Creek where the slopes are steeper and rills best developed. As fires are an integral part of forested ecosystems, it is important to understand their influence on hillslope erosion, particularly rill erosion. The Buffalo Creek Fire altered the hillslope properties within the Spring Creek watershed creating conditions favorable to rill formation. Aerial and ground photos indicated the rills formed two months after the fire as the result of a high intensity rainstorm. If the rills resulted from changes caused by the fire, then the rills should heal as the hillslope properties return to pre-fire conditions. The variables investigated were width, depth, width to depth ratio, area, and hydraulic radius of rills on north and south-facing.hillslopes, percent vegetation cover and hanges in sediment load through time. The study was conducted between 1998 and 2000. The results of this study show what appears to be the stabilization of the rills. The analysis of rill characteristics through time shows little change. The expected relation that the hillslope characteristics will change through time is not significant. The limited number of storms during the study period may account for the lack of change through time. The energy was not available to move the sediment from the interrill to the rill areas.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58124</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Toy, Terrence J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2002_Pine.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57897</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:55Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Snowcover Controls on Alpine Soil Surface Temperature Patterns, Niwot Ridge, Colorado, U.S.A.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hamann, Hillary Beth</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>1998</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>140</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Seasonally frozen soils play an important role in many hydrologic, biologic, and hydrochemical processes. In the alpine, heterogeneous vegetation, topography and snow conditions during the winter should affect spatial and temporal variations in soil temperatures. In 1996-97 a network of soil temperature recorders were installed at 3500 m on Niwot Ridge to evaluate variations in surface soil temperatures and the primary controls on spatial and temporal variability of ground surface conditions. This study utilized a constructed snowfence on the Ridge as well as naturally occurring shallow, moderate and deep snow deposition sites. Snow depth was monitored throughout the winter season, and a reconnaissance of ground surface conditions was carried out prior-to and after snowmelt to look for basal ice at the snow-soil interface. Available data was utilized to examine soil moisture, vegetation and snow cover as primary controls on temperatures and temperature variations in the soil. Results indicate that although interactions occur between vegetation, soil moisture and soil temperatures, snow cover maximum depth and timing information can be used as a simple and effective predictor of general soil surface temperatures and variations. Maximum snow accumulations at the study site ranged from 10 cm to 560 cm and occurred in late April, 1997. Results from the 1996-97 snow year show that as seasonal snow cover depth and duration increase, short term temperatures variations are delayed and dampened. Sites with early snow accumulation less than 40 cm showed the greatest and fastest response to synoptic temperature changes. At sites where the early season snowpack ranged from 40 to 90 cm, response to general synoptic temperature trends was evident, though temperatures and their range were dampened by up to 10° C. The depth and timing of the snow cover also influenced minimum temperatures, the timing of minimum temperatures and the duration of an isothermal period at the end of the snow season. Snow cover and soil temperatures also appeared to affect the occurrence of basal ice and snowmelt flowpaths. Results of the basal ice survey point to antecedent soil moisture in the fall and spring meltwater supply as primary conditions necessary for basal ice formation on Niwot Ridge.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57897</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1998_Hamann.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55682</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:55Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil Characteristics of the Terrace System Associated with the Archaeological Site of Aperlae</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Longbrake, William</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>November 2007</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>115</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The soils surrounding the city of Aperlae in modern Turkey were studied in order to determine the overall suitability for agriculture during Roman and Byzantine occupation. Both terraced and non-terraced soils were examined to determine what if any benefits were gained due to the construction of terraces. Soil characteristics investigated include, pH, depth, C:N, total phosphorus, water storage capacity and pF, electrical conductivity, bulk density, and organic carbon content. The only factor found to vary significantly and consistently between terraced and non-terraced soils was total depth with terraced soils being on average 40cm deeper. It is posited that the cumulic nature of the terraced soils had a homogenizing effect in the time since abandonment. While it was hypothesized that the terraces were constructed as sediment control devices to protect Murex trunculus habitat, there was not enough evidence to support this. A new type of terrace construction was also identified and described.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55682</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Sullivan, Donald G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2007_Longbrake.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_38529</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:55Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Some Aspects Of Alteration Of Hydrology By The Construction of Trincheras In The Pompa Basin Sierra Madre Occidental Mexico</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Griffin, Ernst Clark</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>December 1966</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>91</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This paper deals with alterations of the normal hydrologic regime of the Pompa Basin, Mesa del Huracan, Chihuahua, Mexico due to the construction of trincheras, crude stone check dams placed across stream channels, Trincheras were built in the Pompa Basin by the Unidad Industriales Forestal de Bosques de Chihuahua, a private timber company, in 1963 and 1964. They are similar in design and construction to ancient trincheras built throughout the Sierra Madre Occidental of Mexico by ancient Indian civilizations. In the Pompa Basin trincheras act as water and soil conservation structures. They have altered the normal hydro-logic and erosional regimes of the basin by reducing stream competence and increasing moisture levels in the soil. The drainage pattern of the basin has been changed from a dendritic pattern to a non-integrated pattern by the construction of trincheras. Changes have taken place in the drainage area con¬trolled by the stream channels of the various arroyitos of the basin. Individual micro-drainage basins have been created by the construction of trincheras in the basin giving rise to reduced stream competence and a change in the final position of sediment deposition. Potential stream energy in the several flow channels of the Pompa Basin has been decreased by the fragmentation and obstruction of stream flow. This has lead to decreased velocities, turbulence, and volumes in the various flow channels. Water-holding capacity within the basin, both surface capacity and ground-water and soil moisture capacities, have been increased with the advent of trincheras. This is due to the holding capacity of each individual trinchera as well as greater length of time which water remains in the basin. Field observations substantiated by field measurements support the conclusion that trincheras in the Pompa Basin serve as water conservation and erosion control devices. This was a part of their avowed function when constructed and they serve their purpose well. It would seem logical to deduce that similar trincheras constructed by ancient peoples in similar environments of the Sierra Madre Occidental must have functioned in the same manner and for the same purposes as those in the Pompa Basin.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:38529</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Griffiths, Thomas M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1966_Griffin.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_37749</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:55Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Some Effects of an Economic Base Change on the Land Use of Selected Areas</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>La Perriere, Louis Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>December 1961</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>135</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This study was undertaken to interpret some of the effects that an economic base change has on the land use in some selected areas in the United States. Today, because of the rapid growth in some of these areas, land use has been greatly effected by rapid economic base changes. The economic base changes have occurred to satisfy new demands by industry and national defense measures, having been the results of primarily technological advances and new locational land requirements. The base determinations have been acquired or measured in a number of Methods, This measurement indicates direction, rate, and depth of changes of the space economy, which in turn registers the land utilization as a segment of this economy. Four areas were selected to explore the economic base and chart the effect upon the areas that this change caused. Brevard County, Florida; Santa Barbara County, California; Savannah River Area, South Carolina; and the Williston Basin Area in North Dakota comprise these selected areas that incurred a rapid economic base change in the last few years. Brevard and Santa Barbara counties&apos; base change was the result of missile activity, the Savannah River area reflected an ideal site for the location of an atomic plant, and in the Williston Basin area—oil forced the base change. These changes were measured by income, employment, input and output and other means to secure a regional analysis of the areas of study. Within the individual selected study areas, the population impacts indicated the extent of the economic base changes that were in progress. This impact was observed to judge the extent of land use and scope of the economic development in the study areas. From the effect of the base changes, the land use changes were clearly discerned and a foundation was established for future planning and development within the areas. The result of the study indicated that a number of situations occurred that had not previously existed and the normal rate and direction of growth was altered from the growth pattern prior to the population impact. Within the study areas, speculation and exploitation occurred in anticipation of the accelerated growth. Planning was non-existant or ineffectual in the area of rapid growth. Also urban services problems have become a major issue in urban development. It was further discovered that in order to make adequate measurements of the economic base and its change plus the effect on the local economy, more qualitative as well as quantitative information is necessary. Much information is readily accessible, but it may not be in a usable form, Further inquires into base measurements must be accomplished to use an economic base as an adequate measurement of an area.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:37749</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>  
<dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1961_LaPerrier.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57356</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:56Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Spatial Associations Between Land Use and Natural Hazards in Glenwood Springs, Colorado, in 1965 and 1974: A Comparison</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Koulet, Kim J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>March 1979</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>79</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This study was interested in determining whether or not significant change in the spatial association of land use types and natural hazards occurred between 1965 and 1974 in Glenwood Springs, Colorado. Specifically, this study focused on the identification of land use in Glenwood Springs in 1965 and 1974; the estimation of changes in the areal extent of various land use categories in non-hazard and hazard areas; and an attempt to identify trends between land use types and associated natural hazard areas. The basis for identifying land use and determining land use change in hazard and non- hazard areas was through the employment of the stratified, systematic, unaligned, sampling method on large scale (1:48.00) maps and aerial photographs. Based upon data generated by this research, it is clear that no great change in the way the land is used in Glenwood Springs occurred between 1965 and 1974, although modest amounts of;change did occur among several categories of use. In addition, as the city limits expanded, including additional areas of hazards, they were occupied by use types that did not significantly differ from those which existed before the city&apos;s expansion. Overall, no strong associations between land use and natural hazards were found, nor was there any clear-cut evidence of a trend away from hazard areas.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57356</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1979_Koulet.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55714</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:56Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Spatial Variations in the Commission of Serious Class I Crimes in Denver for 1977</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Duru, Titus Udunna</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>December 1979</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>66</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This study proposed to determine if there were any spatial variations in the occurrence pattern of serious Class I crimes in the city of Denver for 1977 and, if so, how geographic and socioeconomic variables related to these spatial variations. The research method and design developed hypotheses that were aimed at determining if: (1) the five serious Class I crimes of homicide, robbery, rape, aggravated assault, and burglary have similar geographic patterns; (2) the Commission rate of serious Class I crimes Varies with direction from the Central Business District; (3) high rates of serious Class I crimes are inversely related to distance from Denver;s Central Business District; (4) high rates of serious Class I crimes are inversely related to median family income; (5) high rates of serious Class I crimes are positively related to the percentage of families living in multiple family units; and (6) high rates of serious Class I crimes are positively related to the percentage of school-age children. Hypothesis 1 was investigated using computer mapping techniques and correlation analysis to test for spatial similarities in the patterns of the five serious Class I crimes for the city of Denver. Hypothesis 2 was tested using analysis of variance to determine if there were significant variations in crime rates with direction from the Central Business District. Hypothesis 3 through 6 were tested utilizing correlation analysis. Findings indicate that the five serious Class I crimes display similarities in their patterns of occurrence. It was also found that variations existed in the different quadrants of the city with respect to direction from the Central Business District. (The northeast quadrant had the highest crime rates.) Both median family income and distance from the Central Business District were statistically significant in the analysis as opposed to the percentage of school-age children and multiple dwelling units. In conclusion, the five serious Class I crimes displayed similarities in their patterns of occurrence which justified grouping them together to form a composite crime index for further analysis. Median family income and distance from the Central Business District contributed in accounting for high crime rates and their spatial variations in Denver for 1977. Youthfulness of population and multiple family units, at least as measured in this study, did not make any significant contribution to the understanding of high crime rates and their spatial variations.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55714</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Longbrake, David B.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1979_Duru.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_57843</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:56Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Asian Community in East Africa: Its Geographical Distribution and Economic and Social Characteristics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zaidi, Juliet H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>December 1967</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>75</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Man has been on the move since early times. There are many and various reasons motivating people to leave their homeland and seek other opportunities in strange and foreign lands. People from the Indian sub-continent have been found to leave their native land to settle in strange lands both far and near. Indians can be found in all the former British possessions. They are distributed all over the African continent south of the Sahara with special concentration in the former British holdings of Bast and South Africa. There have been various migrations from Asia to the African continent. Asians have settled in East Africa since early times. Due to the proximity of the East African seaboard to India and the ideal maritime conditions Indians are to be found in large numbers even to this present time. A look at their present geographical distribution would show that the Asian population of Kenya, Uganda and Tanganyika tend to concentrate around the great capitals and port cities in each of these countries. In Kenya they are to be found around Nairobi, the capital and Mombasa,, the great port city. In Uganda the numerical strength of Asians coincides with the most economically developed districts of West Mengo and Busoga. In Tanganyika the Asians focus overwhelmingly on the capital city of Dar es Salaam. The Asians of East Africa have played the role of the middle man between the European and the African both economically and socially. In Kenya the Asians tend to dominate industrial and 2 commercial establishments while there is insignificant participation in agriculture when compared with the African or European group. In Uganda, however, the Asians have gone into commerce with more active part in agriculture with cotton ginning, coffee curing and sugar production. In Tanganyika many Asians are to be found in the import and export trade of that country. For years the Asians have formed this middle layer of the society holding jobs that the native Africans would like to acquire. Since the independence in the countries of Bast Africa the Africans have won political power but economic power still eludes them and is mainly in the hands of the Asians. The 350,000 Asians living in these three countries of East Africa control four fifths of the regional commerce from large wholesale firms to simple dukas. They hold the majority of skilled and semi-skilled jobs. Due to the rise in African nationalism caused by the independence and the dominance of the trade by Asians, the Asians have found themselves in a difficult situation and exposed to widespread criticism. To avoid this hostility the Asians have one of the two alternatives—either to depart from East Africa or make the necessary change to integrate themselves with the new society.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:57843</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Griffiths, Thomas M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description> 
 <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1968_Zaidi.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_37744</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:56Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Benefits To Be Derived From The Colorado Big Thompson Water Diversion Project By The Wellington, Colorado Area</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Graves, Lynus C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>1950</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>71</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The purpose of this thesis is an attempt to analyse the agricultural problems of the Wellington, Colorado area and to contemplate the possible increase in farming dependability in the future. The possible increase in the dependability is based upon the supplementary water to be derived from the Colorado Big Thompson Water Diversion Project. A survey of the conditions existing in the area was made end contrasted with conditions that would probably exist after the additional water supply was received. A survey was made of the soil conditions in the area and it was found that if these soils receive enough water they will produce very well. The past trouble has been undefendable water supply end not soil conditions. Farming methods are up to date and adequate, markets are readily available, and yields have been good in the wetter years. Despite these conditions, however, a precarious farming economy exists at the present time. The main problem confronting the area is that of an undefendable water supply. This point is exemplified by contrasting the crop yields during a sufficiently wet year tilth yields of a dry year. Water from the Colorado Big Thompson Project will approximately double the present average water supply of the area and therefore greatly increase the dependability of crop production each year. This primary problem, however, does not constitute the entire handicap of the area in terms of maximum efficiency. The erosion and soil damage exist, and may be greatly increased after additional water is received. This is found primarily In the areas underlain by an impervious shale formation. This area causes rapid run-off of water which ultimately drains to lower lands, causing over-irrigation on these lower lands. In some cases, alkali flats develop there and the soil Is made infertile and useless for further cultivation. Other problems are of minor consequence and probably can be overcome in the course of time. The additional water supply will certainly be the main factor in aiding the area to approach its maximum efficiency. The facts indicate that there can be no doubt that the area will benefit greatly by the additional water and that farming efficiency, and particularly farming dependability, will increase considerably. There may be changes in the method of farming, in the typos of crops grown on certain lands, and in the entire cultural pattern of the area, but this Is pure conjecture and will have to await proof after the water supply has been received and the newer farming conditions have been present for a time.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:37744</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>  
<dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1950_Graves.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_37748</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:58Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Denver Site A Geographic Study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schierbrock, William Noble</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1960</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>102</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>This study was undertaken to inventory and interpret some of the causes and reasons that the city of Denver, Colorado, is so located. In developing this study factors mostly from an historical and geographical view point were used, enumerating primarily the history, natural environment, human factors, and economic activities that formed the city. These factors and activities can be reduced to establish the foundation of the Denver site in recognizable terms. Much has been written about the location and site of an urban area. Aside from the theoretical causes that are attributed to the site there are definite tangible as well as historical factors that have contributed to Denver&apos;s establishment. The Denver site is effected by its natural environment in terms of location, climate, natural vegetation, landforms, physiography, soils, and minerals. The location of Denver is also effected by the human elements that chronologically induced the city into its present development. Indians, fur trappers, traders, miners, farmers, cattle industry, and population settlement gave impetus to its development and growth. This development and additional activities as transportation, industrial and commercial growth occured to further the use of the Denver site. A comprehensive alignment of all the above factors has given some conclusions for the use of the Denver site as a seat of an urban center. These outlined factors and activities give only a basic criterion for the cities existence. Further development in all the outlined factors must be expanded to further the study of the Denver site.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:37748</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1960_Schierbrock.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55710</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:58Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Effect of Irrigation on Available Void Capacity of Disturbed Soils in Semiarid Regions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Munson, Brian E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>1978 January</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>108</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Precipitation characteristics in semiarid regions pose special problems for strip mine rehabilitation. Low amounts of precipitation account for a sparse vegetal cover while infrequent storms of high intensity can produce high erosion rates. Strip mining operations can compound moisture problems by compaction soils during the regrading process. There is a need for a mechanism to improve the ability of disturbed soils to take on and store water to facilitate revegetation efforts. Through alternate wetting and drying, water infiltrates into soils, adsorbs to soil particles as molecular layers, and can separate the distance between closely spaced soil particles. When the soil dries, some of the created void remains. It was found that this method increased the quantity of void for a 10 to 20 centimeter depth in a silty clay loam. Further, the greatest increase occurred for only one 3.8 liter irrigation with subsequent application producing little or no change. The change in void created by the methodology in a sandy loam soil was negligible. Results suggest that the increase in void is probably due to a combination of shrink swell potential of the soils, and force exerted by the water being adsorbed. Further research suggestions are: 1) the contribution of shrink swell due to differing clay content to void increase; 2) the minimum amount of irrigation required to maximize void increase; and 3) the effect of void increase on infiltration capacity.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55710</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1978_Munson.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.
</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_38546</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:58Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Effect of Trincheras Upon Agriculture In The Pompa Basin Sierra Madre Occidental, Mexico</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dennis, Howard Willis</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>March 1967</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>123</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Within the past three years the Department of Geography of the University of Denver has become increasingly interested in man-made rock structures found in southwestern United States and northern Mexico. These structures, built by ancient inhabitants of this large area, have only recently been discussed in scientific literature. The earliest reference found is 1892 but most references post date 1930. These rock structures are called trincheras in the present literature and the name is applied to a variety of rock structures. Trinchera in Spanish means “…a trench, entrenchment; deep cut, or ditch.” For the purpose of this investigation trinchera shall be defined as any structure of rock, earth, or combination of rock and earth built across a perennial or ephemeral stream channel. Some of these rock structures are said to be as much as 900 years old and many uses have been attributed to them; defense, religion, soil collection, water spreading, and water collection are some of the uses mentioned in the literature. The structures built for defensive and religious purposes are apparently easily recognizable. (See Figure 1.) The other type of structure, the so-called “true” trincheras, which is associated with hydrology and agriculture, is the subject of this study. In the past two and one-half years rock structures have been built in the heart of the Serra Madre Occidental in northwestern Chihuahua, Mexico, by the Unidad Industrial Forestal de Bosques de Chihuahua. The purpose of these structures is never in doubt; the engineer responsible for the construction has been interviewed and states unequivocally the purpose for which they were built. This eliminates the argument over the primary purpose of these trincheras, limiting this discussion to other effects. The secondary effects produced by trincheras are the concern of this investigation; more precisely the question: Do trincheras have positive effect on agriculture? The results of the basic inquiry establishes the fact that these simple structures have indeed affected agriculture. A.F. Bandlier, Final Report of Investigation Among the Indians of the Southwestern United States Carried on Mainly in the Years from 1880 to 1885 (Papers of the Archaeological Institute of America, American Series IV. Cambridge: John Wilson and Son, University Press, 1892). Edgar Allison Peers, et al. (eds.), Cassell’s Spanish Dictionary (New York: Funk and Wagnall’s, 1959), p. 757. Laurance C.Herold, “Trincheras and Physical Environment Along the Rio Gavilan, Chihuahua, Mexico (Publications in Geography, Technical Paper 65-1. University of Denver, 1965), p.2. Bandelier, op. cit., pp. 491, 566.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:38546</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1967_Dennis.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58120</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:58Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Effects of Regional Political Instability on Moroccan Tourism, 1989-2000</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kizlyk, Darrick</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 2001</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>144</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>For less-developed countries. tourism. as a development option has become widely promoted. However, tourism development is no panacea because of its volatile nature-in many instances caused by internal or regional political instability. Looking at Morocco specifically, there is strong evidence suggesting that the Gulf War in 1991 and events associated with the Algerian civil war caused a precipitous decline in tourism receipts for Morocco. By examining who the tourists visiting Morocco are, how long they stay, and how much they spend, we find that the patterns from different source countries are remarkably different. Prospective tourists from Western countries to Morocco respond negatively when they fear their safety is in danger-even if the political instability is in the Middle East, but in a culturally similar region. On the other hand, the ability of North African tourists to get to Morocco was hindered as violence in the Algerian civil war escalated and the Moroccan- Algerian border closed in late 1994. As a result, tourism receipts for Morocco have been volatile in the 1990s. However, the different causes of the volatility have led to varying effects within Morocco. The decline in Western tourists to Morocco caused by regional political instability lasted approximately one year, while the border closure has limited the number of North African tourists since late 1994. This has led to areas in the country, particularly eastern Morocco, to have suffered through a prolonged decline in their tourism industry. While Morocco could become less susceptible to regional political instability by becoming a mass tourism destination, the nature of the tourist attractions in the country would make the transition difficult and also lead to other potential problems. Therefore, perhaps there are no definitive answers, and Morocco, like other less-developed countries, must take the good and the bad associated with using tourism as a development strategy.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58120</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Keables, Michael J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2001_Kizlyk.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58127</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:58Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Effects of Soil Depth and Soil Characteristics on Plant Community Development in North Dakota</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wick, Abbey Foster</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 2004</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>230</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Re-vegetation of mined lands in North Dakota is challenging because of poor physical and chemical properties of the spoil material and a semi-arid climate. Adequate topsoil and subsoil replacement has been a successful method rised to establish productive reclaimed plant communities. Previous studies conducted by Merrill eta/. (1998) and Power eta/.(1 81) have determined adequate soil depth for optimal productivity during six years of study. This was determined through the establishment of topsoil wedges in Zap and Stanton, ND. There-sampling of these sites in 2003 provided important information concerning the long-term effects of soil depth and soil characteristics on plant community development. The influence of total soil depth and soil characteristics was significantly different in 2003 when compared to previous years. In 2003, the highest production on the Zap, ND Double Topsoil Wedge occurred on 40 to 120 em of total soil and the highest diversity was on the alfalfa vegetation strips with 0 to 40 em of total soil. In the previous study, higher yields were on 51 to 110 em of total soil. The highest production on the Stanton, ND Topsoil Wedge was on 65 to 120 em of total soil in 2003. In the previous study, the highest yields were on 92 to 132 em of total soil.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58127</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Toy, Terrence J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sullivan, Donald</dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2004_Wick.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Kerwin, Mike</dc:contributor>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55652</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:59Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Heavy Winter Snows of 1972-1973 in the U.S. Southwest</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Polansky, Michael D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>August 1974</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:format>23</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The objective of this investigation was to ascertain if there was a dominant weather type which led to the excessive snowfalls in the southwestern United States during the winter of 1972-73. Having identified one, the investigation then describes and portrays the weather type and its associated circulation pattern which produced abnormally high snowfall and compares its activity that year with a relatively normal year in the study area. The research shows that the percentage of widespread snow situations caused by this weather type did not vary markedly from the extreme year to the normal year, i.e. the type was not proportionately more important during the snowier winter. The great variance, however, was in the actual number of occurrences of this weather type during the 1972-73 season as compared to the normal year.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55652</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1974_Polansky.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_54110</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:59Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Influence of Territorial Shape On Municipal Expenditures: England And Wales</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hampson, Arthur</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>June 1971</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>159</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>It is a basic assumption that cost of transportation is directly related to distance travelled. Assuming a focus for distribution of goods and services, then, it logically follows that a circle whose center coincides with that focus is the most efficient shape for a service area. It was therefore hypothesized that urban centers which are compact (e.g. circular) in shape will spend less per capita on certain services than urban centers which are not compact. Using a quantitative index of circularity, sixty county boroughs in England and Wales were subjected to simple correlation between shape and nine categories of municipal expenditure. In addition, the explanatory power of shape was compared to that of six traditionally accepted explainers of municipal expenditure variation (1) population, (2) population change: 1951-1961, (3) area, (4) population density, (5) per capita yield from rates, and (6) the percentage of county borough income from both rates and central government grants which was derived just from rates. Both simple and multiple correlation techniques were used to make the comparison. Shape showed a statistically significant correlation with only two categories of municipal expenditure—education and parks. The correlation with education was a positive one, negating the original hypothesis. It was concluded that shape is not an important determinant of per capita municipal expenditure variations. This does not contradict the &quot;friction of distance&quot; concept, but it does question its relevance in an urban area. In spite of this, shape appeared to be no less influential than most of the independent variables commonly used in studies dealing with municipal spending.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:54110</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1971_Hampson.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55687</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:59Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Role of Soil Characteristics and Seasonal Soil Moisture in the Distribution of Vegetation on the Palmer Divide, Colorado</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Skinner, Catherine P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>August 1995</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>215</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The Palmer Divide separates the drainage basins of the South Platte and Arkansas Rivers in east-central Colorado. Situated between Denver and Colorado Springs, it joins the Front Range on the west, and gradually descends eastward for about 110 km, to near Limon, Colorado. The Palmer Divide major vegetation types—ponderosa pine (Pinus ponderosa) woodland, gamble oak (Quercus gambelii) scrub, and prairie grasslands form distinctive east-west distributional patterns. Several approaches were used in this study to investigate relations between plants and soil moisture. Methods selected provide quantitative data on soil characteristics including water retention and saturation capacity, pH, electrical conductivity, and variations in soil development. The study sites represent the four common plant associations on the Palmer Divide, and range from near the highest point on the Palmer Divide in the west, to the eastern-most stand of pines on the divide. Ponderosa pine stands predominate at the summits of hillslopes and in rocky outcrops; pines at the western end of the Palmer Divide grow on ridgetops and rocky outcrops where soil moisture fills rock fractures, where they do not have to compete with other vegetation for moisture. The porous soils on the west half of the divide appear to permit transport of moisture downward where it accumulates above the bedrock and in bedrock joints. Shallow depth to bedrock under pine may be an indication that pines in this location develop deep taproots that can take advantage of moisture in rock fractures below. Gambel oak at the higher elevations on the divide occupies transitional areas between grasses and pines, serves as understory with pines, or forms short, scrubby patches surrounded by mixed grasses and forbs on valley side slopes. Oaks may take advantage of subsurface flow of moisture which penetrates from higher rocky slopes above, avoiding competitive use of moisture by grasses. The eastern-most limit of the gamble oak range in Colorado is approximately 30 km east of the Front Range. Grasses appear to be good indicators of relative water availability; as soil moisture availability decreases from west to east, the proportion of short grass prairie species increases. Grasses utilize more of the available soil moisture than either oak or pine. The type and texture of soils has a direct influence on how much moisture soils can retain. Soil moisture availability to grasses decreases from west-to-east on the Palmer Divide. Rooting depth is greater in the west where soil moisture is greater and can penetrate to greater depths in rocky, porous soils; shallow rooting is more common in the east where moisture is less abundant and does not penetrate as deeply in finer-textured soils. Fine soils in the east, with a large amount of particle surface, can adsorb moisture in greater quantities; the energy required for plants to remove moisture from the soil, however, is greater in the east than in the west. Trends in soil moisture influence distribution of vegetation on the Palmer Divide. Soil moisture retention capacity tends to be less in the west than in the east. Available soil moisture, rooting depths and precipitation differences work together and are influenced by organic matter content and soil pH. Trends attributable to the influence of humus on retention capacity are most evident in soils under oak which show greater development than those under pine or grass.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55687</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Sullivan, Donald G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>Skinner_Catherine.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_55650</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:59Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Spatial Expression of Public Schools in the City and County of Denver, Colorado: A Central Place Study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Driscoll, Linda B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>August 1973</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>136</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>The study is concerned with an application of central place theory to the non-economically oriented service of a public school system, whereas central place theory has been applied primarily to economic functions. Not only can central place theory produce a theoretical explanation of spatial aspects of public facility location, but the theory may be further refined by its application to noneconomic functions. This research attempts to describe the explanatory significance of central place theory in describing the spatial attributes of public schools in a municipal setting. Following a discussion of the assumptive conditions of Christaller’s central place model, the seven fundamental diagnostic criteria of the ideal central place hierarchical structure are outlined. These criteria, established by John Marshall, are used as the theoretic basis for the study of central place applied to a school system. Criterion four, the interstitial placement of orders, is also the theoretical basis for the empirical validation. The theoretic portion of this study would have application to any public school system, while the empirical portion relates only to data on the Denver Public School System of the City and County of Denver, Colorado. The empirical application is divided into two parts. The first part is concerned with determining whether the spatial distribution of the Denver Public Schools is random, hexagonal, or clustered, using nearest neighbor technique modified for central place studies by Dacey. These five relationships are tested. 1. All central places. 2. Senior high schools with respect to all central places. 3. Junior high schools with respect to all central places. 4. Elementary schools with respect to all central places. 5. All Senior high schools The analysis is for a thirty year span using the years 1940, 1950, 1960, and 1970. The results show the distributional pattern approaching randomness from clustered, rather than hexagonal as required by central place theory. The second part of the analysis is concerned with the shapes of the complementary regions (service areas) of the three levels of schools—elementary, junior highs, senior highs—for 1940, 1950, 1960, 1970 through the use of Dirichlet polygons. The assumption is made that all pupils are assigned the school nearest their place of residence. The service areas have a tendency toward five sides rather than the required hexagons. It is suggested that central place theory could readily explain the locational aspects of a school system within a municipality if the criterion of interstitial placement of orders were not so rigid. To</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:55650</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Not Specified</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_1973_Driscoll.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_58119</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-09T22:56:59Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_65309</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Use of Urban Trails and Adjacent Land Use, Socio-Economic Characteristics, and Trail Design: A Denver Case Study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Keeley, Amy K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:date>August 2001</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>en</dc:language>
  <dc:format>218</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:description>Master&apos;s</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Urban trails in riparian corridors follow an organic course through a diversity of environments, &quot;linking&quot; several varying areas of a community as transportation and recreation routes. This research was an attempt to account for the geographic distribution of types and amounts of urban riparian trail use within the study area. This was done by relating trail corridor characteristics to the trail traffic levels. Two urban trails were studied within Denver, Colorado. The trailways consist of 400 acres of parks along a 20-mile network that runs parallel to the major transportation corridors in Denver. The trails merge together near the CBD and intercept a diversity of neighborhoods. At twenty sites along the trailways, data on trail use was collected on Sundays and during morning and evening peak commuter times on weekdays. The data consist of trail surveys completed by users, total amount of trail-users with their modal type, gender, race, age group, and travel direction. These data were used to determine the spatial variation of the characteristics of the trail-users, and to determine if any relationships exist between total trail traffic per site and adjacent land use types and densities, adjacent socio-economic characteristics of trail corridor residents, and trail site design characteristics. This study contributes to transportation research which focuses on alternative transportation modes, as well as recreational research which focuses on urban trail use trends.</dc:description>
  <dc:relation></dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>codu:58119</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>All Rights Reserved</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Goetz, Andrew R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Geography</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:identifier>du_mas_2001_Keely.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63414</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T20:39:39Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A CROSS-SHEAR-BASED NUMERICAL WEAR MODEL OF INTERVERTEBRAL DISC IMPLANTS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ghiglieri, William Andrew</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Mechanical Engineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Ultra high molecular weight polyethylene is the bearing surface of choice for implants, but because of wear, it is often a limiting factor for the longevity of the implant. Understanding the wear potential of new implants such as the total disc replacement (TDR) is critical due to their rise in clinical implementation. Unidirectional motion shows dramatically lower wear rates then multidirectional motion due to a phenomenon known as cross-shear. Previously, numerical wear models did not incorporate cross-shear, limiting the accuracy of the model for prediction of wear over multiple loading conditions. The objective of this study was to develop an adaptive finite element model to study the effects of cross-shear wear of TDR over multiple loading conditions. The framework for the calculation of wear was developed from a previous wear model used in the hip and knee, and updated to include cross-shear based upon the A/(A+B) theory of Turell et al. Based on the sliding distances and directions, the model computed a wear factor for each node which was used to adaptively compute the wear at each update interval representing ten million wear cycles. The platform was applied to the lumbar ProDisc implant (ProDisc-L) TDR, and run for 10 million wear cycles with multiple loading conditions to find how the varying cross-path motions affected wear. Next, a cervical ProDisc (ProDisc-C) implant was run with three different loading conditions and compared to experimental results to validate the cross-shear based model using the A/(A+B) method and a modified A/(A+B) method.As expected with unidirectional motion, the lumbar model predicted the wear to be essentially zero. With multidirectional motion, the more cross path motion experienced, the higher the wear. Using the A/(A+B) method, the cervical model showed good agreement in trend to the experimental wear results, while the modified A/(A+B) method showed good agreement in trend and value to the experimental results.  Even though this model uses a simplification of the wear process, the results prove that by incorporating cross-shear into a numerical wear analysis, the wear rates can be accurately predicted.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>MS</dc:description>
  <dc:format>108</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63414</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63414</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Rullkoetter, Paul J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Matin, Mohammad</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
  <dc:contributor>Laz, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lengsfeld, Corinne</dc:contributor>
  <dc:subject>Mechanical engineering</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biomedical research</dc:subject>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63049</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T20:41:33Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A New Heaven and A New Earth: The Book of Revelation and Latin American Liberation Theology</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Olson, Alicia M</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Religious Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The Apocalypse of John is often cited as a favorite text of base communities in Latin America, but little has been written about how Revelation is interpreted in this context. Works on Revelation by four Latin American liberationist authors, Pablo Richard, Carlos Mesters, Jorge Pixley, and Justo Gonzalez, are discussed in detail.  Content, method, and the influence of the themes of liberation theology on their interpretations of the Apocalypse are discussed in relation to each.  Liberationist readings of Revelation are oriented toward the present in such a way that they do not ignore the past or future, but rather find in the past a mirror of the present struggles and in Revelation&apos;s visions of the future a model for liberating activity in the present.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>MA</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Religion, General--Latin American Liberation Theology; Bible--Revelation; Carlos Mesters; Pablo Richard; Jorge Pixley; Justo Gonzalez</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>75</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63049</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63049</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Robbins, Gregory</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Leon, Luis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wadsworth, Nancy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63189</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T20:44:22Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A NEW METHODOLOGY FOR DEVELOPING FUELS DATA FOR FIRE SIMULATION MODELS IN THE COLORADO FRONT RANGE</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Walsh, Benjamin David</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Geography</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>The use of fire simulation models for hazard assessment in topographically diverse and fire sensitive regions such as Colorado&apos;s Front Range has been used effectively.  The Hayman Fire, which burned over an area of more than 138,000 acres, highlighted the need for accurate hazard assessment in such areas.  In this study, a new methodology is implemented, which addresses the issues of differential illumination and delineation of spectrally similar fuels categories as they relate to generating the critical fuels data layer necessary for effective fire simulations.  
				
The methods are designed to be streamlined, resource efficient, and robust.  Although fuels data are already being generated by the Forest Service for much of the United States, the resources employed to do so are not representative of those of many individuals and organizations who may have a desire to quantify the fire hazard present in their area.  This research develops and tests a methodology which is capable of generating similarly effective fuels data in a much more streamlined and less resource intensive way.  The result is a functionally similar fuels layer to that developed by the Forest Service.  A statistical comparison of the two layers shows a 76% accuracy rate in fuel model delineation.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>MA</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Geography--Geotechnology</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>90</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63189</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63189</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Keables, Michael J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Berry, Joseph</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Anderson, Sharolyn</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63210</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T21:02:12Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Quantitative Molecular Technique for Studying Competition Among Strains of Micromonas pusilla</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Olsofka, Claire</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Biological Sciences</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>November 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>In order to study competitive interactions of a globally important picophytoplankton, Micromonas pusilla, a novel methodology enlisting quantitative polymerase chain reaction (qPCR) was used to determine cell abundance among three different strains of M. pusilla.  Phytoplankton are important primary producers and play a vital role in aquatic food webs.  M. pusilla remains a cryptic species in its global distribution; while genetic differences separate strains of M. pusilla, it exhibits morphologically indistinguishable characteristics.  Optimization and validation of methods for qPCR involved primer and probe specificity for three M. pusilla strains (CCMP488, CCMP491, CCMP1195) as well as qPCR amplification efficiency, and standard curves based on the relationship between β-tubulin gene copies and cells.  Competition assays were based on semicontinuous growth methods whereby strains were mixed together at different temperatures and transferred weekly.  CCMP1195 outgrew CCMP491 at 22°C; however, the opposite trend occurred at 26°C.  While little information is known about the global distribution of M. pusilla, it was found that temperature influences the distribution and competition of the different strains studied.  This novel molecular technique reveals a new ways to observe the dynamic properties of the temperature of the ocean.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>MS</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Biology, General</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>99</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63210</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63210</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Dores, Robert</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Smith, Dwight</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Short, Steven</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Angleson, Joseph</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63556</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T21:05:29Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Study of Colorado&apos;s TABOR Law and Its Influence on Public Finance During the 2001 Recession</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brewer, Zak</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Economics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Colorado&apos;s constitutional Taxpayer Bill of Rights (TABOR) is a product of the citizen initiative process, a mechanism of direct democracy that allows citizens to circumvent legislatures and enact laws themselves.  A prominent argument against this process is that such a mode of lawmaking can generate conflicts within state constitutions and bring about unintended consequences.  This paper considers the Colorado state budget difficulties that arose during the 2001 recession, the relationship of TABOR and those difficulties, and finds that TABOR resulted in unintended consequences that were unforeseen by voters who approved the measure.  Examples of these unanticipated, unintended consequences include: significant budget cuts for higher education, reductions in state mental health services, and insufficiencies within the TABOR law regarding how TABOR refunds were to be made.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Economics, Finance</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>76</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63556</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63556</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Wilson, Matthew</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Freeman, Katherine</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Mott, Tracy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sterett, Susan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63005</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T21:08:33Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ADAPTIVE NEURO-FUZZY MODELING AND ITS APPLICATION TO AUTONOMOUS NAVIGATION</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mitra, Arjun</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Computer Engineering</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This thesis research project proposes modeling dynamic environments defined in Cartesian space utilizing the inherent linear separability property of neural networks. The activation function of the neurons fuzzifies the linear separation of points in Cartesian space. The composition of sets of linearly separated points create an entity or agent in the environment.Due to the parallel nature of artificial neural networks this model is parallely decomposable and reduces the computation time either when incorporated on a hardware neural network platform or by utilizing multithreading in a simple processor. Hence, not only does this modeling methodology provide an efficient and viable mechanism to model the environment, but simultaneously creates a decision space (fuzzy membership), that provides meaningful information about the interaction of the entities in the universe of discourse.To test this modeling methodology, it was applied to the domain of autonomous robot navigation in two dimensional Cartesian space. A number of computer simulations were carried out to test the feasibility of using the neuro-fuzzy modeling architecture with the Artificial Potential Fields (APF) method of robot navigation and the hybrid A-star (A*) - APF navigation strategy. The results of the simulations proved that the neuro-fuzzy modeling architecture can be successfully interfaced with the hybrid A-star (A*) - APF navigation strategy to provide a viable navigation heuristic for autonomous holonomic robot navigation in a dynamic environment.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>MS</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Computer Science--Engineering, Robotics--Autonomous robot navigation; neural networks; hybrid neuro-fuzzy architecture; A star algorithm; Artificial Potential Fields</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>86</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63005</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63005</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Jones, Irvin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Newman, Kim</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Narapareddy, Vijaya L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salters, Roger</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63024</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T21:10:36Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>American Protestant Fundamentalist Anti-Intellectualism in Historical and Critical Perspective</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tillman, Rachel</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Religious Studies</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>June 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This paper seeks to explore what is meant by the common scholarly characterization of American Protestant fundamentalists as &quot;anti-intellectual.&quot; Fundamentalists are heirs of the nineteenth century evangelical assimilation of popular Baconian science and Common to Christian Scripture. Yet as popular intellectual currents shifted to Darwinism and scientific positivism, the fundamentalists increasingly withdrew from the public intellectual sphere, placing Biblical faith in opposition to human reason. The combination of an uncritical acceptance of nineteenth century philosophy and a wholesale retreat from the public intellectual realm created an array of obstacles for fundamentalists&apos; engagement with the life of the mind. Yet more importantly, as a result of this history, the fundamentalists embraced an essentially self-contradictory theological epistemology that both relied on and denied the capacity of the natural human mind to know truth. In order to understand how the tensions within this position are resolved by the fundamentalist community, this paper examines how literalist readings of Scripture, themselves based on positive Common Sense epistemology, are used to defend a strong anti-intellectual bias. David Kelsey&apos;s analysis of theology as &apos;imaginative construal&quot; is used to show how fundamentalists discovered within literalist, Baconian readings of Scripture doctrines that justify their anti-intellectual stance.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>MA</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Religion, General--Philosophy--Fundamentalism; evangelicalism; anti-intellectual; inerrancy; theology; Common Sense philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>86</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63024</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63024</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Raschke, Carl</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Reshotko, Naomi</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Robbins, Gregory</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63563</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T21:13:48Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An Inquiry into the Metaphysical Foundations of Mathematics in Economics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Luna, Edgar</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Economics</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>January 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>Economics is supposed to fall somewhere between a hard science and a social science.  During the last half century, economics has become highly mathematical trying to mimic physics.  The purpose of this study is to look at the metaphysical statements linked to mathematical models, specifically, Game Theory.  In doing so, it will be demonstrated that Game Theory, as part of neoclassical economics, engages in analysis which can be categorized as metaphysical, with real metaphysical implications.  In categorizing the metaphysical assumptions of neoclassical economists/game theorists we will see how much of their analysis is consists in a reductive, implausible metaphysical view.  Problems that arise from this view are hardly taken into consideration most economists.  This lack of consideration has non-trivial consequences for economics as a discipline and for its methodology.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>M.A.</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Economics, Theory--Philosophy--Economics, History--Economic Methodology--History of Economic Thought--Philosophy of Mathematics--Philosophy of Science</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>122</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63563</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63563</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Urquhart, Robert</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Mott, Tracy</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Upton, Candace</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63209</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T21:17:55Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Applications of High-Speed Infrared Spectroscopy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Holubowitch, Nicolas Edward</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Chemistry and Biochemistry</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>This thesis discusses four major projects performed at the University of Denver utilizing high-speed infrared spectroscopy for gas phase detection of carbon dioxide and other species. One project was performed for ADA-ES based in Littleton, Colorado as an investigation of potential new materials (or novel combinations of existing materials) for the capture of carbon dioxide in flue gases emitted by power plants. A second project uses traditional remote sensing instrumentation developed at DU to create a modified fast-response continuous remote sensor that can be placed at one side of the road. Hopes are to ultimately couple this technology with other detectors (i.e. PM detectors) to monitor species which cannot currently be quantified using across-the-road techniques. Third, a series of tests was performed on FEAT instruments to make them easier to use. And finally, a study of diesel truck emissions was performed in California and findings are presented and compared to new EPA standards.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>MS</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Chemistry, Analytical</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>139</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63209</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63209</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Stedman, Donald H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor></dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
  <record>
   <header>
    <identifier>oai:digitaldu.coalliance.org:codu_63388</identifier>
    <datestamp>2013-01-28T21:20:02Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>codu_62282</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Characterization of Nano-Confined Lipids Using FTIR and EPR Spectroscopy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kryszak, Kristin D</dc:creator>
  <dc:contributor>Chemistry and Biochemistry</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>University of Denver</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>September 2008</dc:date>
  <dc:publisher>University of Denver</dc:publisher>
  <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
  <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
  <dc:description>An optical biosensor can used to study biological membrane interactions. In order to create such a biosensor, the membrane is supported on a solid support substrate, anodic aluminum oxide (AAO) discs. This will protects the membrane from contaminants while increasing the surface area able to be studied. The overall goal of this project is to create an optical biosensor in order to detect interactions with biological membranes.The nature of the discontinuous chain-melting transition of nanopore-confined saturated phosphatidylcholines has been characterized by FTIR and EPR spectroscopy and compared to aqueous vesicle dispersions. Determined by FTIR spectroscopy, confinement alters the melting temperature of the DPPC bilayers, increasing it slightly in the heating direction and reducing it by as much as 1.5°C in the cooling direction. Moreover, the cooperative nature of the Lβ&apos; (gel phase) ↔  Lα&apos; (liquid crystalline phase) is reduced at least in the cooling direction.Investigation of the CH2 wagging modes gives us a more direct look at the amount of gauche rotomers in the lipid acyl chain. The nanopores influence the extent of rotomer formation, not decreasing it as we initially thought. The largest change appears in gauche rotomers contained in double gauche.Using the order parameters determined by EPR with doxylstearate spin labels, the number of gauche rotomers in the liquid crystalline phase was estimated. The calculated gauche content per molecule (using the 5-doxyl) is 8.19 which compares well to the values of 8.18 obtained from the FTIR analysis. For the AAO confined lipids the calculated gauche content is 8.71, when a slightly higher value of 9.20 was obtained by FTIR. The EPR order parameters suggest that the AAO cause a reduction of disorder mostly in the gel phase. The reduction in long axis rotation observed in FTIR experiments is confirmed by EPR. It appears that confinement favors trans-gauche isomerization over rotation.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>MS</dc:description>
  <dc:subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry--Biophysics, General--Chemistry, Physical--Supported Lipids; Anodic Aluminum Oxide; Nanopores; DPPC; Doxylstearate; Wagging Modes</dc:subject>
  <dc:format>189</dc:format>
  <dc:format>reformatted digital</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>codu:63388</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>Copyright is held by the author.</dc:rights>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:63388</dc:identifier>
  <dc:contributor>Wells, Todd A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sadler, Susan E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Stedman, Donald H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Eaton, Sandra S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:type></dc:type>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description></dc:description>
  <dc:description>master</dc:description>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:coverage></dc:coverage>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:subject></dc:subject>
  <dc:rights></dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc></metadata>
  </record>
 </ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
